<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><xml><records><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Narayanan, Annamalai</author><author>Chandramohan, Mahinthan</author><author>Chen, Lihui</author><author>Liu, Yang</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Context-Aware, Adaptive, and Scalable Android Malware Detection Through Online Learning</title><secondary-title>IEEE Transactions on Emerging Topics in Computational Intelligence</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Transactions on Emerging Topics in Computational Intelligence</full-title></periodical><pages>157-175</pages><volume>1</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Concept drift</keyword><keyword>graph kernels</keyword><keyword>malware detection</keyword><keyword>online learning.</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/TETCI.2017.2699220</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://narayanan2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7935482/</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>It is well known that Android malware constantly evolves so as to evade detection. This causes the entire malware population to be nonstationary. Contrary to this fact, most of the priorworks on machine learning based androidmalware detection have assumed that the distribution of the observed malware char- acteristics (i.e., features) does not change over time. In this paper, we address the problem of malware population drift and propose a novel online learning based framework to detect malware, named CASANDRA (Context-aware, Adaptive and Scalable ANDRoid mAlware detector). In order to perform accurate detection, a novel graph kernel that facilitates capturing apps security-sensitive behaviors along with their context information from dependence graphs is proposed. Besides being accurate and scalable, CASAN- DRA has specific advantages: first, being adaptive to the evolution in malware features over time; second, explaining the significant fea- tures that led to an apps classification as being malicious or benign. In a large-scale comparative analysis, CASANDRA outperforms two state-of-the-art techniques on a benchmark dataset achieving 99.23% F-measure. When evaluated with more than 87 000 apps collected in-the-wild, CASANDRA achieves 89.92% accuracy, outperforming existing techniques by more than 25% in their typical batch learning setting and more than 7% when they are continuously retained, while maintaining comparable efficiency. Index</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">3</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Omeleze, Stacey</author><author>Venter, H. S.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Testing the harmonised digital forensic investigation process model-using an Android mobile phone</title><secondary-title>2013 Information Security for South Africa - Proceedings of the ISSA 2013 Conference</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2013 Information Security for South Africa - Proceedings of the ISSA 2013 Conference</full-title></periodical><keywords><keyword>(ISO/IEC 27043)</keyword><keyword>Android mobile phone</keyword><keyword>Mobile forensics</keyword><keyword>digital forensics investigation procedure</keyword><keyword>harmonised digital forensic investigation process</keyword><keyword>mobile forensic framework</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><isbn>9781479908080</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ISSA.2013.6641063</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://omeleze2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile forensics is a branch of digital forensics relating to the recovery of digital evidence from mobile devices under forensically sound conditions. Mobile forensics is consid- ered to be at an infant stage with different investigation process models being applied. The biggest challenge in many of the available digital forensic investigation process models lies in their lack of testing before being fully applied to mobile forensics. Furthermore, for any proposed digital forensic investigation process model to be approved by the scientific community, it has to be tested. The Harmonised Digital Forensic Investigation (HDFI) process model is currently in the working draft stage towards becoming an international standard for digital forensic investigations (ISO/IEC 27043), thus the need for its testing. In this paper, the (HDFI) process model is tested using an Android mobile phone. The selection of an Android mobile phone is motivated by the fact that Android mobile phones have the greatest share of the mobile market index. In the last three years, for example, the market share index for mobile phones put Android mobile devices at 75% of the entire smartphone market. Through observing the findings of the test using an Android mobile phone, this paper demonstrates that conducting mobile forensics using the HDFI process model produces satisfactory results.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jadhav, Suyash</author><author>Oh, Tae Tom</author><author>Jeong, Jaehoon Paul</author><author>Kim, Young Ho</author><author>Kim, Jeong Neyo</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An Assistive System for Android Malware Analysis to Increase Malware Analysis Efficiency</title><secondary-title>2017 31st International Conference on Advanced Information Networking and Applications Workshops (WAINA)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2017 31st International Conference on Advanced Information Networking and Applications Workshops (WAINA)</full-title></periodical><pages>370-374</pages><keywords><keyword>-malware</keyword><keyword>analysis</keyword><keyword>assistive system</keyword><keyword>malware</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><isbn>978-1-5090-6231-7</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/WAINA.2017.26</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://jadhav2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7929706/</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">3</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Johnson, Ryan</author><author>Stavrou, Angelos</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Forced-path execution for android applications on x86 platforms</title><secondary-title>Proceedings - 7th International Conference on Software Security and Reliability Companion, SERE-C 2013</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings - 7th International Conference on Software Security and Reliability Companion, SERE-C 2013</full-title></periodical><pages>188-197</pages><issue>Vm</issue><keywords><keyword>Android OS</keyword><keyword>Application Analysis</keyword><keyword>Emulation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><isbn>978-1-4799-2925-2</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/SERE-C.2013.36</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://johnson2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>We present a code analysis framework that performs scalable forced-path execution of Android applications in commodity hardware. Our goal is to reveal the full application functional behavior for large commercial applications without access to source code. We do so by identifying code blocks and API calls that are deemed sensitive and provide a security report to an analyst regarding the functionality of the Android application that is under inspection. We show that our approach is scalable by allowing for the execution of each software component by numerous instances of execution modules. Each execution instance exercises a different code path through the application call-graph leading to full code and state space coverage and exposing any hidden or unwanted functionality. The output is a list of API calls, parameter values, component call graphs, and control flow graphs. We show how this can be leveraged for automated policy enforcement of runtime functionality.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">3</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kuzuno, Hiroki</author><author>Tonami, Satoshi</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Signature generation for sensitive information leakage in android applications</title><secondary-title>Proceedings - International Conference on Data Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings - International Conference on Data Engineering</full-title></periodical><pages>112-119</pages><volume>1</volume><keywords><keyword>Privacy</keyword><keyword>Security</keyword><keyword>Smartphone</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><isbn>9781467353021</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICDEW.2013.6547438</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://kuzuno2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>In recent years, there has been rapid growth in mobile devices such as smartphones, and a number of applications are developed specifically for the smartphone market. In particular, there are many applications that are “free” to the user, but depend on advertisement services for their revenue. Such applications include an advertisement module - a library provided by the advertisement service - that can collect a user's sensitive information and transmit it across the network. Such information is used for targeted advertisements, and user behavior statistics. Users accept this business model, but in most cases the applications do not require the user's acknowledgment in order to transmit sensitive information. Therefore, such applications' behavior becomes an invasion of privacy. In our analysis of 1,188 Android applications' network traffic and permissions, 93% of the applications we analyzed connected to multiple destinations when using the network. 61% required a permission combination that included both access to sensitive information and use of networking services. These applications have the potential to leak the user's sensitive information. Of the 107,859 HTTP packets from these applications, 23,309 (22%) contained sensitive information, such as device identification number and carrier name. In an effort to enable users to control the transmission of their private information, we propose a system which, using a novel clustering method based on the HTTP packet destination and content distances, generates signatures from the clustering result and uses them to detect sensitive information leakage from Android applications. Our system does not require an Android framework modification or any special privileges. Thus users can easily introduce our system to their devices, and manage suspicious applications' network behavior in a fine grained manner. Our system accurately detected 94% of the sensitive information leakage from the applications- evaluated and produced only 5% false negative results, and less than 3% false positive results.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Frank, Mario</author><author>Dong, Ben</author><author>Felt, Adrienne Porter</author><author>Song, Dawn</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Mining permission request patterns from Android and Facebook applications</title><secondary-title>Proceedings - IEEE International Conference on Data Mining, ICDM</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings - IEEE International Conference on Data Mining, ICDM</full-title></periodical><pages>870-875</pages><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>Facebook</keyword><keyword>Pattern mining</keyword><keyword>Permissions</keyword><keyword>Smartphones</keyword><keyword>Unsupervised learning</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2012</year></dates><isbn>9780769549057</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/ICDM.2012.86</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://frank2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Android and Facebook provide third-party applications with access to users' private data and the ability to perform potentially sensitive operations (e.g., post to a user's wall or place phone calls). As a security measure, these platforms restrict applications' privileges with permission systems: users must approve the permissions requested by applications before the applications can make privacy-or security-relevant API calls. However, recent studies have shown that users often do not understand permission requests and are unsure of which permissions are typical for applications. As a first step towards simplifying permission systems, we cluster a corpus of 188,389 Android applications and 27,029 Facebook applications to find patterns in permission requests. Using a method for Boolean matrix factorization to find overlapping clusters of permissions, we find that Facebook permission requests follow a clear structure that can be fitted well with only five patterns, whereas Android applications demonstrate more complex permission requests. We also find that low-reputation applications often deviate from the permission request patterns that we identified for high-reputation applications, which suggests that permission request patterns can be indicative of user satisfaction or application quality.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">3</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zarras, Apostolis</author><author>Papadogiannakis, Antonis</author><author>Gawlik, Robert</author><author>Holz, Thorsten</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Automated generation of models for fast and precise detection of HTTP-based malware</title><secondary-title>2014 12th Annual Conference on Privacy, Security and Trust, PST 2014</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2014 12th Annual Conference on Privacy, Security and Trust, PST 2014</full-title></periodical><pages>249-256</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><isbn>9781479935031</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/PST.2014.6890946</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://zarras2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Malicious software and especially botnets are among the most important security threats in the Internet. Thus, the accurate and timely detection of such threats is of great importance. Detecting machines infected with malware by identifying their malicious activities at the network level is an appealing approach, due to the ease of deployment. Nowadays, the most common communication channels used by attackers to control the infected machines are based on the HTTP protocol. To evade detection, HTTP-based malware adapt their behavior to the communication patterns of the benign HTTP clients, such as web browsers. This poses significant challenges to existing detection approaches like signature-based and behavioral-based detection systems. In this paper, we propose BOTHOUND: a novel approach to precisely detect HTTP-based malware at the network level. The key idea is that implementations of the HTTP protocol by different entities have small but perceivable differences. Building on this observation,BOTHOUND automatically generates models for malicious and benign requests and classifies at real time the HTTP traffic of a monitored network. Our evaluation results demonstrate that BOTHOUND outperforms prior work on identifying HTTP-based botnets, being able to detect a large variety of real-world HTTP-based malware, including advanced persistent threats used in targeted attacks, with a very low percentage of classification errors.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Baskaran, Balaji</author><author>Ralescu, Anca</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Study of Android Malware Detection Techniques and Machine Learning</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of the 27th Modern Artificial Intelligence and Cognitive Science Conference 2016, Dayton, OH, USA, April 22-23, 2016.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the 27th Modern Artificial Intelligence and Cognitive Science Conference 2016, Dayton, OH, USA, April 22-23, 2016.</full-title></periodical><pages>15-23</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://70d54b46d37792976fd4a961c6f389202981.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-1584/paper19.pdf</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Android OS is one of the widely used mobile Operat-ing Systems. The number of malicious applications and adwares are increasing constantly on par with the num-ber of mobile devices. A great number of commercial signature based tools are available on the market which prevent to an extent the penetration and distribution of malicious applications. Numerous researches have been conducted which claims that traditional signature based detection system work well up to certain level and mal-ware authors use numerous techniques to evade these tools. So given this state of affairs, there is an increas-ing need for an alternative, really tough malware de-tection system to complement and rectify the signature based system. Recent substantial research focused on machine learning algorithms that analyze features from malicious application and use those features to classify and detect unknown malicious applications. This study summarizes the evolution of malware detection tech-niques based on machine learning algorithms focused on the Android OS.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Alzaylaee, Mohammed K.</author><author>Yerima, Suleiman Y.</author><author>Sezer, Sakir</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Improving Dynamic Analysis of Android Apps Using Hybrid Test Input Generation</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://1705.06691.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://arxiv.org/abs/1705.06691</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The Android OS has become the most popular mobile operating system leading to a significant increase in the spread of Android malware. Consequently, several static and dynamic analysis systems have been developed to detect Android malware. With dynamic analysis, efficient test input generation is needed in order to trigger the potential run-time malicious behaviours. Most existing dynamic analysis systems employ random-based input generation methods usually built using the Android Monkey tool. Random-based input generation has several shortcomings including limited code coverage, which motivates us to explore combining it with a state-based method in order to improve efficiency. Hence, in this paper, we present a novel hybrid test input generation approach designed to improve dynamic analysis on real devices. We implemented the hybrid system by integrating a random based tool (Monkey) with a state based tool (DroidBot) in order to improve code coverage and potentially uncover more malicious behaviours. The system is evaluated using 2,444 Android apps containing 1222 benign and 1222 malware samples from the Android malware genome project. Three scenarios, random only, state-based only, and our proposed hybrid approach were investigated to comparatively evaluate their performances. Our study shows that the hybrid approach significantly improved the amount of dynamic features extracted from both benign and malware samples over the state-based and commonly used random test input generation method.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Prieto, Luis P.</author><author>Rodríguez-Triana, María Jesús</author><author>Kusmin, Marge</author><author>Laanpere, Mart</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Smart school multimodal dataset and challenges</title><secondary-title>CEUR Workshop Proceedings</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>CEUR Workshop Proceedings</full-title></periodical><pages>53-59</pages><volume>1828</volume><keywords><keyword>Multimodal learning analytics</keyword><keyword>Multimodal teaching analytics</keyword><keyword>STEM education</keyword><keyword>Sensors</keyword><keyword>Smart classroom</keyword><keyword>Smart school</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><isbn>9781450321389</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/1235</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://1606.01403.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The pervasive presence of interconnected objects enables new communication paradigms where devices can easily reach each other while interacting within their environment. The so-called Internet of Things (IoT) represents the integration of several computing and communications systems aiming at facilitating the interaction between these devices. Arduino is one of the most popular platforms used to prototype new IoT devices due to its open, flexible and easy-to-use archi- tecture. Ardunio Yun is a dual board microcontroller that supports a Linux distribution and it is currently one of the most versatile and powerful Arduino systems. This feature positions Arduino Yun as a popular platform for developers, but it also introduces unique infection vectors from the secu- rity viewpoint. In this work, we present a security analysis of Arduino Yun. We show that Arduino Yun is vulnerable to a number of attacks and we implement a proof of concept capable of exploiting some of them.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Grillo, Antonio</author><author>Lentini, Alessandro</author><author>Ottaviani, Vittorio</author><author>Italiano, Giuseppe F</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>SAVED : Secure Android Value addED services State of the Art</title></titles><periodical/><pages>415-427</pages><keywords><keyword>digital certificate</keyword><keyword>ipc security</keyword><keyword>service</keyword><keyword>value added services</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2012</year></dates><isbn>9783642293351</isbn><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://7e2ad6fb43360cef1827b97ff180d89aed7c.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mylonas, Alexios</author><author>Dritsas, Stelios</author><author>Tsoumas, Bill</author><author>Gritzalis, Dimitris</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Smartphone security evaluation - The malware attack case</title><secondary-title>SECRYPT 2011 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Security and Cryptography</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SECRYPT 2011 - Proceedings of the International Conference on Security and Cryptography</full-title></periodical><pages>25-36</pages><issue>July</issue><keywords><keyword>Attack</keyword><keyword>Evaluation criteria</keyword><keyword>Malware</keyword><keyword>Security</keyword><keyword>Smartphone</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2011</year></dates><isbn>9789898425713</isbn><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://4a841e73f4069b159656ae413eedb8956032.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.scopus.com/inward/record.url?eid=2-s2.0-80052493767&amp;partnerID=tZOtx3y1</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The adoption of smartphones, devices transforming from simple communication devices to 'smart' and multipurpose devices, is constantly increasing. Amongst the main reasons are their small size, their enhanced functionality and their ability to host many useful and attractive applications. However, this vast use of mobile platforms makes them an attractive target for conducting privacy and security attacks. This scenario increases the risk introduced by these attacks for personal mobile devices, given that the use of smartphones as business tools may extend the perimeter of an organization's IT infrastructure. Furthermore, smartphone platforms provide application developers with rich capabilities, which can be used to compromise the security and privacy of the device holder and her environment (private and/or organizational). This paper examines the feasibility of malware development in smartphone platforms by average programmers that have access to the official tools and programming libraries provided by smartphone platforms. Towards this direction in this paper we initially propose specific evaluation criteria assessing the security level of the well-known smartphone platforms (i.e. Android, BlackBerry, Apple iOS, Symbian, Windows Mobile), in terms of the development of malware. In the sequel, we provide a comparative analysis, based on a proof of concept study, in which the implementation and distribution of a location tracking malware is attempted. Our study has proven that, under circumstances, all smartphone platforms could be used by average developers as privacy attack vectors, harvesting data from the device without the users knowledge and consent.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Shabtai, Asaf</author><author>Elovici, Yuval</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Applying behavioral detection on android-based devices</title><secondary-title>Lecture Notes of the Institute for Computer Sciences, Social-Informatics and Telecommunications Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Lecture Notes of the Institute for Computer Sciences, Social-Informatics and Telecommunications Engineering</full-title></periodical><pages>235-249</pages><volume>48 LNICST</volume><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>Intrusion detection</keyword><keyword>Machine learning</keyword><keyword>Malware</keyword><keyword>Mobile devices</keyword><keyword>Security</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2010</year></dates><isbn>3642177573</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/978-3-642-17758-3_17</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://6ff94c24b20905e92b9aa53c013ba7584134.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>We present Andromaly - a behavioral-based detection framework for Android-powered mobile devices. The proposed framework realizes a Host-based Intrusion Detection System (HIDS) that continuously monitors various features and events obtained from the mobile device, and then applies Machine Learning methods to classify the collected data as normal (benign) or abnormal (malicious). Since no malicious applications are yet available for Android, we evaluated Andromaly’s ability to differentiate between game and tool applications. Successful differentiation between games and tools is expected to provide a positive indication about the ability of such methods to learn and model the behavior of an Android application and potentially detect malicious applications. Several combinations of classification algorithms, feature selections and the number of top features were evaluated. Empirical results suggest that the proposed detection framework is effective in detecting types of applications having similar behavior, which is an indication for the ability to detect unknown malware in the Android framework.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Alzaylaee, Mohammed K.</author><author>Yerima, Suleiman Y.</author><author>Sezer, Sakir</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>EMULATOR vs REAL PHONE: Android Malware Detection Using Machine Learning</title></titles><periodical/><pages>65-72</pages><keywords><keyword>android</keyword><keyword>anti-</keyword><keyword>anti-analysis</keyword><keyword>device-based detection</keyword><keyword>emulation</keyword><keyword>machine learning</keyword><keyword>malware</keyword><keyword>malware detection</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><isbn>9781450349093</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3041008.3041010</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://4d7bc3eeb23ed6f2d7e6cb168190950abb98.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://arxiv.org/abs/1703.10926%0Ahttp://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3041008.3041010</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The Android operating system has become the most popular operating system for smartphones and tablets leading to a rapid rise in malware. Sophisticated Android malware employ detection avoidance techniques in order to hide their malicious activities from analysis tools. These include a wide range of anti-emulator techniques, where the malware programs attempt to hide their malicious activities by detecting the emulator. For this reason, countermeasures against antiemulation are becoming increasingly important in Android malware detection. Analysis and detection based on real devices can alleviate the problems of anti-emulation as well as improve the effectiveness of dynamic analysis. Hence, in this paper we present an investigation of machine learning based malware detection using dynamic analysis on real devices. A tool is implemented to automatically extract dynamic features from Android phones and through several experiments, a comparative analysis of emulator based vs. device based detection by means of several machine learning algorithms is undertaken. Our study shows that several features could be extracted more effectively from the on-device dynamic analysis compared to emulators. It was also found that approximately 24% more apps were successfully analysed on the phone. Furthermore, all of the studied machine learning based detection performed better when applied to features extracted from the on-device dynamic analysis.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Liang, H.</author><author>Wu, D.</author><author>Liu, S.</author><author>Dai, H.</author><author>Liu, H.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Providing Privacy Protection and Personalization Awareness for Android Devices</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>4645256-4645256</pages><volume>12</volume><issue>7</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1177/155014774645256</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://155014774645256.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dsn.sagepub.com/lookup/doi/10.1177/155014774645256</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>With an increasing number of applications appearing, smartphones with powerful processors and a variety of sensors are ideal mobile devices at hand. On one hand, various applications which are able to provide personalization functions that provide the service of interest to users rely on gathering and analyzing the sensor data and other sensitive information. On the other hand, attackers can accurately classify activities of mobile users from these data. As a result, the risk of users compromising their privacy has risen exponentially. Mobile users currently cannot control how various applications handle the privacy of their sensor data. To address the issue, we present P3Android whose architecture can support applications' personalization functions in Android according to users' personae and use the concept of profile to prevent sensitive information from unauthorized access. Furthermore, we provide a privacy protection service for legacy apps. which can enforce different protection policies according to...</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kim, Taejin</author><author>Yi, Jeong Hyun</author><author>Seo, Changho</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Spyware resistant smartphone user authentication scheme</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</full-title></periodical><volume>2014</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><publisher>Hindawi Publishing Corporation</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1155/2014/237125</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://2014_237125.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>As smart phones are becoming widely used, a variety of services to store and use important information such as photos and financial information are now provided. User authentication to protect this information is increasingly important. The commonly used 4-digit PIN, however, is vulnerable to the Brute Force Attack, Shoulder-Surfing Attack, and Recording Attack. Various authentication techniques are being developed in order to solve these problems. However, the technique that provides perfect protection, even from the Recording Attack, is not yet known, and in most cases, a password can be exposed by multiple Recording Attacks. This paper proposes a new user authentication method that protects against a Recording Attack from spyware on the user's smart phone. The proposed method prevents password exposure by multiple Recording Attacks, is implemented on a real Android phone, and has been evaluated for usability.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kim, Dongwoo</author><author>Kwak, Jin</author><author>Ryou, Jaecheol</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>DWroidDump: Executable Code Extraction from Android Applications for Malware Analysis</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</full-title></periodical><volume>2015</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Hindawi Publishing Corporation</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1155/2015/379682</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://2015_379682.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>We suggest an idea to dump executable code from memory for malicious application analysis on Android platform. Malicious applications are getting enhanced in terms of antianalysis techniques. Recently, sophisticated malicious applications have been found, which are not decompiled and debugged by existing analysis tools. It becomes serious threat to services related to embedded devices based on Android. Thus, we have implemented the idea to obtain main code from the memory by modifying a part of Dalvik Virtual Machine of Android. As a result, we have confirmed that the executable code is completely obtainable. In this paper, we introduce the existing analysis techniques for Android application, and antianalysis techniques. We then describe the proposed method with a sample malicious application which has strong antianalysis techniques.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jiang, Shiqi</author><author>Zhou, Pengfei</author><author>Li, Mo</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Detecting Phantom Data Usage on Smartphones with Analysis of Contextual Information</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</full-title></periodical><volume>2015</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1155/2015/135150</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://2015_135150.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>With the wide development of smartphones, mobile data usage has enjoyed rapid growth in recent years. Unfortunately many users are plagued with Phantom Data Usage (PDU), which refers to the unexpected mobile data usage that does not accord with user perception. We investigate about 400 real PDU issues and find the causes of PDU are not only the exceptions of applications, for example, software bugs or malware, but also the user's personalized misuse. Based on the observations that each user preserves specific data usage patterns under particular environmental context, we present PDS, a PDU detection system, which automatically detects whether the current data usage is consumed as expected. Results from our evaluation experiments show that 72% of PDU cases detected by PDS are confirmed by users. © 2015 Shiqi Jiang et al.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Brown, James</author><author>Anwar, Mohd</author><author>Dozier, Gerry</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An artificial immunity approach to malware detection in a mobile platform</title><secondary-title>EURASIP Journal on Information Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>EURASIP Journal on Information Security</full-title></periodical><pages>7</pages><volume>2017</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Mobile malware,Static flow analysis,Artificial imm</keyword><keyword>artificial immunity</keyword><keyword>feature selection</keyword><keyword>mobile malware</keyword><keyword>negative selection</keyword><keyword>static flow analysis</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>EURASIP Journal on Information Security</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1186/s13635-017-0059-2</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://s13635-017-0059-2.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://jis-eurasipjournals.springeropen.com/articles/10.1186/s13635-017-0059-2</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kang, Hyunjae</author><author>Jang, Jae Wook</author><author>Mohaisen, Aziz</author><author>Kim, Huy Kang</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Detecting and classifying android malware using static analysis along with creator information</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</full-title></periodical><volume>2015</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Hindawi Publishing Corporation</publisher><isbn>1550-1329</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1155/2015/479174</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://2015_479174.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Thousands of malicious applications targeting mobile devices, including the popular Android platform, are created every day. A large number of those applications are created by a small number of professional underground actors; however previous studies overlooked such information as a feature in detecting and classifying malware and in attributing malware to creators. Guided by this insight, we propose a method to improve the performance of Android malware detection by incorporating the creator’s information as a feature and classify malicious applications into similar groups. We developed a system that implements this method in practice. Our system enables fast detection of malware by using creator information such as serial number of certificate. Additionally, it analyzes malicious behaviors and permissions to increase detection accuracy. The system also can classify malware based on similarity scoring. Finally, we showed detection and classification performance with 98% and 90% accuracy, respectively.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Xu, Yanping</author><author>Wu, Chunhua</author><author>Zheng, Kangfeng</author><author>Niu, Xinxin</author><author>Yang, Yixian</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Fuzzy–synthetic minority oversampling technique: Oversampling based on fuzzy set theory for Android malware detection in imbalanced datasets</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>155014771770311</pages><volume>13</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>android malware</keyword><keyword>fuzzy</keyword><keyword>fuzzy region</keyword><keyword>imbalanced datasets</keyword><keyword>oversample</keyword><keyword>synthetic minority oversampling technique</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1177/1550147717703116</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://1550147717703116.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/1550147717703116</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>In previous work, imbalanced datasets composed of more benign samples (the majority class) than the malicious one (the minority class) have been widely adopted in Android malware detection. These imbalanced datasets bias learning toward the majority class, so that the minority class examples are more likely to be misclassified. To solve the problem, we propose a new oversampling method called fuzzy-synthetic minority oversampling technique, which is based on fuzzy set theory and the synthetic minority oversampling technique method. As the sample size of the majority class increases relative to that of the minority class, fuzzy-synthetic minority oversampling technique generates more synthetic examples for each minority class examples in the fuzzy region, where the minority examples have a low degree of membership to the minority class and are more likely to be misclassified. Using the new synthetic examples, the classifiers build larger decision regions that contain more minority examples, and they are no longer biased to the majority class. Compared with synthetic minority oversampling technique and Borderline-synthetic minority oversampling technique methods, fuzzy-synthetic minority oversampling technique achieves higher accuracy on both the minority class and the entire datasets. &amp;copy; The Author(s) 2017.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, Ping</author><author>Chao, K.-M.</author><author>Lo, C.-C.</author><author>Lin, W.-H.</author><author>Lin, H.-C.</author><author>Chao, W.-J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Using malware for software-defined networking-based smart home security management through a taint checking approach</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Distributed Sensor Networks</full-title></periodical><volume>12</volume><issue>8</issue><keywords><keyword>*Correspondence</keyword><keyword>android</keyword><keyword>bytecode rewriting</keyword><keyword>detection</keyword><keyword>privilege escalation attack</keyword><keyword>transitive permission attack</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1177/1550147716662947</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://1550147716662947.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/1550147716662947%5Cnhttp://dsn.sagepub.com/lookup/doi/10.1177/1550147716662947</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Numerous security concerns exist in smart home systems in which Internet of Things devices are connected through a home network to enable control using a centralised gateway with a handset device from the Internet. Safeguarding personal information privacy is an increasing concern in smart living services. To guarantee the mobile security of smart living services, security managers use taint checking approaches with dynamic taint propagation analysis operations to examine how a software-defined networking app uses sensitive information and investigate suspicious security vulnerabilities of devices and the effects of the spread of taint propagation over the Internet by identifying taint paths. For solving the dynamic taint propagation analysis problem, most approaches focus on cloud computing applications (apps) with malware threat analysis that involves program vulnerability analyses, rather than on the risk posed by suspicious apps connected to the cloud computing server. Accordingly, this article proposes a taint propagation analysis model incorporating a weighted spanning tree analysis scheme for tracking data with taint marking using several taint checking tools with an open software-defined networking architecture for solving the dynamic taint propagation analysis problem. In the proposed model, Android programs perform dynamic taint propagation to analyse the spread of risks posed by suspicious apps connected to the centralised gateway in a smart home system. In probabilistic risk analysis, risk and defence capability are used for each taint path to assist a defender in recognising the attack results against network threats caused by malware infection and to estimate the losses of associated taint sources. A case of threat analysis of a typical cyber security attack is presented to demonstrate the proposed approach. A new approach was used for verifying the details of an attack sequence for malware infection by incorporating a finite state machine to appropriately represent the real dynamic taint propagation analysis situations at various configuration settings and safeguard deployment. The experimental results proved that the threat analysis model enables a defender to convert the spread of taint propagation to loss and estimate the risk of a specific threat using behavioural analysis associated with 60 families of real malware. Consequently, our scheme was significantly effective in predicting the risk and loss of tainted data propagation for security concerns in smart home systems when the number of taint paths associated with the propagation rules discovered through taint analysis was increased.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cai, Fu</author><author>Qingfeng, Huang</author><author>LanSheng, Han</author><author>Li, Shen</author><author>Xiao-Yang, Liu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Virus propagation power of the dynamic network</title><secondary-title>EURASIP Journal on Wireless Communications and Networking</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>EURASIP Journal on Wireless Communications and Networking</full-title></periodical><pages>210</pages><volume>2013</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>basic propagation structure</keyword><keyword>dynamic network</keyword><keyword>propagation power</keyword><keyword>virus restraint</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1186/1687-1499-2013-210</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://1687-1499-2013-210.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://jwcn.eurasipjournals.com/content/2013/1/210</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>With the development of mobile networks, propagation characteristics and defense mechanism of the virus have attracted increasing research attention. But current researches are mainly concerned with static network topology or community structure and some studies focus on characteristics of virus and malware. Little attention is paid to the influence of dynamic changes of network topology to virus propagation. Meanwhile, many studies focus on the threshold rate of the infection (or the immunization rate) for virus outbreak. In this paper, we present a new way to assess and restrain virus propagation by proposing the concepts of propagation power and propagation structure. Three basic propagation structures are presented through which the infection risk can be quantified, and a framework is proposed to assess the impact of virus propagation in different network structures. The relationship between the speed of virus propagation and network structure is also explored. An algorithm is designed to assess the propagation power in a dynamic network with no need to redetect the community under the dynamic network which may significantly improve the efficiency of assessment in a large-scale dynamic network. This study offers a feasible approach for quantifying the risk of virus infection in the network community which is valuable for designing and optimizing the virus defense systems.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Demertzis, Konstantinos</author><author>Iliadis, Lazaros</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Computational intelligence anti-malware framework for android OS</title><secondary-title>Vietnam Journal of Computer Science</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Vietnam Journal of Computer Science</full-title></periodical><keywords><keyword>Android malware,Firmware malware,Mobile banking ma</keyword><keyword>android malware</keyword><keyword>banking malware</keyword><keyword>firmware malware</keyword><keyword>mobile</keyword><keyword>online</keyword><keyword>ransomware</keyword><keyword>rootkits</keyword><keyword>sequential extreme learning machine</keyword><keyword>tor traffic analysis</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><isbn>4059501700953</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s40595-017-0095-3</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://10.1007%2Fs40595-017-0095-3.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s40595-017-0095-3</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>It is a fact that more and more users are adopting the online digital payment systems via mobile devices for everyday use. This attracts powerful gangs of cybercriminals, which use sophisticated and highly intelligent types of malware to broaden their attacks. Malicious software is designed to run quietly and to remain unsolved for a long time. It manages to take full control of the device and to communicate (via the Tor network) with its Command {&amp;} Control servers of fast-flux botnets' networks to which it belongs. This is done to achieve the malicious objectives of the botmasters. This paper proposes the development of the computational intelligence anti-malware framework (CIantiMF) which is innovative, ultra-fast and has low requirements. It runs under the android operating system (OS) and its reasoning is based on advanced computational intelligence approaches. The selection of the android OS was based on its popularity and on the number of critical applications available for it. The CIantiMF uses two advanced technology extensions for the ART java virtual machine which is the default in the recent versions of android. The first is the smart anti-malware extension, which can recognize whether the java classes of an android application are benign or malicious using an optimized multi-layer perceptron. The optimization is done by the employment of the biogeography-based optimizer algorithm. The second is the Tor online traffic identification extension, which is capable of achieving malware localization, Tor traffic identification and botnets prohibition, with the use of the online sequential extreme learning machine algorithm.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cho, Geumhwan</author><author>Cho, Junsung</author><author>Song, Youngbae</author><author>Choi, Donghyun</author><author>Kim, Hyoungshick</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Combating online fraud attacks in mobile-based advertising</title><secondary-title>EURASIP Journal on Information Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>EURASIP Journal on Information Security</full-title></periodical><pages>2</pages><volume>2016</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>advertising network</keyword><keyword>android</keyword><keyword>click fraud</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>EURASIP Journal on Information Security</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1186/s13635-015-0027-7</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://s13635-015-0027-7.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://jis-eurasipjournals.springeropen.com/articles/10.1186/s13635-015-0027-7</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Smartphone advertisement is increasingly used among many applications and allows developers to obtain revenue through in-app advertising. Our study aims at identifying potential security risks of mobile-based advertising services where advertisers are charged for their advertisements on mobile applications. In the Android platform, we particularly implement bot programs that can massively generate click events on advertisements on mobile applications and test their feasibility with eight popular advertising networks. Our experimental results show that six advertising networks (75 %) out of eight are vulnerable to our attacks. To mitigate click fraud attacks, we suggest three possible defense mechanisms: (1) filtering out program-generated touch events; (2) identifying click fraud attacks with faked advertisement banners; and (3) detecting anomalous behaviors generated by click fraud attacks. We also discuss why few companies were only willing to deploy such defense mechanisms by examining economic misincentives on the mobile advertising industry.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Nissim, Nir</author><author>Cohen, Aviad</author><author>Moskovitch, Robert</author><author>Shabtai, Asaf</author><author>Edri, Matan</author><author>BarAd, Oren</author><author>Elovici, Yuval</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Keeping pace with the creation of new malicious PDF files using an active-learning based detection framework</title><secondary-title>Security Informatics</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security Informatics</full-title></periodical><pages>1</pages><volume>5</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Active learning</keyword><keyword>Machine learning</keyword><keyword>Malware</keyword><keyword>PDF</keyword><keyword>active learning</keyword><keyword>machine learning</keyword><keyword>malware</keyword><keyword>pdf</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher><isbn>1338801600</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1186/s13388-016-0026-3</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://s13388-016-0026-3.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.security-informatics.com/content/5/1/1</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Attackers increasingly take advantage of naive users who tend to treat non-executable files casually, as if they are benign. Such users often open non-executable files although they can conceal and perform malicious operations. Existing defensive solutions currently used by organizations prevent executable files from entering organizational networks via web browsers or email messages. Therefore, recent advanced persistent threat attacks tend to lever-age non-executable files such as portable document format (PDF) documents which are used daily by organizations. Machine Learning (ML) methods have recently been applied to detect malicious PDF files, however these techniques lack an essential element—they cannot be efficiently updated daily. In this study we present an active learning (AL) based framework, specifically designed to efficiently assist anti-virus vendors focus their analytical efforts aimed at acquiring novel malicious content. This focus is accomplished by identifying and acquiring both new PDF files that are most likely malicious and informative benign PDF documents. These files are used for retraining and enhancing the knowledge stores of both the detection model and anti-virus. We propose two AL based methods: exploitation and combination. Our methods are evaluated and compared to existing AL method (SVM-margin) and to random sampling for 10 days, and results indicate that on the last day of the experiment, combination outperformed all of the other methods, enriching the signature repository of the anti-virus with almost seven times more new malicious PDF files, while each day improving the detection model's capabilities further. At the same time, it dramatically reduces security experts' efforts by 75 %. Despite this significant reduction, results also indicate that our framework better detects new malicious PDF files than leading anti-virus tools commonly used by organizations for protection against malicious PDF files.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Husák, Martin</author><author>Čermák, Milan</author><author>Jirsík, Tomáš</author><author>Čeleda, Pavel</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>HTTPS traffic analysis and client identification using passive SSL/TLS fingerprinting</title><secondary-title>EURASIP Journal on Information Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>EURASIP Journal on Information Security</full-title></periodical><pages>6</pages><volume>2016</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>fingerprinting</keyword><keyword>https</keyword><keyword>network monitoring</keyword><keyword>ssl</keyword><keyword>tls</keyword><keyword>user-agent</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>EURASIP Journal on Information Security</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1186/s13635-016-0030-7</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://s13635-016-0030-7.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://jis-eurasipjournals.springeropen.com/articles/10.1186/s13635-016-0030-7</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The encryption of network traffic complicates legitimate network monitoring, traffic analysis, and network forensics. In this paper, we present real-time lightweight identification of HTTPS clients based on network monitoring and SSL/TLS fingerprinting. Our experiment shows that it is possible to estimate the User-Agent of a client in HTTPS communication via the analysis of the SSL/TLS handshake. The fingerprints of SSL/TLS handshakes, including a list of supported cipher suites, differ among clients and correlate to User-Agent values from a HTTP header. We built up a dictionary of SSL/TLS cipher suite lists and HTTP User-Agents and assigned the User-Agents to the observed SSL/TLS connections to identify communicating clients. The dictionary was used to classify live HTTPS network traffic. We were able to retrieve client types from 95.4 {%} of HTTPS network traffic. Further, we discussed host-based and network-based methods of dictionary retrieval and estimated the quality of the data.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, Xiaolei</author><author>Yang, Yuexiang</author><author>Zeng, Yingzhi</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Accurate mobile malware detection and classification in the cloud</title><secondary-title>SpringerPlus</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SpringerPlus</full-title></periodical><pages>583</pages><volume>4</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>Anomaly detection</keyword><keyword>Classification</keyword><keyword>CuckooDroid</keyword><keyword>Dynamic analysis</keyword><keyword>Mobile cloud service</keyword><keyword>Mobile malware detection</keyword><keyword>Signature detection</keyword><keyword>Static analysis</keyword><keyword>analysis</keyword><keyword>android</keyword><keyword>anomaly detection</keyword><keyword>classification</keyword><keyword>cuckoodroid</keyword><keyword>dynamic</keyword><keyword>mobile cloud service</keyword><keyword>mobile malware detection</keyword><keyword>signature detection</keyword><keyword>static analysis</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher><isbn>2193-1801</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1186/s40064-015-1356-1</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://s40064-015-1356-1.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.springerplus.com/content/4/1/583</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>As the dominator of the Smartphone operating system market, consequently android has attracted the attention of smalware authors and researcher alike. The number of types of android malware is increasing rapidly regardless of the considerable number of proposed malware analysis systems. In this paper, by taking advantages of low false-positive rate of misuse detection and the ability of anomaly detection to detect zero-day malware, we propose a novel hybrid detection system based on a new open-source framework CuckooDroid, which enables the use of Cuckoo Sandbox's features to analyze Android malware through dynamic and static analysis. Our proposed system mainly consists of two parts: anomaly detection engine performing abnormal apps detection through dynamic analysis; signature detection engine performing known malware detection and classification with the combination of static and dynamic analysis. We evaluate our system using 5560 malware samples and 6000 benign samples. Experiments show that our anomaly detection engine with dynamic analysis is capable of detecting zero-day malware with a low false negative rate (1.16 {%}) and acceptable false positive rate (1.30 {%}); it is worth noting that our signature detection engine with hybrid analysis can accurately classify malware samples with an average positive rate 98.94 {%}. Considering the intensive computing resources required by the static and dynamic analysis, our proposed detection system should be deployed off-device, such as in the Cloud. The app store markets and the ordinary users can access our detection system for malware detection through cloud service.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lim, Jongsu</author><author>Yi, Jeong Hyun</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Structural analysis of packing schemes for extracting hidden codes in mobile malware</title><secondary-title>EURASIP Journal on Wireless Communications and Networking</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>EURASIP Journal on Wireless Communications and Networking</full-title></periodical><pages>221</pages><volume>2016</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>android app security</keyword><keyword>mobile code hiding</keyword><keyword>repackaging attack</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>EURASIP Journal on Wireless Communications and Networking</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1186/s13638-016-0720-3</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://s13638-016-0720-3.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://jwcn-eurasipjournals.springeropen.com/articles/10.1186/s13638-016-0720-3</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>In the Internet of Things service environment where all things are connected, mobile devices will become an extremely important medium linking together things with built-in heterogeneous communication functions. If a mobile device is exposed to hacking in this context, a security threat arises where all things linked to the device become targets of cyber hacking; therefore, greater emphasis will be placed on the demand for swift mobile malware detection and countermeasures. Such mobile malware applies advanced code-hiding schemes to ensure that the part of the code that executes malicious behavior is not detected by an anti-virus software. In order to detect mobile malware, we must first conduct structural analysis of their code-hiding schemes.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Baig, Zubair A.</author><author>Szewczyk, Patryk</author><author>Valli, Craig</author><author>Rabadia, Priya</author><author>Hannay, Peter</author><author>Chernyshev, Maxim</author><author>Johnstone, Mike</author><author>Kerai, Paresh</author><author>Ibrahim, Ahmed</author><author>Sansurooah, Krishnun</author><author>Syed, Naeem</author><author>Peacock, Matthew</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Future challenges for smart cities: Cyber-security and digital forensics</title><secondary-title>Digital Investigation</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Digital Investigation</full-title></periodical><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.diin.2017.06.015</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://10.1016@j.diin.2017.06.015.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S1742287617300579</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Eterovic-Soric, Brett</author><author>Choo, Kim Kwang Raymond</author><author>Ashman, Helen</author><author>Mubarak, Sameera</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Stalking the stalkers – detecting and deterring stalking behaviours using technology: A review</title><secondary-title>Computers and Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computers and Security</full-title></periodical><pages>278-289</pages><volume>70</volume><keywords><keyword>Counter-surveillance</keyword><keyword>Cyberstalker</keyword><keyword>Cyberstalking</keyword><keyword>Online surveillance</keyword><keyword>Privacy</keyword><keyword>Spyware</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.cose.2017.06.008</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://10.1016@j.cose.2017.06.008.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cose.2017.06.008</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The Internet age has brought with it a slew of tools and research which allow stalkers, from ex-lovers to complete strangers, to follow a person's life in great detail without their consent. The converse side of the issue, the ability of a target to detect and track stalking behaviour, has not received nearly as much attention, with privacy and security research largely discussing other threat models. This article reviews the current literature on the subject and explores the disparity between technologies used by stalkers and technologies used against stalkers, then suggests some research avenues which may help correct this imbalance.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jang, Jae-wook</author><author>Yun, Jaesung</author><author>Mohaisen, Aziz</author><author>Woo, Jiyoung</author><author>Kim, Huy Kang</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Detecting and classifying method based on similarity matching of Android malware behavior with profile</title><secondary-title>SpringerPlus</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SpringerPlus</full-title></periodical><pages>273</pages><volume>5</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>Behavior profiling</keyword><keyword>Malware</keyword><keyword>Similarity</keyword><keyword>System call</keyword><keyword>android</keyword><keyword>behavior profiling</keyword><keyword>malware</keyword><keyword>similarity</keyword><keyword>system call</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher><isbn>2193-1801</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1186/s40064-016-1861-x</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://s40064-016-1861-x.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.springerplus.com/content/5/1/273</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Mass-market mobile security threats have increased recently due to the growth of mobile technologies and the popularity of mobile devices. Accordingly, techniques have been introduced for identifying, classifying, and defending against mobile threats utilizing static, dynamic, on-device, and off-device techniques. Static techniques are easy to evade, while dynamic techniques are expensive. On-device techniques are evasion, while off-device techniques need being always online. To address some of those shortcomings, we introduce Andro-profiler, a hybrid behavior based analysis and classification system for mobile malware. Andro-profiler main goals are efficiency, scalability, and accuracy. For that, Andro-profiler classifies malware by exploiting the behavior profiling extracted from the integrated system logs including system calls. Andro-profiler executes a malicious application on an emulator in order to generate the integrated system logs, and creates human-readable behavior profiles by analyzing the integrated system logs. By comparing the behavior profile of malicious application with representative behavior profile for each malware family using a weighted similarity matching technique, Andro-profiler detects and classifies it into malware families. The experiment results demonstrate that Andro-profiler is scalable, performs well in detecting and classifying malware with accuracy greater than 98 %, outperforms the existing state-of-the-art work, and is capable of identifying 0-day mobile malware samples.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>S. Bhuyan, Soumitra</author><author>Kim, Hyunmin</author><author>Isehunwa, Oluwaseyi O.</author><author>Kumar, Naveen</author><author>Bhatt, Jay</author><author>Wyant, David K.</author><author>Kedia, Satish</author><author>Chang, Cyril F.</author><author>Dasgupta, Dipankar</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Privacy and security issues in mobile health: Current research and future directions</title><secondary-title>Health Policy and Technology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Health Policy and Technology</full-title></periodical><pages>188-191</pages><volume>6</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Data privacy</keyword><keyword>Data sharing</keyword><keyword>Mhealth</keyword><keyword>Security</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><isbn>2211-8837</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.hlpt.2017.01.004</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://10.1016@j.hlpt.2017.01.004.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.hlpt.2017.01.004</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile health (mHealth) is being recognized as an innovative approach to deliver health care in an accessible, portable and cost effective manner. Despite the numerous benefits associated with the use of mobile devices, there are major concerns with mhealth in the area of privacy and security. These aspects need to be considered at every stage of design and development of mHealth devices and applications which need to be developed by security-trained, trusted manufacturers who should be accountable to minimize damages in the healthcare industry. It is also crucial for users and/or organizations to be more cautious and responsible to use mobile devices. Major stakeholders, including those in the user׳s community (patients and providers), vendors and developers, and policy makers need to come together to survey the landscape, identify the issues, and develop policies, regulations, safeguards and industry standards.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Norouzizadeh Dezfouli, Farhood</author><author>Dehghantanha, Ali</author><author>Eterovic-Soric, Brett</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Investigating Social Networking applications on smartphones detecting Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google+ artefacts on Android and iOS platforms</title><secondary-title>Australian Journal of Forensic Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Australian Journal of Forensic Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>469-488</pages><volume>48</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><isbn>http://usir.salford.ac.uk/36092/1/Investigating%20Social%20Networking%20Applications.pdf</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/00450618.2015.1066854</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://10.1080@00450618.2015.1066854.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00450618.2015.1066854</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The rapid growth in usage and application of Social Networking (SN) platforms make them a potential target by cyber criminals to conduct malicious activities such as identity theft, piracy, illegal trading, sexual harassment, cyber stalking and cyber terrorism. Many SN platforms are extending their services to mobile platforms, making them an important source of evidence in cyber investigation cases. Therefore, understanding the types of potential evidence of users’ SN activities available on mobile devices is crucial to forensic investigation and research. In this paper, we examine four popular SN applications: Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google+, on Android and iOS platforms, to detect remnants of users’ activities that are of forensic interest. We detect a variety of artefacts (e.g. usernames, passwords, login information, personal information, uploaded posts, exchanged messages and uploaded comments from SN applications) that could facilitate a criminal investigation.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Alaa, Mussab</author><author>Zaidan, A.A.</author><author>Zaidan, B.B.</author><author>Talal, Mohammed</author><author>Kiah, M.L.M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Review of Smart Home Applications based on Internet of Things</title><secondary-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</full-title></periodical><keywords><keyword>Automated home</keyword><keyword>Home automation system</keyword><keyword>Intelligent home</keyword><keyword>Internet of Things (IoT)</keyword><keyword>Remote home</keyword><keyword>Smart home application</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.jnca.2017.08.017</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://10.1016@j.jnca.2017.08.017.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1084804517302801</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The new and disruptive technology of smart home applications (hereafter referred to as apps) based on Internet of Things (IoT) is largely limited and scattered. To provide valuable insights into technological environments and support researchers, we must understand the available options and gaps in this line of research. Thus, in this study, a review is conducted to map the research landscape into a coherent taxonomy. We conduct a focused search for every article related to (1) smart homes, (2) apps, and (3) IoT in three major databases, namely, Web of Science, ScienceDirect, and IEEE Explore. These databases contain literature focusing on smart home apps using IoT. The final dataset resulting from the classification scheme includes 229 articles divided into four classes. The first class comprises review and survey articles related to smart home IoT applications. The second class includes papers on IoT applications and their use in smart home technology. The third class contains proposals of frameworks to develop and operate applications. The final class includes studies with actual attempts to develop smart home IoT applications. We then identify the basic characteristics of this emerging field in the following aspects: motivation of using IoT in smart home applications, open challenges hindering utilization, and recommendations to improve the acceptance and use of smart home applications in literature.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hu, Donghui</author><author>Ma, Zhongjin</author><author>Zhang, Xiaotian</author><author>Li, Peipei</author><author>Ye, Dengpan</author><author>Ling, Baohong</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The concept drift problem in Android malware detection and its solution</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1-11</pages><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://4956386.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Currently, the Android platform is the most popular mobile platform in the world and holds a dominant share in the mobile device market. With the popularization of the Android platform, large numbers of Android malware programs have begun to emerge on the Internet, and the sophistication of these programs is developing rapidly. While many studies have already investigated Androidmalware detection throughmachine learning and have achieved good results, most of these are based on static data sources and fail to consider the concept drift problem resulting from the rapid growth in the number of Android malware programs and normal Android applications, as well as rapid technological advancement in the Android environment. To address this problem, this work proposes a solution based on an ensemble classifier. This ensemble classifier is based on a streaming data-based Naive Bayes classifier. Android malware has identifiable feature utilization tendencies. On this basis, a feature selection algorithm is introduced into the ensemble classifier, and a sliding window is maintained inside the ensemble classifier. Based on the performance of the sub- classifiers inside the sliding window, the ensemble classifier makes dynamic adjustments to address the concept drift problem in Android malware detection. The experimental results from the proposed method demonstrate that it can effectively address the concept drift problem in Android malware detection in a streaming data environment.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Alegre-Sanahuja, Juan</author><author>Camacho, Javier</author><author>Cortés López, Juan Carlos</author><author>Santonja, Francisco José</author><author>Villanueva Micó, Rafael Jacinto</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Agent-based model to study and quantify the evolution dynamics of android malware infection</title><secondary-title>Abstract and Applied Analysis</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Abstract and Applied Analysis</full-title></periodical><volume>2014</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1155/2014/623436</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://623436.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>In the last years the number of malware Apps that the users download to their devices has risen. In this paper, we propose an agent-based model to quantify the Android malware infection evolution, modeling the behavior of the users and the different markets where the users may download Apps. The model predicts the number of infected smartphones depending on the type of malware. Additionally, we will estimate the cost that the users should afford when the malware is in their devices. We will be able to analyze which part is more critical: the users, giving indiscriminate permissions to the Apps or not protecting their devices with antivirus software, or the Android platform, due to the vulnerabilities of the Android devices that permit their rooted. We focus on the community of Valencia, Spain, although the obtained results can be extrapolated to other places where the number of Android smartphones remains fairly stable.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ham, Hyo Sik</author><author>Kim, Hwan Hee</author><author>Kim, Myung Sup</author><author>Choi, Mi Jung</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Linear SVM-based Android malware detection for reliable IoT services</title><secondary-title>Journal of Applied Mathematics</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Applied Mathematics</full-title></periodical><volume>2014</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><isbn>1110-757X</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1155/2014/594501</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://594501.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Current many Internet of Things (IoT) services are monitored and controlled through smartphone applications. By combining IoT with smartphones, many convenient IoT services have been provided to users. However, there are adverse underlying effects in such services including invasion of privacy and information leakage. In most cases, mobile devices have become cluttered with important personal user information as various services and contents are provided through them. Accordingly, attackers are expanding the scope of their attacks beyond the existing PC and Internet environment into mobile devices. In this paper, we apply a linear support vector machine (SVM) to detect Android malware and compare the malware detection performance of SVM with that of other machine learning classifiers. Through experimental validation, we show that the SVM outperforms other machine learning classifiers.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Xu, Yanping</author><author>Wu, Chunhua</author><author>Zheng, Kangfeng</author><author>Wang, Xu</author><author>Niu, Xinxin</author><author>Lu, Tianliang</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Computing Adaptive Feature Weights with PSO to Improve Android Malware Detection</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>1-14</pages><volume>2017</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/3284080</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://3284080.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, Xin</author><author>Zhang, Dafang</author><author>Su, Xin</author><author>Li, Wenjia</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Mlifdect : Android Malware Detection based on Parallel Machine Learning and Information Fusion</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1-14</pages><volume>2017</volume><keywords><keyword>android malware</keyword><keyword>information fusion</keyword><keyword>parallel machine learning</keyword><keyword>static analysis</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://6451260.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Yang, Hongyu</author><author>Tang, Ruiwen</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Power Consumption Based Android Malware Detection</title><secondary-title>Journal of Electrical and Computer Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Electrical and Computer Engineering</full-title></periodical><pages>1-7</pages><volume>2016</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1155/2016/6860217</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://6860217.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>&lt;p&gt;In order to solve the problem that Android platform’s sand-box mechanism prevents security protection software from accessing effective information to detect malware, this paper proposes a malicious software detection method based on power consumption. Firstly, the mobile battery consumption status information was obtained, and the Gaussian mixture model (GMM) was built by using Mel frequency cepstral coefficients (MFCC). Then, the GMM was used to analyze power consumption; malicious software can be classified and detected through classification processing. Experiment results demonstrate that the function of an application and its power consumption have a close relationship, and our method can detect some typical malicious application software accurately.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ahmed, M</author><author>Litchfield, AT</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Taxonomy for Identification of Security Issues in Cloud Computing Environments</title><secondary-title>Journal of Computer Information Systems</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Computer Information Systems</full-title></periodical><pages>1-10</pages><volume>00</volume><issue>00</issue><keywords><keyword>a security framework</keyword><keyword>be impacted by increased</keyword><keyword>computing and consequential changes</keyword><keyword>issues surrounding the exploitation</keyword><keyword>leaves little doubt that</keyword><keyword>most computing platforms will</keyword><keyword>of hard or</keyword><keyword>practices</keyword><keyword>security concerns</keyword><keyword>the emergence of cloud</keyword><keyword>therefore</keyword><keyword>to infrastructure and work</keyword><keyword>within the context of</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/08874417.2016.1192520</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://ahmed2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/08874417.2016.1192520</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Alazab, Ammar</author><author>Abawajy, Jemal</author><author>Hobbs, Michael</author><author>Khraisat, Ansam</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Crime Toolkits: The Current Threats to Web Applications</title><secondary-title>Journal of Information Privacy and Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Information Privacy and Security</full-title></periodical><pages>21-39</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/15536548.2013.10845677</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://alazab2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/15536548.2013.10845677</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Somarriba, Oscar</author><author>Zurutuza, Urko</author><author>Uribeetxeberria, Roberto</author><author>Delosières, Laurent</author><author>Nadjm-Tehrani, Simin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Detection and Visualization of Android Malware Behavior</title><secondary-title>Journal of Electrical and Computer Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Electrical and Computer Engineering</full-title></periodical><volume>2016</volume><issue>i</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1155/2016/8034967</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://8034967.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Malware analysts still need to manually inspect malware samples that are considered suspicious by heuristic rules. They dissect software pieces and look for malware evidence in the code. The increasing number of malicious applications targeting Android devices raises the demand for analyzing them to find where the malcode is triggered when user interacts with them. In this paper a framework to monitor and visualize Android applications’ anomalous function calls is described. Our approach includes platform-independent application instrumentation, introducing hooks in order to trace restricted API functions used at runtime of the application. These function calls are collected at a central server where the application behavior filtering and a visualization take place. This can help Android malware analysts in visually inspecting what the application under study does, easily identifying such malicious functions.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Aleroud, Ahmed</author><author>Zhou, Lina</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Phishing environments, techniques, and countermeasures: A survey</title><secondary-title>Computers and Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computers and Security</full-title></periodical><pages>160-196</pages><volume>68</volume><keywords><keyword>Honeypots</keyword><keyword>Mobile phishing</keyword><keyword>Ontology</keyword><keyword>Phishing</keyword><keyword>Phishing detection</keyword><keyword>Social engineering</keyword><keyword>Social networks phishing</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.cose.2017.04.006</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://aleroud2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cose.2017.04.006</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Phishing has become an increasing threat in online space, largely driven by the evolving web, mobile, and social networking technologies. Previous phishing taxonomies have mainly focused on the underlying mechanisms of phishing but ignored the emerging attacking techniques, targeted environments, and countermeasures for mitigating new phishing types. This survey investigates phishing attacks and anti-phishing techniques developed not only in traditional environments such as e-mails and websites, but also in new environments such as mobile and social networking sites. Taking an integrated view of phishing, we propose a taxonomy that involves attacking techniques, countermeasures, targeted environments and communication media. The taxonomy will not only provide guidance for the design of effective techniques for phishing detection and prevention in various types of environments, but also facilitate practitioners in evaluating and selecting tools, methods, and features for handling specific types of phishing problems.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Alizadeh, Mojtaba</author><author>Abolfazli, Saeid</author><author>Zamani, Mazdak</author><author>Baaaharun, Sabariah</author><author>Sakurai, Kouichi</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Authentication in mobile cloud computing: A survey</title><secondary-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</full-title></periodical><pages>59-80</pages><volume>61</volume><keywords><keyword>Authentication</keyword><keyword>Cloud computing</keyword><keyword>Mobile cloud computing</keyword><keyword>Security</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.jnca.2015.10.005</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://alizadeh2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile cloud computing (MCC) is the state-of-the-art mobile distributed computing model that incorporates multitude of heterogeneous cloud-based resources to augment computational capabilities of the plethora of resource-constraint mobile devices. In MCC, execution time and energy consumption are significantly improved by transferring execution of resource-intensive tasks such as image processing, 3D rendering, and voice recognition from the hosting mobile to the cloud-based resources. However, accessing and exploiting remote cloud-based resources is associated with numerous security and privacy implications, including user authentication and authorization. User authentication in MCC is a critical requirement in securing cloud-based computations and communications. Despite its critical role, there is a gap for a comprehensive study of the authentication approaches in MCC which can provide a deep insight into the state-of-the-art research. This paper presents a comprehensive study of authentication methods in MCC to describe MCC authentication and compare it with that of cloud computing. The taxonomy of the state-of-the-art authentication methods is devised and the most credible efforts are critically reviewed. Moreover, we present a comparison of the state-of-the-art MCC authentication methods considering five evaluation metrics. The results suggest the need for futuristic authentication methods that are designed based on capabilities and limitations of MCC environment. Finally, the design factors deemed could lead to effective authentication mechanisms are presented, and open challenges are highlighted based on the weaknesses and strengths of existing authentication methods.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Arlitsch, Kenning</author><author>Edelman, Adam</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Staying Safe: Cyber Security for People and Organizations</title><secondary-title>Journal of Library Administration</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Library Administration</full-title></periodical><pages>46-56</pages><volume>54</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/01930826.2014.893116</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://arlitsch2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/01930826.2014.893116</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This JLA column posits that academic libraries and their services are dominated by information technologies, and that the success of librarians and professional staff is contingent on their ability to thrive in this technology-rich environment.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Alexander, Bryan</author><author>Sullenger, Paula</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Libraries, Mobile Devices, and the Visible College</title><secondary-title>The Serials Librarian</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>The Serials Librarian</full-title></periodical><pages>31-43</pages><volume>66</volume><issue>1-4</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/0361526X.2014.879635</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://alexander2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/0361526X.2014.879635</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Bryan Alexander described the digital environment that we live in, giving an extensive overview of the current state of interactive devices, particularly mobile devices, which are moving us beyond the personal computer. He covered recent major developments that have transformed the world in surprising ways in a rather short period of time. The world of apps is further expanding what these devices can do, also bringing with them more challenges to individual privacy. Gaming and augmented reality are becoming deeply embedded in much of what we do. Alexander laid out four possible futures that these contemporary developments could lead to.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Anwar, Shahid</author><author>Inayat, Zakira</author><author>Zolkipli, Mohamad Fadli</author><author>Zain, Jasni Mohamad</author><author>Gani, Abdullah</author><author>Anuar, Nor Badrul</author><author>Khan, Muhammad Khurram</author><author>Chang, Victor</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Cross-VM cache-based side channel attacks and proposed prevention mechanisms: A survey</title><secondary-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</full-title></periodical><pages>259-279</pages><volume>93</volume><keywords><keyword>Cache-based Side channel attacks</keyword><keyword>Cloud computing</keyword><keyword>Countermeasures</keyword><keyword>Cross-VM Cache-based side channel attacks</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.jnca.2017.06.001</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://anwar2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jnca.2017.06.001</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The state-of-the-art Cloud Computing (CC) has been commercially popular for shared resources of third party applications. A cloud platform enables to share resources among mutually distrusting CC clients and offers cost-effective, on-demand scaling. With the exponential growth of CC environment, vulnerabilities and their corresponding exploitation of the prevailing cloud resources may potentially increase. Although CC provides numerous benefits to the cloud computing tenant. However, features namely resource sharing and Virtual Machine (VM) physical co-residency raising the potential for sensitive information leakages such as Side Channel (SC) attacks. In particular, the physical co-residency feature allows attackers to communicate with another VM on the same physical machine and leak the confidential information due to inadequate logical isolation. Unlike encryption, which protects information from being decoded by unauthorized persons, SC attacks aim to exploit the encryption systems and to hide the occurrence of communication. SC attacks were initially identified as the main threat on multi-level secure systems i.e. OS, database, and networks. More recently, the focus of the researchers has shifted toward SC attacks in CC. Since the last level cache (L2 or L3) is always shared between VM, is the most targeting device for these attacks. Therefore, the aim of this article is to explore cross-VM SC attacks involving the CPU cache and their countermeasures in CC and to compare with the traditional SC attacks and countermeasures. We categorized the SC attacks according to the hardware medium they target and exploit, the ways they access the module and the method they use to extract confidential information. We identified that traditional prevention mechanisms for SC attacks are not appropriate for prevention of cross-VM cache-based SC attacks. We also proposed countermeasures for the prevention of these attacks in order to improve security in CC.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Connor, Michael</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Editorial Preface</title><secondary-title>Journal of Autism and Developmental.Disorders</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Autism and Developmental.Disorders</full-title></periodical><pages>93-94</pages><volume>Vol 34</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>ADOLESCENTS</keyword><keyword>ARTICLE</keyword><keyword>AUTISM</keyword><keyword>Adolescent</keyword><keyword>Adult</keyword><keyword>Autism spectrum disorder</keyword><keyword>Behavioral</keyword><keyword>Biological</keyword><keyword>CHILDREN</keyword><keyword>Cognitive processing</keyword><keyword>Communication</keyword><keyword>Communication Skills</keyword><keyword>Comprehension</keyword><keyword>Control</keyword><keyword>DISORDERS</keyword><keyword>Developmental</keyword><keyword>FRONTAL LOBES</keyword><keyword>FRONTAL-LOBE</keyword><keyword>First</keyword><keyword>Frontal Lobe</keyword><keyword>Group</keyword><keyword>High functioning autism</keyword><keyword>High-functioning</keyword><keyword>KLEIN</keyword><keyword>Psychiatric</keyword><keyword>Reading</keyword><keyword>Spectrum</keyword><keyword>Work</keyword><keyword>Young Adult</keyword><keyword>adults</keyword><keyword>autism spectrum disorders</keyword><keyword>c</keyword><keyword>editorial</keyword><keyword>emotion</keyword><keyword>high-functioning autism</keyword><keyword>skill</keyword><keyword>studies</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2004</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1177/0022022117723104</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://bagchi2015.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Presents an editorial preface regarding the content of the journal &quot;Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders.&quot; This issue is a testament to the continued productivity of our field. In the first article in this issue, Hetzorni and Tannous examine the usefulness of a computer-based intervention system for enhancing communication skills in children with autism. The next article, by O'Connor and Klein, evaluates three approaches to increasing reading comprehension; this work builds on an important target for intervention that is highly relevant to individuals with autism spectrum disorders. Ozonoff and coworkers present the results of a study on the functioning of the frontal lobes in people with autism. Bradley, Summer, Wood, and Bryson are concerned with an important issue in their article-the rates of psychiatric and behavioral difficulties in adolescents and young adults with severe intellectual disability with and without autism. Dyches et al provide an article on an important but little researched topic- multicultural issues in autism. Hill, Perthoz, and Frith studied difficulties in cognitive processing of emotion in a group of individuals with high-functioning autism spectrum disorder, a group of biological relatives, and a control group of typically developing adults. (PsycINFO Database Record (c) 2004 APA, all rights reserved) Record 136 of 564 in PsycINFO (2004/01-2004/06)</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Arunkumar, S.</author><author>Srivatsa, M.</author><author>Rajarajan, M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A review paper on preserving privacy in mobile environments</title><secondary-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</full-title></periodical><pages>74-90</pages><volume>53</volume><keywords><keyword>Mobile</keyword><keyword>Privacy</keyword><keyword>Security</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><isbn>10848045 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.jnca.2015.01.008</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://arunkumar2015.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jnca.2015.01.008</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Technology is improving day-by-day and so is the usage of mobile devices. Every activity that would involve manual and paper transactions can now be completed in seconds using your fingertips. On one hand, life has become fairly convenient with the help of mobile devices, whereas on the other hand security of the data and the transactions occurring in the process have been under continuous threat. This paper, re-evaluates the different policies and procedures used for preserving the privacy of sensitive data and device location. Policy languages have been very vital in the mobile environments as they can be extended/used significantly for sending/receiving any data. In the mobile environment users always go to service providers to access various services. Hence, communications between the service providers and mobile handsets needs to be secured. Also, the data access control needs to be in place. A section of this paper will review the communication paths and channels and their related access criteria. This paper is a contribution to the mobile domain, showing the possible attacks related to privacy and the various mechanisms used to preserve the end-user privacy. In addition, it also gives a comparison of the different privacy preserving methods in mobile environments to provide guidance to the readers. Finally, the paper summarizes future research challenges in the area of privacy preservation. This paper examines the 'where' problem and in particular, examines tradeoffs between enforcing location security at a device vs. enforcing location security at an edge location server. This paper also sketches an implementation of location security solution at both the device and the edge location server and presents detailed experiments using real mobility and user profile data sets collected from multiple data sources (taxicabs, Smartphones).</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bersimis, S.</author><author>Sgora, A.</author><author>Psarakis, S.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The application of multivariate statistical process monitoring in non-industrial processes</title><secondary-title>Quality Technology and Quantitative Management</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Quality Technology and Quantitative Management</full-title></periodical><pages>1-24</pages><volume>3703</volume><issue>September</issue><keywords><keyword>[control charts, hotelling (Formula presented.) co</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/16843703.2016.1226711</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://bersimis2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/16843703.2016.1226711</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>© 2016 International Chinese Association of Quantitative ManagementStatistical process monitoring (SPM) techniques have been widely used in industry for many decades in order to assess the process stability, as well as the final product quality. Interestingly, SPM techniques have gained popularity in many non-industrial fields providing even more opportunities for research. In this paper, we consider the case of multivariate statistical process monitoring (MSPM) and perform an extensive literature review on MSPM applications in non-industrial fields. More specifically, the aim of this paper is to point out the main non-industrial application fields of MSPM that have appeared in the literature, discuss the main challenges that arise upon applying MSPM outside the industrial environment and provide some thoughts for the future of MSPM outside industry.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Barmpatsalou, Konstantia</author><author>Damopoulos, Dimitrios</author><author>Kambourakis, Georgios</author><author>Katos, Vasilios</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A critical review of 7 years of Mobile Device Forensics</title><secondary-title>Digital Investigation</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Digital Investigation</full-title></periodical><pages>323-349</pages><volume>10</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Forensic acquisition</keyword><keyword>Mobile Device Forensics</keyword><keyword>Mobile OS</keyword><keyword>Security</keyword><keyword>Smartphone</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher><isbn>1742-2876</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.diin.2013.10.003</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://barmpatsalou2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.diin.2013.10.003</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile Device Forensics (MF) is an interdisciplinary field consisting of techniques applied to a wide range of computing devices, including smartphones and satellite navigation systems. Over the last few years, a significant amount of research has been conducted, concerning various mobile device platforms, data acquisition schemes, and information extraction methods. This work provides a comprehensive overview of the field, by presenting a detailed assessment of the actions and methodologies taken throughout the last seven years. A multilevel chronological categorization of the most significant studies is given in order to provide a quick but complete way of observing the trends within the field. This categorization chart also serves as an analytic progress report, with regards to the evolution of MF. Moreover, since standardization efforts in this area are still in their infancy, this synopsis of research helps set the foundations for a common framework proposal. Furthermore, because technology related to mobile devices is evolving rapidly, disciplines in the MF ecosystem experience frequent changes. The rigorous and critical review of the state-of-the-art in this paper will serve as a resource to support efficient and effective reference and adaptation. © 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Brunton, Finn</author><author>Driscoll, Kevin</author><author>Gillespie, Tarleton</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Culture Digitally: Spam, and the Challenge of Chasing Shadows</title><secondary-title>Journal of Broadcasting &amp; Electronic Media</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Broadcasting &amp; Electronic Media</full-title></periodical><pages>687-697</pages><volume>58</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>authorship</keyword><keyword>history</keyword><keyword>internet</keyword><keyword>product obsolescence</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/08838151.2014.966366</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://brunton2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/08838151.2014.966366</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>An interview is presented with author and professor Finn Brunton that focuses on his book &quot;Spam: The Shadow History of the Internet.&quot; Topics discussed include the history of the Internet and computers, the process Brunton went through to write the book, and so-called &quot;dead end,&quot; or outdated, technology.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Borgia, Eleonora</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The internet of things vision: Key features, applications and open issues</title><secondary-title>Computer Communications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computer Communications</full-title></periodical><pages>1-31</pages><volume>54</volume><keywords><keyword>Internet of</keyword><keyword>Machine-to-Machine (M2M) communications</keyword><keyword>RFIDs</keyword><keyword>Sensors</keyword><keyword>Standardization</keyword><keyword>Things (IoT)</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier B.V.</publisher><isbn>0140-3664</isbn><accession-num>20810307</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.comcom.2014.09.008</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://borgia2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.comcom.2014.09.008</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The Internet of Things (IoT) is a new paradigm that combines aspects and technologies coming from different approaches. Ubiquitous computing, pervasive computing, Internet Protocol, sensing technologies, communication technologies, and embedded devices are merged together in order to form a system where the real and digital worlds meet and are continuously in symbiotic interaction. The smart object is the building block of the IoT vision. By putting intelligence into everyday objects, they are turned into smart objects able not only to collect information from the environment and interact/control the physical world, but also to be interconnected, to each other, through Internet to exchange data and information. The expected huge number of interconnected devices and the significant amount of available data open new opportunities to create services that will bring tangible benefits to the society, environment, economy and individual citizens. In this paper we present the key features and the driver technologies of IoT. In addition to identifying the application scenarios and the correspondent potential applications, we focus on research challenges and open issues to be faced for the IoT realization in the real world.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bhandari, Shweta</author><author>Jaballah, Wafa Ben</author><author>Jain, Vineeta</author><author>Laxmi, Vijay</author><author>Zemmari, Akka</author><author>Gaur, Manoj Singh</author><author>Mosbah, Mohamed</author><author>Conti, Mauro</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Android inter-app communication threats and detection techniques</title><secondary-title>Computers and Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computers and Security</full-title></periodical><pages>392-421</pages><volume>70</volume><keywords><keyword>App collusion</keyword><keyword>Inter component communication</keyword><keyword>Inter-app communication</keyword><keyword>Multi-app analysis</keyword><keyword>Privacy leakage</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.cose.2017.07.002</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://bhandari2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cose.2017.07.002</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>With the digital breakthrough, smart phones have become very essential component for many routine tasks like shopping, paying bills, transferring money, instant messaging, emails etc. Mobile devices are very attractive attack surface for cyber thieves as they hold personal details (accounts, locations, contacts, photos) and have potential capabilities for eavesdropping (with cameras/microphone, wireless connections). Android, being the most popular, is the target of malicious hackers who are trying to use Android app as a tool to break into and control device. Android malware authors use many anti-analysis techniques to hide from analysis tools. Academic researchers and commercial anti-malware companies are putting great effort to detect such malicious apps. They are making use of the combinations of static, dynamic and behavior-based analysis techniques. Despite of all the security mechanisms provided by Android, apps can carry out malicious actions through inter-app communication. One such inter-app communication threats is collusion. In collusion, malicious functionality is divided across multiple apps. Each participating app accomplishes its part and communicate information to another app through Inter Component Communication (ICC). ICC does not require any special permissions. Also there is no compulsion to inform user about the communication. Each participating app needs to request a minimal set of privileges, which may make it appear benign to current state-of-the-art techniques that analyze one app at a time. There are many surveys on app analysis techniques in Android; however they focus on single-app analysis. This survey highlights several inter-app communication threats, in particular collusion among multiple-apps. In this paper, we present Android vulnerabilities that may be exploited for carrying privilege escalation attacks, privacy leakage and collusion attacks. We cover the existing threat analysis, scenarios, and a detailed comparison of tools for intra- and inter-app analysis. To the best of our knowledge this is the first survey on inter-app communication threats, app collusion and state-of-the-art detection tools in Android.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Buchanan, Ben</author><author>Buchanan, Ben</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Cryptography and Sovereignty</title><secondary-title>Survival</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Survival</full-title></periodical><pages>95-122</pages><volume>58</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/00396338.2016.1231534</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://buchanan2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Cryptography has gone mainstream. Now more than ever, encryption is used by ordinary citizens, often without their knowledge, and is a subject of national debate.1 Intelligence and law-enforcement officials warn of the dangers of messages they cannot read.2 Presidents and prime ministers weigh in on the way cryptography shapes the balance between liberty and security.3 The Edward Snowden revelations drive encryption-related cover- age in major newspapers, even as the technology is rolled out by increasing numbers of companies over government objections.4 All told, it may be the most international attention a mathematical concept has received since the space race.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Brandenburg, Caitlin</author><author>Worrall, Linda E</author><author>Copland, David</author><author>Power, Emma</author><author>Rodriguez, Amy D.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The development and accuracy testing of CommFit™, an iPhone application for individuals with aphasia</title><secondary-title>Aphasiology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Aphasiology</full-title></periodical><pages>1-19</pages><volume>7038</volume><issue>April</issue><keywords><keyword>aphasia</keyword><keyword>digital</keyword><keyword>mobile technology</keyword><keyword>participation</keyword><keyword>smartphone</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><isbn>0268-7038</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/02687038.2015.1028329</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://brandenburg2015.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www-tandfonline-com.proxy.library.dmu.ac.uk/doi/full/10.1080/02687038.2015.1028329#abstract</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Background: There has been an increasing amount of focus on measuring the ICF concept of participation in the rehabilitation of people with aphasia. The amount of time that people with aphasia talk has the potential to be used as an indicator of participation for this population. However, in order to measure talk time, an accurate, portable, and usable biofeedback tool is required. This paper details the development and accuracy testing of the CommFit™ iPhone application, which, paired with a BlueTooth headset, times the talk of the user.Aims: The aim of development of CommFit™ was to maximise the likelihood that the app would be usable by people with stroke and aphasia. Accordingly, aphasia-friendly text principles and other features of accessibility were integrated into the design, which is described in detail in this paper. The purpose of this study was to investigate the accuracy of CommFit™ in quantifying talk time in everyday environments in a small number of healthy adults.Methods &amp; Procedures: Par...</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Busis, Neil</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Mobile Phones to Improve the Practice of Neurology</title><secondary-title>Neurologic Clinics</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Neurologic Clinics</full-title></periodical><pages>395-410</pages><volume>28</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Information technology</keyword><keyword>Mobile phones</keyword><keyword>Neurology practice</keyword><keyword>Smartphones</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2010</year></dates><isbn>0733-8619</isbn><accession-num>20202500</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.ncl.2009.11.001</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://busis2010.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Smartphones make mobile computing at point of care practical. Smartphones can think, sync, and link. Built-in and user-installed applications facilitate communications between neurologists and their medical colleagues and patients and augment data acquisition and processing in the core medical information domains of patient data, clinical decision support, and practice management. Mobile telemedicine is becoming practical in certain scenarios. Smartphones can improve neurologic diagnosis and treatment, teaching, and research. Patients can benefit from smartphone technology. In addition to enhanced communication, patient education, and social networking, these devices can promote healthy lifestyles, preventive medicine, and compliance and even serve as monitoring and prosthetic devices. ?? 2010 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Daryabar, Farid</author><author>Dehghantanha, Ali</author><author>Eterovic-Soric, Brett</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author><author>Federici, Corrado</author><author>Daryabar, Farid</author><author>Dehghantanha, Ali</author><author>Eterovic-Soric, Brett</author><author>Daryabar, Farid</author><author>Dehghantanha, Ali</author><author>Eterovic-Soric, Brett</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Forensic investigation of OneDrive, Box, GoogleDrive and Dropbox applications on Android and iOS devices</title><secondary-title>Australian Journal of Forensic Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Australian Journal of Forensic Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>1-28</pages><volume>48</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Android forensic</keyword><keyword>Cloud computing</keyword><keyword>Cloud storage</keyword><keyword>Computer forensics</keyword><keyword>Dropbox</keyword><keyword>Google Drive</keyword><keyword>ISO/IEC 27037</keyword><keyword>Interoperability</keyword><keyword>Microsoft Skydrive</keyword><keyword>Remote forensic acquisition</keyword><keyword>Virtual volume</keyword><keyword>cloud forensics</keyword><keyword>cloud storage applications forensics</keyword><keyword>digital forensics</keyword><keyword>iOS forensic</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/00450618.2015.1110620</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://daryabar2016(1).pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S174228761400005X</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>In today’s Internet-connected world, mobile devices are increasingly used to access cloud storage services, which allow users to access data anywhere, anytime. Mobile devices have, however, been known to be used and/or targeted by cyber criminals to conduct malicious activities, such as data exfiltration, malware, identity theft, piracy, illegal trading, sexual harassment, cyber stalking and cyber terrorism. Conse- quently, mobile devices are an increasing important source of evidence in digital investigations. In this paper, we examine four popular cloud client apps, namely OneDrive, Box, GoogleDrive, and Dropbox, on both Android and iOS platforms (two of the most popular mobile operating systems). We identify artefacts of foren- sic interest, such as information generated during login, uploading, downloading, deletion, and the sharing of files. These findings may assist forensic examiners and practitioners in real-world examination of cloud client applications on Android and iOS platforms.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Chanajitt, Rajchada</author><author>Viriyasitavat, Wantanee</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Forensic analysis and security assessment of Android m-banking apps</title><secondary-title>Australian Journal of Forensic Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Australian Journal of Forensic Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>1-17</pages><volume>0618</volume><issue>May</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><isbn>1834-562X\r0045-0618</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/00450618.2016.1182589</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://chanajitt2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00450618.2016.1182589</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>© 2016 Australian Academy of Forensic SciencesThe increasing popularity and constant evolution of mobile technologies have resulted in an increased focus in mobile device and app security and forensics research. Banking apps appear to be an understudied topic, despite their popularity with consumers. In this paper, seven Android m-banking apps in Thailand are analysed. Based on the findings of our study, we describe the forensic artefacts that could be forensically recovered from the apps, and the findings of security assessment of the apps. For example, we found that several of the apps do not implement root device detection, do not encrypt user data, or it is possible to modify the apps and install repackaged apps.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Das, Saini</author><author>Mukhopadhyay, Arunabha</author><author>Bagchi, Kallol K.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>National-Level Determinants of Global Music Piracy and Online Music Sales: An Exploratory Study</title><secondary-title>Journal of Global Information Technology Management</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Global Information Technology Management</full-title></periodical><pages>6-25</pages><volume>17</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/1097198X.2014.910988</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://das2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/1097198X.2014.910988</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Piracy adversely affects online music sales. This article aims to investigate the factors that affect global music piracy directly and electronic business indirectly. These factors can be grouped into three categories: economic, legal/regulatory, and technological. On analyzing data from 68 countries, a country’s economic status and regulatory status emerge as the primary factors affecting music piracy. Technology indirectly affects music piracy by acting as a mediator between a nation’s economic status and the music piracy rate. Hence, a nation can reduce its music piracy rate and enhance e-business by devising stricter laws to safeguard intellectual property, punishing violations of information and communication technology related laws more strictly, allowing more free trade with other countries, inspiring attitudinal changes about inappropriate copying behavior through awareness campaigns, and encouraging increased and secure broadband usage.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Daryabar, Farid</author><author>Dehghantanha, Ali</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Cloud storage forensics: MEGA as a case study</title><secondary-title>Australian Journal of Forensic Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Australian Journal of Forensic Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>344-357</pages><volume>49</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><isbn>9780124199705</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/00450618.2016.1153714</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://daryabar2016(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00450618.2016.1153714</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The increasing use of smartphones and cloud storage apps allows users to access their data anywhere, anytime. Due to the potential of mobile devices being used and/or targeted by criminals, such devices are an important source of evidence in investigations of both cybercrime and traditional crimes, such as drug trafficking. In this paper, we study the MEGA cloud client app, an increasingly popular alternative to Google Drive, Dropbox and OneDrive, on both Android and iOS platforms. In our study, we identify a range of artefacts arising from user activities, such as login, uploading, downloading, deletion, and the sharing of files, which could be forensically recovered, as well as findings such as modification of files’ timestamps. Our findings contribute to an up-to-date understanding of cloud storage forensics.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Feizollah, Ali</author><author>Anuar, Nor Badrul</author><author>Salleh, Rosli</author><author>Wahab, Ainuddin Wahid Abdul</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A review on feature selection in mobile malware detection</title><secondary-title>Digital Investigation</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Digital Investigation</full-title></periodical><pages>22-37</pages><volume>13</volume><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>Feature selection</keyword><keyword>Mobile malware</keyword><keyword>Mobile operating system</keyword><keyword>Review paper</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher><isbn>978-1-4673-2358-1</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.diin.2015.02.001</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://feizollah2015.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.diin.2015.02.001</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The widespread use of mobile devices in comparison to personal computers has led to a new era of information exchange. The purchase trends of personal computers have started decreasing whereas the shipment of mobile devices is increasing. In addition, the increasing power of mobile devices along with portability characteristics has attracted the attention of users. Not only are such devices popular among users, but they are favorite targets of attackers. The number of mobile malware is rapidly on the rise with malicious activities, such as stealing users data, sending premium messages and making phone call to premium numbers that users have no knowledge. Numerous studies have developed methods to thwart such attacks. In order to develop an effective detection system, we have to select a subset of features from hundreds of available features. In this paper, we studied 100 research works published between 2010 and 2014 with the perspective of feature selection in mobile malware detection. We categorize available features into four groups, namely, static features, dynamic features, hybrid features and applications metadata. Additionally, we discuss datasets used in the recent research studies as well as analyzing evaluation measures utilized.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Fang, Zheran</author><author>Han, Weili</author><author>Li, Yingjiu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Permission based Android security: Issues and countermeasures</title><secondary-title>Computers and Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computers and Security</full-title></periodical><pages>205-218</pages><volume>43</volume><issue>0</issue><keywords><keyword>Access control</keyword><keyword>Android security</keyword><keyword>Granularity of access control</keyword><keyword>Over-claim of permission</keyword><keyword>Permission based security</keyword><keyword>Permission escalation attack</keyword><keyword>Policy administration</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher><isbn>0167-4048</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.cose.2014.02.007</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://fang2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cose.2014.02.007</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Android security has been a hot spot recently in both academic research and public concerns due to numerous instances of security attacks and privacy leakage on Android platform. Android security has been built upon a permission based mechanism which restricts accesses of third-party Android applications to critical resources on an Android device. Such permission based mechanism is widely criticized for its coarse-grained control of application permissions and difficult management of permissions by developers, marketers, and end-users. In this paper, we investigate the arising issues in Android security, including coarse granularity of permissions, incompetent permission administration, insufficient permission documentation, over-claim of permissions, permission escalation attack, and TOCTOU (Time of Check to Time of Use) attack. We illustrate the relationships among these issues, and investigate the existing countermeasures to address these issues. In particular, we provide a systematic review on the development of these countermeasures, and compare them according to their technical features. Finally, we propose several methods to further mitigate the risk in Android security. © 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Herrero, Juan</author><author>Urueña, Alberto</author><author>Torres, Andrea</author><author>Hidalgo, Antonio</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Smartphone addiction: psychosocial correlates, risky attitudes, and smartphone harm</title><secondary-title>Journal of Risk Research</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Risk Research</full-title></periodical><pages>1-12</pages><volume>9877</volume><issue>July</issue><keywords><keyword>Smartphone addiction</keyword><keyword>malware</keyword><keyword>personality</keyword><keyword>sensation seeking</keyword><keyword>social support</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Routledge</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/13669877.2017.1351472</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://herrero2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13669877.2017.1351472</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>© 2017 Informa UK Limited, trading as Taylor  &amp;  Francis Group Smartphone use has brought convenience to users, although its excessive use and addiction might also have negative consequences. Using a representative sample of 526 smartphone users in Spain, the present study analyzes smartphone extensive use and addiction as well as its relationship to smartphone harm. Self-reported and scanned data were obtained from users and their smartphones. Multivariate linear regression analyses showed that higher levels of smartphone extensive use were found for female respondents, those high on general propensity to risk, neuroticism, and low on conscientiousness, openness, or social support. Multivariate binary logistic results showed that general propensity to risk and low social support were predictive of smartphone addiction. The combination of high smartphone extensive use and low social support was positively and significantly related to the existence of smartphone harm as well as higher levels of risk attitudes toward smartphone use. These results might indicate that when low social support is coupled with an extensive smartphone use, respondents not only show a more positive attitude toward risky behaviors while using their smartphone but, also, a greater level of harm is found in their terminals.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Harris, Mark A.</author><author>Furnell, Steven</author><author>Patten, Karen</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Comparing the Mobile Device Security Behavior of College Students and Information Technology Professionals</title><secondary-title>Journal of Information Privacy and Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Information Privacy and Security</full-title></periodical><pages>186-202</pages><volume>10</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/15536548.2014.974429</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://harris2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/15536548.2014.974429</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile devices are now a standard part of both personal and workplace information technology (IT) usage. However, they introduce a variety of security concerns that users are failing to address. This article examines and compares the security preparedness of 227 IT and non-IT college students about to enter the workforce and 83 predominately non-security-focused IT professionals. Results indicate that all groups put their data and connected networks at risk by failing to properly secure their personal mobile devices. Suggestions include organizational mobile device security policies and mobile device security awareness and training for both current and incoming employees.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Imgraben, James</author><author>Engelbrecht, Alewyn</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Always connected, but are smart mobile users getting more security savvy? A survey of smart mobile device users</title><secondary-title>Behaviour &amp; Information Technology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Behaviour &amp; Information Technology</full-title></periodical><pages>1347-1360</pages><volume>33</volume><issue>12</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><isbn>0144-929X</isbn><accession-num>98861324</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/0144929X.2014.934286</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://imgraben2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/0144929X.2014.934286</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Smart mobile devices are a potential attack vector for cyber criminal activities. Two hundred and fifty smart mobile device owners from the University of South Australia were surveyed. Not surprisingly, it was found that smart mobile device users in the survey generally underestimated the value that their collective identities have to criminals and how these can be sold. For example, participants who reported jail-breaking/rooting their devices were also more likely to exhibit risky behaviour (e.g. downloading and installing applications from unknown providers), and the participants generally had no idea of the value of their collective identities to criminals which can be sold to the highest bidder. In general, the participants did not understand the risks and may not have perceived cyber crime to be a real threat. Findings from the survey and the escalating complexities of the end-user mobile and online environment underscore the need for regular ongoing training programs for basic online security and the promotion of a culture of security among smart mobile device users. For example, targeted education and awareness programmes could be developed to inform or educate smart mobile device users and correct misconceptions or myths in order to bring about changes in attitudes and usage behaviour (e.g. not taking preventative measures such as strong passwords to protect their devices). Such initiatives would enable all end users (including senior University management who use such devices to access privileged corporate data and accounts) to maintain current knowledge of the latest cyber crime activities and the best cyber security protection measures available. [ABSTRACT FROM AUTHOR]</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hussain, Muzammil</author><author>Al-Haiqi, Ahmed</author><author>Zaidan, A. A.</author><author>Zaidan, B. B.</author><author>Kiah, M. L.M.</author><author>Anuar, Nor Badrul</author><author>Abdulnabi, Mohamed</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The landscape of research on smartphone medical apps: Coherent taxonomy, motivations, open challenges and recommendations</title><secondary-title>Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine</full-title></periodical><pages>393-408</pages><volume>122</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Medical and health apps</keyword><keyword>Mobile health</keyword><keyword>Smartphone apps</keyword><keyword>Survey</keyword><keyword>Taxonomy</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ireland Ltd</publisher><isbn>9781450311564</isbn><accession-num>26412009</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.cmpb.2015.08.015</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://hussain2015.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cmpb.2015.08.015</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Objective: To survey researchers' efforts in response to the new and disruptive technology of smartphone medical apps, mapping the research landscape form the literature into a coherent taxonomy, and finding out basic characteristics of this emerging field represented on: motivation of using smartphone apps in medicine and healthcare, open challenges that hinder the utility, and the recommendations to improve the acceptance and use of medical apps in the literature. Methods: We performed a focused search for every article on (1) smartphone (2) medical or health-related (3) app, in four major databases: MEDLINE, Web of Science, ScienceDirect, and IEEE Xplore. Those databases are deemed broad enough to cover both medical and technical literature. Results: The final set included 133 articles. Most articles (68/133) are reviews and surveys that refer to actual apps or the literature to describe medical apps for a specific specialty, disease, or purpose; or to provide a general overview of the technology. Another group (43/133) carried various studies, from evaluation of apps to exploration of desired features when developing them. Few researchers (17/133) presented actual attempts to develop medical apps, or shared their experiences in doing so. The smallest portion (5/133) proposed general frameworks addressing the production or operation of apps. Discussion: Since 2010, researchers followed the trend of medical apps in several ways, though leaving areas or aspect for further attention. Regardless of their category, articles focus on the challenges that hinder the full utility of medical apps and do recommend mitigations to them. Conclusions: Research on smartphone medical apps is active and various. We hope that this survey contribute to the understanding of the available options and gaps for other researchers to join this line of research.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kalaimannan, Ezhil</author><author>John, Sharon K</author><author>Dubose, Theresa</author><author>Pinto, Anthony</author><author>Kalaimannan, Ezhil</author><author>John, Sharon K</author><author>Dubose, Theresa</author><author>Pinto, Anthony</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Influences on ransomware ’ s evolution and predictions for the future challenges</title><secondary-title>Journal of Cyber Security Technology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Cyber Security Technology</full-title></periodical><pages>23-31</pages><volume>1</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Ransomware</keyword><keyword>application security</keyword><keyword>cybercriminals</keyword><keyword>cybersecurity</keyword><keyword>information technology</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/23742917.2016.1252191</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://kalaimannan2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/23742917.2016.1252191</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>ABSTRACTThe inception of malware disguised as a solution to fix a problem to the current sophisticated malware demanding huge money, ransomware has attained significant proliferation through various advancements in information technologies. As a result of this development, cybercriminals have become adept and highly successful in compromising advanced information systems. Computer and network systems infected with ransomware are also often infected with various forms of malicious software. Ransomware targets have become more educated, aware and cautious of malware, motivating cybercriminals to respond with innovative attacks. In this paper, we analyse the evolution of ransomware from the perspective of what makes an individual or an organisation susceptible to the succumbing demands of ransomware. Finally, we conclude with few suggestions about the predictions of future trends of ransomware.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Iqbal, Salman</author><author>Mat Kiah, Miss Laiha</author><author>Dhaghighi, Babak</author><author>Hussain, Muzammil</author><author>Khan, Suleman</author><author>Khan, Muhammad Khurram</author><author>Raymond Choo, Kim Kwang</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>On cloud security attacks: A taxonomy and intrusion detection and prevention as a service</title><secondary-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</full-title></periodical><pages>98-120</pages><volume>74</volume><keywords><keyword>Cloud computing</keyword><keyword>Intrusion detection</keyword><keyword>Security attacks</keyword><keyword>Taxonomy</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.jnca.2016.08.016</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://iqbal2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jnca.2016.08.016</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Major provisioning of cloud computing is mainly delivered via Software as a Service, Platform as a Service and Infrastructure as a Service. However, these service delivery models are vulnerable to a range of security attacks, exploiting both cloud specific and existing web service vulnerabilities. Taxonomies are a useful tool for system designers as they provide a systematic way of understanding, identifying and addressing security risks. In this research work, Cloud based attacks and vulnerabilities are collected and classify with respect to their cloud models. We also present taxonomy of cloud security attacks and potential mitigation strategies with the aim of providing an in-depth understanding of security requirements in the cloud environment. We also highlight the importance of intrusion detection and prevention as a service.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Karcher, Nicole R.</author><author>Presser, Nan R.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Ethical and Legal Issues Addressing the Use of Mobile Health (mHealth) as an Adjunct to Psychotherapy</title><secondary-title>Ethics &amp; Behavior</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Ethics &amp; Behavior</full-title></periodical><pages>1-22</pages><volume>00</volume><issue>00</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Routledge</publisher><isbn>10508422 (ISSN)</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/10508422.2016.1229187</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://karcher2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10508422.2016.1229187</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>mHealth refers to the rapidly evolving use of mobile devices for health care treatment purposes, particularly the use of apps and texting as adjuncts to psychotherapy. Although there is currently an extensive literature on issues related to telehealth, to date little guidance has been developed to help professionals function ethically in the rapidly emerging area of mHealth. This article identifies the major ethical considerations that need attention and proposes several recommendations to address mHealth use as an adjunct to psychotherapy, including the pressing need for relevant American Psychological Association practice guidelines to assist mental health providers in the ethical implementation of mHealth. Copyright © 2016 Taylor &amp; Francis Group, LLC</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kallender, Paul</author><author>Hughes, Christopher W.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Japan’s Emerging Trajectory as a ‘Cyber Power’: From Securitization to Militarization of Cyberspace</title><secondary-title>Journal of Strategic Studies</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Strategic Studies</full-title></periodical><pages>118-145</pages><volume>40</volume><issue>1-2</issue><keywords><keyword>China</keyword><keyword>Japan</keyword><keyword>US–Japan alliance</keyword><keyword>cybersecurity</keyword><keyword>securitization</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Routledge</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/01402390.2016.1233493</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://kallender2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01402390.2016.1233493</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Japan has been overlooked as a ‘cyber power’ but it now becoming a serious player in this new strategic domain. Japanese policy-makers have forged a consensus to move cybersecurity to the very core of national security policy, to create more centralized frameworks for cybersecurity, and for Japan’s military institutions to build dynamic cyberdefense capabilities. Japan’s stance has moved rapidly toward the securitization and now militarization of responses to cyber challenges. Japan’s cybersecurity stance has bolstered US–Japan alliance responses to securing all dimensions of the ‘global com- mons’ and extended its defense perimeter to further deter but potentially raise tensions with China.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lee, Hwan-Taek</author><author>Kim, Dongjin</author><author>Park, Minkyu</author><author>Cho, Seong-je</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Protecting data on android platform against privilege escalation attack</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Computer Mathematics</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Computer Mathematics</full-title></periodical><pages>401-414</pages><volume>93</volume><issue>2, SI</issue><keywords><keyword>68N25; 97P30; system call hooking; privilege escal</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><isbn>0020-7160</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/00207160.2014.986113</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://lee2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The users of smartphones are rapidly expanding worldwide. These devices\nhave user's security-sensitive data and are ready to communicate with\nthe outside world. Various kinds of malware are attacking smartphones,\nespecially Android phones, but the existing Android security measure\ndoes not work satisfactorily. One-third of the current Android malware\nwere privilege escalation attacks, which try to obtain root-privilege to\nfully compromise the Android security. We propose a detection and\nprevention scheme that protects Android against such privilege\nescalation attack that tries to get full access to all data. The\nproposed scheme monitors important system calls from an application\nprocess. If the system call must be called by privileged Android system\ncomponents in normal operation, the scheme prevent it from executing.\nThe scheme can detect and prevent new and unknown malware as well as\ncurrently known one.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kumar, Gulshan</author><author>Kumar, Krishan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Network security – an updated perspective</title><secondary-title>Systems Science &amp; Control Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Systems Science &amp; Control Engineering</full-title></periodical><pages>325-334</pages><volume>2</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>cyber attacks</keyword><keyword>data breaches</keyword><keyword>intrusions</keyword><keyword>network security</keyword><keyword>security intelligence</keyword><keyword>security threats</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/21642583.2014.895969</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://kumar2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/21642583.2014.895969</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Network security is a specialized field consisting of the provisions and policies to prevent and monitor unauthorized access, misuse, modification, or denial of a computer network and network-accessible resources as well as ensuring their availability through proper procedures. Many security devices are being developed and deployed to defend against cyber threats and to prevent unintended data breaches. In spite of all these efforts, the ‘golden age’ of cyber crime continues, as organizations around the world continue to suffer data breaches and security attacks. What kinds of threats we are facing today? How these threats are to be dealt with? The goal of this paper is to communicate an updated perspective of network security for organizations, and researchers in the field and present some recommendations to tackle the current situation of security threats.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Malone, Eloise F</author><author>Malone, Michael J</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The “wicked problem” of cybersecurity policy: analysis of United States and Canadian policy response</title><secondary-title>Canadian Foreign Policy Journal</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Canadian Foreign Policy Journal</full-title></periodical><pages>158-177</pages><volume>19</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/11926422.2013.805152</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://malone2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/11926422.2013.805152</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This article analyses policy response to cyber security issues. By comparing U.S. and Canadian responses, the authors conclude that the nature of cyberspace, defined as a public good with market value as well as an offensive and defensive tool, does not correspond with prevailing public policy models. The authors arrive at this conclusion by a chronological review of technological development, an analysis of conventional models, and consideration of existing public policy.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Li, Li</author><author>Bissyandé, Tegawendé F.</author><author>Papadakis, Mike</author><author>Rasthofer, Siegfried</author><author>Bartel, Alexandre</author><author>Octeau, Damien</author><author>Klein, Jacques</author><author>Traon, Le</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Static analysis of android apps: A systematic literature review</title><secondary-title>Information and Software Technology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Information and Software Technology</full-title></periodical><pages>67-95</pages><volume>88</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><isbn>9782879711508</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.infsof.2017.04.001</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://li2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Context Static analysis exploits techniques that parse program source code or bytecode, often traversing program paths to check some program properties. Static analysis approaches have been proposed for different tasks, including for assessing the security of Android apps, detecting app clones, automating test cases generation, or for uncovering non-functional issues related to performance or energy. The literature thus has proposed a large body of works, each of which attempts to tackle one or more of the several challenges that program analyzers face when dealing with Android apps. Objective We aim to provide a clear view of the state-of-the-art works that statically analyze Android apps, from which we highlight the trends of static analysis approaches, pinpoint where the focus has been put, and enumerate the key aspects where future researches are still needed. Method We have performed a systematic literature review (SLR) which involves studying 124 research papers published in software engineering, programming languages and security venues in the last 5 years (January 2011–December 2015). This review is performed mainly in five dimensions: problems targeted by the approach, fundamental techniques used by authors, static analysis sensitivities considered, android characteristics taken into account and the scale of evaluation performed. Results Our in-depth examination has led to several key findings: 1) Static analysis is largely performed to uncover security and privacy issues; 2) The Soot framework and the Jimple intermediate representation are the most adopted basic support tool and format, respectively; 3) Taint analysis remains the most applied technique in research approaches; 4) Most approaches support several analysis sensitivities, but very few approaches consider path-sensitivity; 5) There is no single work that has been proposed to tackle all challenges of static analysis that are related to Android programming; and 6) Only a small portion of state-of-the-art works have made their artifacts publicly available. Conclusion The research community is still facing a number of challenges for building approaches that are aware altogether of implicit-Flows, dynamic code loading features, reflective calls, native code and multi-threading, in order to implement sound and highly precise static analyzers.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Marks, Larry</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Book Review of Blackjacking: Security Threats to Blackberry Devices, PDAs and Cell Phones in the Enterprise by Daniel V. Hoffman</title><secondary-title>Edpacs</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Edpacs</full-title></periodical><pages>17-18</pages><volume>46</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2012</year></dates><isbn>9780470127544</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/07366981.2012.687561</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://marks2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/07366981.2012.687561</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Marks, Larry</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Book Review of Blackjacking: Security Threats to Blackberry Devices, PDAs and Cell Phones in the Enterprise by Daniel V. Hoffman</title><secondary-title>Edpacs</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Edpacs</full-title></periodical><pages>17-18</pages><volume>46</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2012</year></dates><isbn>9780470127544</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/07366981.2012.687561</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://marks2012(1).pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/07366981.2012.687561</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Leukfeldt, Eric Rutger</author><author>Yar, Majid</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Applying Routine Activity Theory to Cybercrime: A Theoretical and Empirical Analysis</title><secondary-title>Deviant Behavior</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Deviant Behavior</full-title></periodical><pages>263-280</pages><volume>37</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/01639625.2015.1012409</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://leukfeldt2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01639625.2015.1012409</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The central question of this article is whether routine activity theory (RAT) can be used as an analytical framework to study cybercrimes. Both a theoretical analysis and an analysis of empirical studies have thus far failed to provide a clear answer. The multivariate analysis presented in this article tries to avoid some of the limitations of other RAT-based studies. Based on a large sample (N = 9,161), the effects of value, visibility, accessibility, and guardianship on victimization of six cybercrimes have been studied. Analysis shows some RAT elements are more applicable than others. Visibility clearly plays a role within cybercrime victimization. Accessibility and personal capable guardianship show varying results. Value and technical capable guardianship show almost no effects on cybercrime victimization.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mackey, Tim K.</author><author>Nayyar, Gaurvika</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A review of existing and emerging digital technologies to combat the global trade in fake medicines</title><secondary-title>Expert Opinion on Drug Safety</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Expert Opinion on Drug Safety</full-title></periodical><pages>587-602</pages><volume>16</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>anti-counterfeit</keyword><keyword>counterfeit medicines</keyword><keyword>fake medicines</keyword><keyword>falsified medicines</keyword><keyword>health technology</keyword><keyword>online pharmacies</keyword><keyword>substandard medicines</keyword><keyword>supply chain</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</publisher><accession-num>28349715</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/14740338.2017.1313227</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://mackey2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/14740338.2017.1313227</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Introduction: The globalization of the pharmaceutical supply chain has introduced new challenges, chief among them, fighting the international criminal trade in fake medicines. As the manufacture, supply, and distribution of drugs becomes more complex, so does the need for innovative technology-based solutions to protect patients globally. Areas covered: We conducted a multidisciplinary review of the science/health, information technology, computer science, and general academic literature with the aim of identifying cutting-edge existing and emerging “digital” solutions to combat fake medicines. Our review identified five distinct categories of technology including mobile, radio frequency identification, advanced computational methods, online verification, and block chain technology. Expert opinion: Digital fake medicine solutions are unifying platforms that integrate different types of anti-counterfeiting technologies as complementary solutions, improve information sharing and data collection, and are designed to overcome existing barriers of adoption and implementation. Investment in this next generation technology is essential to ensure the future security and integrity of the global drug supply chain.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mollah, Muhammad Baqer</author><author>Azad, Md Abul Kalam</author><author>Vasilakos, Athanasios</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Security and privacy challenges in mobile cloud computing: Survey and way ahead</title><secondary-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</full-title></periodical><pages>38-54</pages><volume>84</volume><keywords><keyword>Cloud computing</keyword><keyword>Computational offloading</keyword><keyword>Mobile computing</keyword><keyword>Security and privacy</keyword><keyword>Virtualization</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.jnca.2017.02.001</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://mollah2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jnca.2017.02.001</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The rapid growth of mobile computing is seriously challenged by the resource constrained mobile devices. However, the growth of mobile computing can be enhanced by integrating mobile computing into cloud computing, and hence a new paradigm of computing called mobile cloud computing emerges. In here, the data is stored in cloud infrastructure and the actual execution is shifted to cloud environment so that a mobile user is set free from resource constrained issue of existing mobile devices. Moreover, to avail the cloud services, the communications between mobile devices and clouds are held through wireless medium. Thus, some new classes of security and privacy challenges are introduced. The purpose of this survey is to present the main security and privacy challenges in this field which have grown much interest among the academia and research community. Although, there are many challenges, corresponding security solutions have been proposed and identified in literature by many researchers to counter the challenges. We also present these recent works in short. Furthermore, we compare these works based on different security and privacy requirements, and finally present open issues.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>McGill, Tanya</author><author>Thompson, Nik</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Old risks, new challenges: exploring differences in security between home computer and mobile device use</title><secondary-title>Behaviour &amp; Information Technology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Behaviour &amp; Information Technology</full-title></periodical><pages>1-14</pages><volume>0</volume><issue>0</issue><keywords><keyword>Information security behaviours</keyword><keyword>home computer security</keyword><keyword>human factors</keyword><keyword>mobile</keyword><keyword>mobile device security</keyword><keyword>smartphone</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/0144929X.2017.1352028</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://mcgill2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0144929X.2017.1352028</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>ABSTRACTHome users are particularly vulnerable to information security threats as they must make decisions about how to protect themselves, often with little knowledge of the technology. Furthermore, information for home users tends to focus on the traditional PC and may downplay threats faced on mobile devices, transforming well-known and old risks into new challenges for information security. To address the need for more behavioural information security research that focusses on mobile devices, this paper reports on the first large-scale study comparing security perceptions and behaviours on home computer and mobile devices. Data from 629 users revealed that in addition to differences in information security behaviour, the following security-related perceptions all differ significantly between home computer and mobile device use: perceived severity, security self-efficacy, response efficacy, response cost, descriptive norm, psychological ownership and intention to perform security behaviours. In each ca...</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sanz, Borja</author><author>Santos, Igor</author><author>Laorden, Carlos</author><author>Ugarte-Pedrero, Xabier</author><author>Nieves, Javier</author><author>Bringas, Pablo G.</author><author>Álvarez Marañón, Gonzalo</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Mama: Manifest Analysis for Malware Detection in Android</title><secondary-title>Cybernetics and Systems</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Cybernetics and Systems</full-title></periodical><pages>469-488</pages><volume>44</volume><issue>6-7</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/01969722.2013.803889</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://sanz20132.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/01969722.2013.803889</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sanz, Borja</author><author>Santos, Igor</author><author>Laorden, Carlos</author><author>Ugarte-Pedrero, Xabier</author><author>Nieves, Javier</author><author>Bringas, Pablo G.</author><author>Álvarez Marañón, Gonzalo</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Mama: Manifest Analysis for Malware Detection in Android</title><secondary-title>Cybernetics and Systems</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Cybernetics and Systems</full-title></periodical><pages>469-488</pages><volume>44</volume><issue>6-7</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/01969722.2013.803889</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://sanz20132.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/01969722.2013.803889</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Razak, Mohd Faizal Ab</author><author>Anuar, Nor Badrul</author><author>Salleh, Rosli</author><author>Firdaus, Ahmad</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The rise of “malware”: Bibliometric analysis of malware study</title><secondary-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</full-title></periodical><pages>58-76</pages><volume>75</volume><keywords><keyword>Bibliometric analysis</keyword><keyword>Intrusion detection system</keyword><keyword>Malware</keyword><keyword>Malware analysis</keyword><keyword>Mobile malware</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.jnca.2016.08.022</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://razak2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jnca.2016.08.022</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Malicious software (malware) is a computer program designed to create harmful and undesirable effects. It considered as one of the many dangerous threats for Internet users. Rootkit, botnet, worm, spyware and Trojan horse are the most common types of malware. Most malware studies aim to investigate novel approaches of preventing, detecting and responding to malware threats. However, despite the many articles published to support the research activities, there is still no trace of any bibliometric report that demonstrates the research trends. This paper aims to fill in that gap by presenting a comprehensive evaluation of malware research practices. It begins by looking at a pool of over 4000 articles that are published between 2005 and 2015 in the ISI Web of Science database. Using bibliometric analysis, this paper discusses the research activities done in both North America, Asia and other continents. This paper performed a detailed analysis by looking at the number of articles published, citations, research area, keywords, institutions, terms, and authors. A summary of the research activities continues by listing the terms into a classification of malware detection system which underlines the important area of malware research. From the analysis, it was concluded that there are several significant impacts of research activities in Asia, in comparison to other continents. In particular, this paper discusses the number of papers published by Asian countries such as China, Korea, India, Singapore and Malaysia in relation to the Middle East and North America.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Nissim, Nir</author><author>Cohen, Aviad</author><author>Glezer, Chanan</author><author>Elovici, Yuval</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Detection of malicious PDF files and directions for enhancements: A state-of-the art survey</title><secondary-title>Computers and Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computers and Security</full-title></periodical><pages>246-266</pages><volume>48</volume><keywords><keyword>APT</keyword><keyword>Cyber-attack</keyword><keyword>Detection</keyword><keyword>Email</keyword><keyword>Malicious code</keyword><keyword>Malware</keyword><keyword>Organizations</keyword><keyword>PDF</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.cose.2014.10.014</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://nissim2015.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cose.2014.10.014</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Initial penetration is one of the first steps of an Advanced Persistent Threat (APT) attack, and it is considered one of the most significant means of initiating cyber-attacks aimed at organizations. Such an attack usually results in the loss of sensitive and confidential information. Because email communication is an integral part of daily business operations, APT attackers frequently leverage email as an attack vector for initial penetration of the targeted organization. Emails allow the attacker to deliver malicious attachments or links to malicious websites. Attackers usually use social engineering in order to make the recipient open the malicious email, open the attachment, or press a link. Existing defensive solutions within organizations prevent executables from entering organizational networks via emails, therefore, recent APT attacks tend to attach non-executable files (PDF, MS Office etc.) which are widely used in organizations and mistakenly considered less suspicious or malicious. This article surveys existing academic methods for the detection of malicious PDF files. The article outlines an Active Learning framework and highlights the correlation between structural incompatibility of PDF files and their likelihood of maliciousness. Finally, we provide comparisons, insights and conclusions, as well as avenues for future research in order to enhance the detection of malicious PDFs.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Shuja, Junaid</author><author>Gani, Abdullah</author><author>Rehman, Muhammad Habib ur</author><author>Ahmed, Ejaz</author><author>Madani, Sajjad A.</author><author>Khan, Muhammad Khurram</author><author>Ko, Kwangman</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Towards native code offloading based MCC frameworks for multimedia applications: A survey</title><secondary-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Network and Computer Applications</full-title></periodical><pages>335-354</pages><volume>75</volume><keywords><keyword>ARM</keyword><keyword>Dynamic Binary Translation</keyword><keyword>Emulation</keyword><keyword>Mobile Cloud Computing</keyword><keyword>SIMD</keyword><keyword>Virtualization</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.jnca.2016.08.021</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://shuja2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jnca.2016.08.021</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>A number of resource-intensive applications, such as augmented reality, natural language processing, object recognition, and multimedia-based software are pushing the computational and energy boundaries of smartphones. Cloud-based services augment the resource-scare capabilities of smartphones while offloading compute-intensive methods to resource-rich cloud servers. The amalgam of cloud and mobile computing technologies has ushered the rise of Mobile Cloud Computing (MCC) paradigm which envisions operating smartphones and modern mobile devices beyond their intrinsic capabilities. System virtualization, application virtualization, and dynamic binary translation (DBT) techniques are required to address the heterogeneity of smartphone and cloud architectures. However, most of the current research work has only focused on the offloading of virtualized applications while giving limited consideration to native code offloading. Moreover, researchers have not attended to the requirements of multimedia based applications in MCC offloading frameworks. In this study, we present a survey and taxonomy of state-of-the-art MCC frameworks, DBT techniques for native offloading, and cross-platform execution techniques for multimedia based applications. We survey the MCC frameworks from the perspective of offload enabling techniques. We focus on native code offloading frameworks and analyze the DBT and emulation techniques of smartphones (ARM) on a cloud server (x86) architectures. Furthermore, we debate the open research issues and challenges to native offloading of multimedia based smartphone applications.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Schreuders, Z. Cliffe</author><author>McGill, Tanya</author><author>Payne, Christian</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The state of the art of application restrictions and sandboxes: A survey of application-oriented access controls and their shortfalls</title><secondary-title>Computers and Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computers and Security</full-title></periodical><pages>219-241</pages><volume>32</volume><issue>0</issue><keywords><keyword>Application-oriented access</keyword><keyword>Confinement</keyword><keyword>Controls</keyword><keyword>Literature review</keyword><keyword>Sandboxing</keyword><keyword>Virtualization</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier Ltd</publisher><isbn>0167-4048</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.cose.2012.09.007</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://schreuders2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cose.2012.09.007</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Under most widely-used security mechanisms the programs users run possess more authority than is strictly necessary, with each process typically capable of utilising all of the user's privileges. Consequently such security mechanisms often fail to protect against contemporary threats, such as previously unknown ('zero-day') malware and software vulnerabilities, as processes can misuse a user's privileges to behave maliciously. Application restrictions and sandboxes can mitigate threats that traditional approaches to access control fail to prevent by limiting the authority granted to each process. This developing field has become an active area of research, and a variety of solutions have been proposed. However, despite the seriousness of the problem and the security advantages these schemes provide, practical obstacles have restricted their adoption. This paper describes the motivation for application restrictions and sandboxes, presenting an in-depth review of the literature covering existing systems. This is the most comprehensive review of the field to date. The paper outlines the broad categories of existing application-oriented access control schemes, such as isolation and rule-based schemes, and discusses their limitations. Adoption of these schemes has arguably been impeded by workflow, policy complexity, and usability issues. The paper concludes with a discussion on areas for future work, and points a way forward within this developing field of research with recommendations for usability and abstraction to be considered to a further extent when designing application-oriented access controls. © 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sipior, Janice C.</author><author>Ward, Burke T.</author><author>Volonino, Linda</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Privacy Concerns Associated with Smartphone Use</title><secondary-title>Journal of Internet Commerce</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Internet Commerce</full-title></periodical><pages>177-193</pages><volume>13</volume><issue>3-4</issue><keywords><keyword>Federal Trade Commission</keyword><keyword>information privacy concerns</keyword><keyword>privacy</keyword><keyword>smartphones</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><isbn>1533-2861</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/15332861.2014.947902</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://sipior2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://proxy.library.upenn.edu:2165/doi/abs/10.1080/15332861.2014.947902#.VVOaLflViko</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>A wide range of personal and consumer information may be collected from smartphone users in utilizing their mobile devices for personal and business purposes. The purpose of this article is to examine smartphone users’ privacy concerns associated with the ways in which their privacy may be violated, including applications, mobile malware, location or movements, information collection by smartphone service providers, and loss or theft of a smartphone. Researchers then examine the United States Federal Trade Commission's ongoing efforts to enforce vendor representations with respect to privacy and develop recommendations for the best practices to improve mobile privacy disclosures. They conclude by offering directions for future research. The jurisdictional scope of this article is limited to the United States.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Swanlund, David</author><author>Schuurman, Nadine</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Mechanism Matters: Data Production for Geosurveillance</title><secondary-title>Annals of the American Association of Geographers</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Annals of the American Association of Geographers</full-title></periodical><pages>1-16</pages><volume>4452</volume><issue>June</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/24694452.2016.1188680</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://swanlund2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/24694452.2016.1188680</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Recent revelations of dragnet surveillance by governments around the world have brought attention to privacy and surveillance in their many forms. In this article, we outline the technical mechanisms of geosurveillance to synthesize and inform on a constantly moving target. Despite their interconnections and overlap, to simplify and elucidate these geosurveillance mechanisms, we classify them into three parts: geolocation, unique identification, and the surveillance medium. We show that together they constitute a language that we, as subjects, did not choose yet are increasingly forced to negotiate. Moreover, these mechanisms are both numerous and highly complex and are only one component within large ecosystems of geosurveillance, making privacy ever more evasive. Understanding the mechanisms of our own subjection is integral to any prospects for intervention, however. As such, we highlight the Tor network as an example of resistance to geosurveillance that is enabled by acutely understanding the hyperte...</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Summey, Terri</author><author>Gutiérrez, Art</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Laptops to Go: A Student Assessment of a Library Laptop Lending Service</title><secondary-title>Journal of Access Services</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Access Services</full-title></periodical><pages>28-43</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>January 2015</issue><keywords><keyword>academic libraries</keyword><keyword>laptop lending</keyword><keyword>library technology</keyword><keyword>student satisfac-</keyword><keyword>tion survey</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2012</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/15367967.2012.629929</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://summey2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Approximately five years ago, the library at Emporia State University started a laptop lending service to provide laptops for use in the library. The program has been highly successful. In the last few years, some modifications were made to the program, and netbooks were added. In this article, the authors will explore laptop programs in a variety of library settings, present details on the ESU Libraries laptop lending service, and discuss the results of a student satisfaction survey. Finally the authors present what the library faculty and staff have learned and potential future modifications to the program. © 2012 Copyright Taylor and Francis Group, LLC.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Thaanum, Jason D.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Threats to Cyber Security: The Dangers of Malicious Mobile Code, Users, and the iPhone</title><secondary-title>Journal of Applied Security Research</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Applied Security Research</full-title></periodical><pages>490-509</pages><volume>8</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/19361610.2013.825755</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://thaanum2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/19361610.2013.825755</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The following article covers issues with the iPhone, along with the cyber threats associated with jailbreaking. The reader will be introduced to how technology has grown from its basic ideas and innovations to today's digital explosion of cyber technology and the associated colored hats that defend and shatter said technology. An overview of cyber security, malicious mobile code, jailbreaking, and personal interviews with hackers will also be presented. {©} 2013 Copyright Taylor and Francis Group, LLC.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Vinaja, Robert</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>&lt;i&gt;Information Security Theory and Practice&lt;/i&gt; , by Akram, R., &amp;amp; Jajodia, S.</title><secondary-title>Journal of Global Information Technology Management</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Global Information Technology Management</full-title></periodical><pages>316-318</pages><volume>18</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><isbn>9783319240176</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/1097198X.2015.1108102</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://vinaja2015.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/1097198X.2015.1108102</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Tewari, Aakanksha</author><author>Jain, A. K.</author><author>Gupta, B. B.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Recent survey of various defense mechanisms against phishing attacks</title><secondary-title>Journal of Information Privacy and Security</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Information Privacy and Security</full-title></periodical><pages>3-13</pages><volume>12</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>IDENTITY theft -- Prevention</keyword><keyword>INFORMATION technology -- Security measures</keyword><keyword>INTERNET fraud</keyword><keyword>INTERNET security</keyword><keyword>PHISHING -- Prevention</keyword><keyword>TECHNOLOGICAL innovations</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><isbn>1553-6548</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/15536548.2016.1139423</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://tewari2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.1080/15536548.2016.1139423</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>In the recent years, the phishing attack has become one of the most serious threats faced by Internet users, organizations, and service providers. In a phishing attack, the attacker tries to defraud Internet users and steal their personal information either by using spoofed emails or by using fake websites or both. Several approaches have been proposed in the literature for the detection and filtering of phishing attacks; however, the Internet community is still looking for a complete solution to secure the Internet from these attacks. This article discusses recent developments and protection mechanisms (i.e., detection and filtering) against a variety of phishing attacks (e.g., email phishing, website phishing, zero-day attacks). In addition, the strengths and weaknesses of these approaches is discussed. This article provides a better understanding of the phishing attack problem in the current solution space and also addresses the scope of future research to deal with such attacks efficiently. [ABSTRACT FROM AUTHOR]</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Walkowiak, Krzysztof</author><author>Woźniak, Michał</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Guest Editorial: Intelligent Network Security and Survivability</title><secondary-title>Cybernetics and Systems</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Cybernetics and Systems</full-title></periodical><pages>467-468</pages><volume>44</volume><issue>6-7</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/01969722.2013.818448</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://walkowiak2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/01969722.2013.818448</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Walker, John</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Security Challenges and Threats for the CISO's Agenda</title><secondary-title>Edpacs</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Edpacs</full-title></periodical><pages>1-13</pages><volume>44</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2011</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/07366981.2011.588088</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://walker2011.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Visinescu, Lucian L.</author><author>Azogu, Olajumoke</author><author>Ryan, Sherry D.</author><author>Wu, Yu “Andy”</author><author>Kim, Dan J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Better Safe than Sorry: A Study of Investigating Individuals’ Protection of Privacy in the Use of Storage as a Cloud Computing Service</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Human–Computer Interaction</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Human–Computer Interaction</full-title></periodical><pages>885-900</pages><volume>32</volume><issue>11</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/10447318.2016.1204838</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://visinescu2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10447318.2016.1204838</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>AbstractSince the use of network-based storage as a cloud computing service (StaaS) becomes ubiquitous, users who store data in the cloud are exposed to risk and potentially severe consequences. Therefore, individuals should carefully consider security and privacy issues when using StaaS. Drawing upon the principle of self-preservation and the theory of protection motivation, this study develops a research model explaining the mechanisms leading to the development of a protection strategy for individuals’ safe use of StaaS and empirically tests the proposed model. The results show that the natural propensity to trust, an individual trait, influences an individual’s need for privacy. This, in turn, along with perception of privacy risk, significantly affects individuals’ perception of the need to protect themselves. Three coping appraisal factors, preventive measures, self-efficacy and willingness to incur cost of prevention, together with the individual perceived need to protect self, directly and positiv...</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ab Rahman, Nurul Hidayah</author><author>Cahyani, Niken Dwi Wahyu</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Cloud incident handling and forensic-by-design: cloud storage as a case study</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>n/a--n/a</pages><volume>29</volume><issue>14</issue><keywords><keyword>cloud computing</keyword><keyword>cloud storage forensics</keyword><keyword>digital forensics</keyword><keyword>forensic-by-design</keyword><keyword>incident handling</keyword><keyword>mobile forensics</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.3868</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.3868</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Information security incident handling strategies or models are important to ensure the security of organisations, particularly in cloud and big data environments. However, existing strategies or models may not adequate as cloud data are generally virtualised, geographically distributed and ephemeral, presenting both technical and jurisdictional challenges. We present an integrated cloud incident handling and forensic-by-design model. We then seek to validate the model using a set of controlled experiments on a cloud-related incident. Three popular cloud storage applications were deployed namely, Dropbox, Google Drive, and OneDrive. This study demonstrates the utility of the model for organisational cloud users to undertake incident investigations (e.g. collect and analyse residual data from cloud storage applications). Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_601to 700.enl" path="My Collection_601to 700.enl">My Collection_601to 700.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Yan, Zheng</author><author>Kantola, Raimo</author><author>Shen, Yue</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A generic solution for unwanted traffic control through trust management</title><secondary-title>New Review of Hypermedia and Multimedia</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>New Review of Hypermedia and Multimedia</full-title></periodical><pages>25-51</pages><volume>20</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/13614568.2013.832807</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://yan2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/13614568.2013.832807</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The Internet has dramatically changed our daily life. But it is also bogged down by unwanted traffic, which is malicious, harmful or unexpected for its receivers. In order to control the unwanted traffic over the Internet, especially the mobile Internet, in this paper, we propose a generic unwanted traffic control (UTC) solution through trust management. It can control unwanted traffic from its source to destinations in a personalized manner according to trust evaluation at a Global Trust Operator, traffic and behavior analysis at hosts and traffic observation in the Internet. Thus, it can conduct UTC by integrating distributed and centralized functions and supporting both defensive and offensive approaches. Simulation based evaluation shows that the solution is effective with regard to accuracy and efficiency for botnet intrusion and DDoS intrusion via reflectors. It is also robust against a number of malicious system attacks, such as hide evidence attack, bad mouthing attack, on-off attack, malicious attack by an Internet Service Provider and combinations of the above, playing in conjunction with traffic intrusions. Meanwhile, the solution can provide a personalized UTC based on unwanted traffic detection behaviors.</abstract></record></records></xml>
