<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><xml><records><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zhang, Yang</author><author>Mekky, Hesham</author><author>Zhang, Zhi-Li</author><author>Torres, Ruben</author><author>Lee, Sung-Ju</author><author>Tongaonkar, Alok</author><author>Mellia, Marco</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Detecting malicious activities with user-agent-based profiles</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Network Management</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Network Management</full-title></periodical><pages>306-319</pages><volume>25</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/nem.1900</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/nem.1900</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Hypertext transfer protocol (HTTP) has become the main protocol to carry out malicious activities. Attackers typically use HTTP for communication with command-and-control servers, click fraud, phishing and other malicious activities, as they can easily hide among the large amount of benign HTTP traffic. The user-agent (UA) field in the HTTP header carries information on the application, operating system (OS), device, and so on, and adversaries fake UA strings as a way to evade detection. Motivated by this, we propose a novel grammar-guided UA string classification method in HTTP flows. We leverage the fact that a number of ‘standard’ applications, such as web browsers and iOS mobile apps, have well-defined syntaxes that can be specified using context-free grammars, and we extract OS, device and other relevant information from them. We develop association heuristics to classify UA strings that are generated by ‘non-standard’ applications that do not contain OS or device information. We provide a proof-of-concept system that demonstrates how our approach can be used to identify malicious applications that generate fake UA strings to engage in fraudulent activities. Copyright © 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Pektaş, Abdurrahman</author><author>Acarman, Tankut</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A dynamic malware analyzer against virtual machine aware malicious software</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>2245-2257</pages><volume>7</volume><issue>12</issue><keywords><keyword>anti-virtual machine techniques</keyword><keyword>binary instrumentation</keyword><keyword>dynamic malware analysis</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.931</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.931</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Nowadays, cyber-world is being enriched by a large variety of digital information technology-based services. An increasing rate of remote and mobile usage leads to a remarkable dependency on information security. Analysis and detection of malicious software or so-called malware is a challenging task due to the introduction of advanced obfuscation techniques by malware authors. In this study, we mainly concentrate on anti-virtual machine evasion techniques to provide secure and reproducible environments for malware analysis and its implementation issues. Malwares are identified on the basis of their behaviors by taking precautions related to the anti-virtual machine detection techniques. The dynamic malware analyzer tool is deployed to execute anti-virtual machine-aware malware samples in VMware environment. Dynamic malware analyzer monitors system resources such as connections, processes, windows registry, and file operations. Success ratio of detection is tested by using public malware sets with an accuracy of 92%. The effectiveness and success of the behavior-based malware analyzer tool is exploited and current state of the art of malware detection schemes is presented. Copyright © 2013 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Park, Jong Hyuk</author><author>Kim, Dohyun</author><author>Park, Ji Soo</author><author>Lee, Sangjin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An enhanced security framework for reliable Android operating system</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>528-534</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>Android OS</keyword><keyword>Android file system</keyword><keyword>Android malware</keyword><keyword>data recovery</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.908</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.908</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The number of applications loaded with malware is rapidly increasing in Android operating system (OS). These malwares spread through the official Android market “Play Store”, unofficial “black market”, and private web pages. Once the malware activates, personal information can be extracted and some data can be deleted, causing tremendous damage to users. In order to provide reliability on Android OS, there is a need to analyze and address these malwares and recover the modified data. In this paper, we propose an enhanced security framework for a reliable Android OS. The framework provides means to prevent influx of malware by examining the Android OS and file system. In addition, it recovers data once deleted by security breaches. Copyright © 2013 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bai, Jinrong</author><author>Wang, Junfeng</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Improving malware detection using multi-view ensemble learning</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>4227-4241</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>17</issue><keywords><keyword>ensemble learning</keyword><keyword>fusion</keyword><keyword>malware detection</keyword><keyword>multi-view feature</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1600</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1600</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The huge influx of new malware is created every day, and those malware have not been previously seen in the wild. Current anti-virus software uses byte signature to identify known malware and has little hope of identifying new malware. Researchers have proposed several malware detection methods based on byte n-grams, opcode n-grams, and format information, and those methods partially capture the distinguishable information between benign and malicious programs. In this study, we design two schemes to incorporate the aforementioned three single-view features and fully exploit complementary information of those features to discover the true nature of a program. Two datasets are used to evaluate new malware detection performance and generalization performance of the proposed schemes. Experimental results indicate that the proposed schemes increase the detection rate of new malware, improve the generalization performance of learning model, and reduce the false alarm rate to 0%. Because malware is hard to disguise itself in every feature view, the proposed schemes are more robust and not easy to be deceived. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>del Rey, Angel Martín</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Mathematical modeling of the propagation of malware: a review</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>2561-2579</pages><volume>8</volume><issue>15</issue><keywords><keyword>cellular automata</keyword><keyword>computational simulation</keyword><keyword>differential equations</keyword><keyword>malware</keyword><keyword>mathematical modeling</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1186</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1186</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>In the present work, we offer a critical review of the mathematical models that have been proposed to date to simulate malware propagation in a network of computers or mobile devices. We analyze the models proposed determining the deficits and possible alternatives for improving them. Copyright © 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Khan, Sohail</author><author>Nauman, Mohammad</author><author>Othman, Abu Talib</author><author>Musa, Shahrulniza</author><author>Syed, Toqeer Ali</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>TSSDroid: realization of an efficient and usable TSS API for the Android software stack</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>1553-1576</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>11</issue><keywords><keyword>API design</keyword><keyword>android</keyword><keyword>mobile platforms</keyword><keyword>trusted computing</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1448</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1448</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The advancement in smartphones capabilities has attracted malware writers to build more sophisticated attacks on these devices. Traditional software-based security mechanisms have failed to provide strong security against these attacks. Similar threats on the PC have been countered using the concepts of Trusted Computing—a highly flexible trust mechanism with strong security properties. However, smartphone platforms have yet to see any Trusted Computing applications—primarily because of the difficulty in adopting this relatively new paradigm of security. In this paper, we present the design of a high-level application programming interface (API) that allows Android-based smartphone application developers to adopt Trusted Computing and use it in their applications without having to learn the intricate details of how Trusted Computing works. The API abstracts away the complexity in using Trusted Computing constructs by offering easy-to-use interfaces for complex tasks. The API has enhanced the usability of Trusted Computing development by significantly reducing the number of lines and complexity of code required to perform these diverse tasks. This paper provides a reference implementation for the proposed API in order to show that the API is efficient in terms of performance overhead. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Amamra, Abdelfattah</author><author>Robert, Jean-Marc</author><author>Abraham, Andrien</author><author>Talhi, Chamseddine</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Generative versus discriminative classifiers for android anomaly-based detection system using system calls filtering and abstraction process</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>3483-3495</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>16</issue><keywords><keyword>android security</keyword><keyword>anomaly detection</keyword><keyword>discriminative machine learning classifiers</keyword><keyword>filtering and abstraction</keyword><keyword>generative machine learning classifiers</keyword><keyword>k-means clustering</keyword><keyword>support vector machine</keyword><keyword>system calls</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1555</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1555</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Anomaly-based detection techniques have been widely studied in recent years. Most of these efforts have focused to improve the accuracy of these techniques. The poor accuracy performance is caused by two factors: (i) the data used for the analysis is insufficient and/or unrepresentative of the application behavior, or (ii) inappropriate algorithms are used to model the behavior of the application. In this paper, we attempt to improve anomaly-based detection techniques by examining these two factors. First, we use system call filtering and abstraction process. This process refines the system call traces. The refined traces are compact and should be more representative of the application main behavior. Second, we use machine learning classifiers to characterize the benign behavior. Generally, there are two main categories of machine learning classifiers: generative classifiers and discriminative classifiers. In their initial training phases, the classifiers build models characterizing the benign behavior. Later on, these models are used to distinguish between different classes of data. They are simply defined by their parameters. The k-means classifier is considered as a representative of the generative classifier category, and the support vector machine classifier as a representative of the discriminative classifier category. The efficiency of these classifiers are reviewed and compared, as well as the impact of the filtering and abstraction process on their performances is evaluated. The experimental results show that the support vector machine model outperforms the k-means model, and the filtering and abstraction process has positive impacts on the performance of both models. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Alomari, Mohammad Ahmed</author><author>Samsudin, Khairulmizam</author><author>Ramli, Abdul Rahman</author><author>Hashim, Shaiful J</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Efficient Android-based storage encryption using multi-core CPUs</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>5673-5686</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>18</issue><keywords><keyword>Google's Android</keyword><keyword>XTS mode</keyword><keyword>encryption algorithms</keyword><keyword>mobile devices</keyword><keyword>multi-core CPUs</keyword><keyword>performance</keyword><keyword>storage security</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1727</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1727</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The huge proliferation of mobile and handheld devices, such as tablets and Smartphone devices, has come with different threats to the sensitive data and personally identifiable information stored inside these devices. The most efficient way to ensure data protection is through encryption; however, it comes with great impact on these small gadgets, which suffer from limited resources. Majority of recent mobile devices are equipped with increasingly powerful multi-core processors that researchers can leverage in order to enhance data protection while maintaining proper device performance. In this paper, we introduce a parallel implementation for data encryption inside the storage of Android-based mobile devices. This work implements a multi-core design of different encryption ciphers, making use of the commodity multi-core CPUs available currently in new smart gadget devices, in order to enhance the performance inside these resource-limited devices. Ciphers XTS-AES, XTS-Twofish, and XTS-RC6 are used during the experiments; however, the main focus is given to XTS-AES because it is developed specifically for storage encryption. Parallel encryption experiments are conducted on a mobile device, and performance comparisons are presented. The parallel XTS-AES has shown a maximum performance speedup of 1.71, with 86% efficiency, faster than the serial counterpart, with higher encryption throughput in the device up to 8290 and 11 380 KB/s when using XTS-AES and XTS-RC6 ciphers, respectively. In addition, we performed comparison between mobile device and desktop machine using similar experimental setup. It shows that the performance of storage encryption in mobile devices still lags by more than 10 folds when compared with desktop environment. Copyright © 2017 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Drummond, Aaron</author><author>Cromarty, Paul</author><author>Battersby, Malcolm</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Privacy in the Digital Age: Implications for Clinical Practice</title><secondary-title>Clinical Psychology: Science and Practice</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Clinical Psychology: Science and Practice</full-title></periodical><pages>227-237</pages><volume>22</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>best practice</keyword><keyword>encryption</keyword><keyword>mental health care</keyword><keyword>privacy</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/cpsp.12105</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/cpsp.12105</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>In 2012, privacy breaches exposed the confidential health data of 22.5 million U.S. citizens. Ensuring clients’ privacy is essential in clinical psychology, and a task that has become increasingly complex as technology has evolved. Many current professional guidelines for clinical practice do not consider issues pertaining to potential privacy breaches from sources such as human error, malicious acts, metadata, and surveillance (e.g., APA, 2007, http://www.apa.org/practice/guidelines/record-keeping.pdf; APS, 2013, http://www.psychology.org.au/Assets/Files/2013-APS-psychological-services-framework-for-public-sector-NGO%20.pdf; BPS, 2011, http://www.bps.org.uk/sites/default/files/documents/electronic_health_records_final.pdf). We review potential sources of privacy breaches arising from electronic storage and communications use. We conclude with best practice recommendations regarding electronic storage and communication, software choices, and spyware removal designed to minimize privacy risk in mental health care. These recommendations need to be regularly reviewed to continue to minimize the risk of privacy-related breaches in the context of ongoing technological development.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Chang, Rui</author><author>Jiang, Liehui</author><author>Chen, Wenzhi</author><author>He, Hongqi</author><author>Yang, Shuiqiao</author><author>Jiang, Hang</author><author>Liu, Wei</author><author>Liu, Yong</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Towards a multilayered permission-based access control for extending Android security</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>n/a--n/a</pages><keywords><keyword>Android security</keyword><keyword>access control</keyword><keyword>multilayered</keyword><keyword>permission</keyword><keyword>sandbox</keyword></keywords><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.4180</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.4180</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This paper discusses security issues on the user equipment, which is the “last mile” of social networks. One of the main Achilles' heel of social networks is not the organization of networks themselves, but the user devices, typically Android ones. The existing system of privileges makes it easy to infiltrate the network via applications installed on users' devices. Conventional signature-based and static analysis methods are vulnerable. Access to privacy- and security-relevant parts of the application programming interface is controlled by the corresponding permission in a manifest file. While requesting access to permissions, it may offer opportunities to malicious codes, which will cause security issues. Few works among permission analysis, however, pay attention to the prevention of permission leakage on both hardware and software frameworks. In this paper we tackle the challenge of providing our multilayered permission-based security extension scheme on Android platforms. We propose a usage and access control model and an effective method of preventing permission leakage based on ARM TrustZone security extension mechanism. In contrast to previous work, the proposed security architecture provides a permission-based mandatory access control on Android middleware, Linux kernel, and hardware layers. The evaluation results demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed scheme in mitigating permission leakage vulnerabilities.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Boero, Luca</author><author>Cello, Marco</author><author>Marchese, Mario</author><author>Mariconti, Enrico</author><author>Naqash, Talha</author><author>Zappatore, Sandro</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Statistical fingerprint-based intrusion detection system (SF-IDS)</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Communication Systems</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Communication Systems</full-title></periodical><pages>n/a--n/a</pages><volume>30</volume><issue>10</issue><keywords><keyword>IP</keyword><keyword>intrusion detection system</keyword><keyword>machine learning</keyword><keyword>networking</keyword><keyword>statistical analysis</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/dac.3225</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/dac.3225</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Intrusion detection systems (IDS) are systems aimed at analyzing and detecting security problems. The IDS may be structured into misuse and anomaly detection. The former are often signature/rule IDS that detect malicious software by inspecting the content of packets or files looking for a “signature” labeling malware. They are often very efficient, but their drawback stands in the weakness of the information to check (eg, the signature), which may be quickly dated, and in the computation time because each packet or file needs to be inspected. The IDS based on anomaly detection and, in particular, on statistical analysis have been originated to bypass the mentioned problems. Instead of inspecting packets, each traffic flow is observed so getting a statistical characterization, which represents the fingerprint of the flow. This paper introduces a statistical analysis based intrusion detection system, which, after extracting the statistical fingerprint, uses machine learning classifiers to decide whether a flow is affected by malware or not. A large set of tests is presented. The obtained results allow selecting the best classifiers and show the performance of a decision maker that exploits the decisions of a bank of classifiers acting in parallel.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Fan, Lejun</author><author>Wang, Yuanzhuo</author><author>Cheng, Xueqi</author><author>Li, Jinming</author><author>Jin, Shuyuan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Privacy theft malware multi-process collaboration analysis</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>51-67</pages><volume>8</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Privacy Petri Net</keyword><keyword>malware detection</keyword><keyword>multi-process</keyword><keyword>privacy theft</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.705</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.705</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Privacy theft malware has become a serious and challenging problem to cyber security. Previous methods are of different categories: one focuses on the outbound network traffic and the other one dives into the inside information flow of the program. We incorporate dynamic behavior analysis with network traffic analysis and present an abstract model called Privacy Petri Net (PPN), which is more applicable to various kinds of malware and more understandable to users. In consideration of the multi-process technique adopted by new malware, we also model the collaborative behaviors between different malicious functionality modules with PPN. We apply our approach to real-world malware, and the experiment result shows that our approach can effectively find categories, content, source, and destination of the privacy theft behavior of the malware sample. Copyright © 2013 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wu, Jianliang</author><author>Cui, Tingting</author><author>Ban, Tao</author><author>Guo, Shanqing</author><author>Cui, Lizhen</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>PaddyFrog: systematically detecting confused deputy vulnerability in Android applications</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>2338-2349</pages><volume>8</volume><issue>13</issue><keywords><keyword>confused deputy attack</keyword><keyword>control flow graph</keyword><keyword>privilege escalation attack</keyword><keyword>static analysis</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1179</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1179</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>An enormous number of applications have been developed for Android in recent years, making it one of the most popular mobile operating systems. However, it is obvious that more vulnerabilities would appear along with the booming amounts of applications. Poorly designed applications may contain security vulnerabilities that can dramatically undermine users' security and privacy. In this paper, we studied a kind of recently reported application vulnerability named confused deputy – a specific type of privilege escalation vulnerability, which can result in unauthorized operations, and so on. We proposed a novel system with code-level static analysis to analyze the applications and automatically detect possible confused deputy vulnerabilities. To tackle analysis challenges imposed by Android's component-based programming paradigm, we employed special control flow graph construction techniques to build call relations among components and function call graph within components. We developed a prototype of this system named PaddyFrog and evaluated with 7190 real world Android applications from two of the most popular markets in China. We found 1240 applications with confused deputy vulnerability and proved to be exploitable. The median execution time of this system on an application is 14.4s, which is fast enough to be used in volumes of applications testing scenarios. Copyright © 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Min, Byungho</author><author>Varadharajan, Vijay</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A novel malware for subversion of self-protection in anti-virus</title><secondary-title>Software: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Software: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>361-379</pages><volume>46</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>anti-virus</keyword><keyword>malware</keyword><keyword>security</keyword><keyword>self-protection</keyword><keyword>vulnerability</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/spe.2317</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/spe.2317</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Major anti-virus solutions have introduced a feature known as ‘self-protection’ so that malware (and even users) cannot modify or disable the core functionality of their products. In this paper, we have investigated 12 anti-virus products from four vendors (AVG, Avira, McAfee and Symantec) and have discovered that they have certain security weaknesses that can be exploited by malware. We have then designed a novel malware, which makes use of the weaknesses in anti-virus software and embeds itself to become a part of the vulnerable anti-virus solution. It subverts the self-protection features of several anti-virus software solutions. This malware integrated anti-virus enjoys several advantages such as longevity (anti-virus is active while the system is running), improved stealthy behaviour, highest privilege and capability to bypass security measures. Then we propose an effective defence against such malware. We have also implemented the defensive measure and evaluated its effectiveness. Finally, we show how the proposed defence can be applied to the current versions of vulnerable anti-virus solutions without requiring signficant modifications. Copyright © 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jang, Bogyu</author><author>Lee, Jaeseung</author><author>Lee, Manhee</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Automatic system for measuring security risk of Android application from third party app store</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>3190-3196</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>16</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>DroidBox</keyword><keyword>VirusTotal</keyword><keyword>dynamic analysis</keyword><keyword>malware</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1525</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1525</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Third party app stores are being used by people to pick up cracked or free Android apps. Hackers make use of these stores to distribute malicious apps. So, the level of security risk of downloading and using apps from such stores will be helpful for people who want to use the store. We implement an automatic system that downloads and analyzes every app. Our preliminary result shows that around half of apps from two app stores interesting to us are already known malware. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Narouei, Masoud</author><author>Ahmadi, Mansour</author><author>Giacinto, Giorgio</author><author>Takabi, Hassan</author><author>Sami, Ashkan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>DLLMiner: structural mining for malware detection</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>3311-3322</pages><volume>8</volume><issue>18</issue><keywords><keyword>closed frequent tree</keyword><keyword>dependency tree</keyword><keyword>evasion</keyword><keyword>malware analysis</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1255</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1255</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Existing anti-malware products usually use signature-based techniques as their main detection engine. Although these methods are very fast, they are unable to provide effective protection against newly discovered malware or mutated variant of old malware. Heuristic approaches are the next generation of detection techniques to mitigate the problem. These approaches aim to improve the detection rate by extracting more behavioral characteristics of malware. Although these approaches cover the disadvantages of signature-based techniques, they usually have a high false positive, and evasion is still possible from these approaches. In this paper, we propose an effective and efficient heuristic technique based on static analysis that not only detect malware with a very high accuracy, but also is robust against common evasion techniques such as junk injection and packing. Our proposed system is able to extract behavioral features from a unique structure in portable executable, which is called dynamic-link library dependency tree, without actually executing the application. Copyright © 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Liu, Yang</author><author>Simpson, Andrew</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Privacy-preserving targeted mobile advertising: requirements, design and a prototype implementation</title><secondary-title>Software: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Software: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>1657-1684</pages><volume>46</volume><issue>12</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>mobile devices</keyword><keyword>privacy</keyword><keyword>targeted advertising</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/spe.2403</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/spe.2403</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>With the continued proliferation of mobile devices, the collection of information associated with such devices and their users—such as location, installed applications and cookies associated with built-in browsers—has become increasingly straightforward. By analysing such information, organisations are often able to deliver more relevant and better focused advertisements. Of course, such targeted mobile advertising gives rise to a number of concerns, with privacy-related concerns being prominent. In this paper, we discuss the necessary balance that needs to be struck between privacy and utility in this emerging area and propose privacy-preserving targeted mobile advertising as a solution that tries to achieve that balance. Our aim is to develop a solution that can be deployed by users but is also palatable to businesses that operate in this space. This paper focuses on the requirements and design of privacy-preserving targeted mobile advertising and also describes an initial prototype. We also discuss how more detailed technical aspects and a complete evaluation will underpin our future work in this area. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mooney, J Lowell</author><author>Parham, Abbie Gail</author><author>Cairney, Timothy D</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Your Guide to Authenticating Mobile Devices</title><secondary-title>Journal of Corporate Accounting &amp; Finance</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Corporate Accounting &amp; Finance</full-title></periodical><pages>51-68</pages><volume>24</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><publisher>Wiley Subscription Services, Inc., A Wiley Company</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/jcaf.21875</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/jcaf.21875</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>New information technology (IT) mobile devices—such as the iPhone and iPad—are increasingly emerging in the consumer market first. Then, they spread to the workplace. But this is creating major privacy and security headaches for corporate executives. Surveys show that IT groups significantly underestimate—by as much as 50%—how many employees use their own mobile devices for work purposes. So what is to be done? The authors take an in-depth look at one vitally important security measure: user authentication. Companies need to go beyond just using passwords if they want to stay safe and secure. This article shows you how. It includes step-by-step instructions and a series of valuable checklists. © 2013 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kambourakis, Georgios</author><author>Damopoulos, Dimitrios</author><author>Papamartzivanos, Dimitrios</author><author>Pavlidakis, Emmanouil</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Introducing touchstroke: keystroke-based authentication system for smartphones</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>542-554</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>authentication</keyword><keyword>keystroke dynamics</keyword><keyword>smartphones</keyword><keyword>touchscreen</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1061</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1061</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Keystroke dynamics is a well-investigated behavioural biometric based on the way and rhythm in which someone interacts with a keyboard or keypad when typing characters. This paper explores the potential of this modality but for touchscreen-equipped smartphones. The main research question posed is whether ‘touchstroking’ can be effective in building the biometric profile of a user, in terms of typing pattern, for future authentication. To reach this goal, we implemented a touchstroke system in the Android platform and executed different scenarios under disparate methodologies to estimate its effectiveness in authenticating the end-user. Apart from typical classification features used in legacy keystroke systems, we introduce two novel ones, namely, speed and distance. From the experiments, it can be argued that touchstroke dynamics can be quite competitive, at least when compared to similar results obtained from keystroke evaluation studies. As far as we are aware of, this is the first time this newly arisen behavioural trait is put into focus. Copyright © 2014 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Iqbal, Md Shahrear</author><author>Zulkernine, Mohammad</author><author>Jaafar, Fehmi</author><author>Gu, Yuan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Protecting Internet users from becoming victimized attackers of click-fraud</title><secondary-title>Journal of Software: Evolution and Process</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Software: Evolution and Process</full-title></periodical><pages>n/a--n/a</pages><keywords><keyword>click-fraud</keyword><keyword>malware detection</keyword><keyword>online advertising</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/smr.1871</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smr.1871</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Internet users are often victimized by malicious attackers. Some attackers infect and use innocent users' machines to launch large-scale attacks without the users' knowledge. One of such attacks is the click-fraud attack. Click-fraud happens in pay-per-click ad networks where the ad network charges advertisers for every click on their ads. Click-fraud has been proved to be a serious problem for the online advertisement industry. In a click-fraud attack, a user or an automated software clicks on an ad with a malicious intent and advertisers need to pay for those valueless clicks. Among many forms of click-fraud, botnets with the automated clickers are the most severe ones. In this study, we present a method for detecting automated clickers from the user side. The proposed method to fight click-fraud, FCFraud, can be integrated into the desktop and smart device operating systems. Since most modern operating systems already provide some kind of antimalware service, our proposed method can be implemented as a part of the service. We believe that an effective protection at the operating system level can save billions of dollars of the advertisers. Experiments show that FCFraud is 99.6% (98.2% in mobile ad library–generated traffic) accurate in classifying ad requests from all user processes and it is 100% successful in detecting clickbots in both desktop and mobile devices. We implement a cloud backend for the FCFraud service to save battery power in mobile devices. The overhead of executing FCFraud is also analyzed and we show that it is reasonable for both the platforms.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Qiang, Weizhong</author><author>Xin, Shifan</author><author>Jin, Hai</author><author>Sun, Guozhong</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>DroidAuditor: A framework for auditing covert communication on Android</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>n/a--n/a</pages><volume>29</volume><issue>19</issue><keywords><keyword>android</keyword><keyword>auditing</keyword><keyword>covert channel</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.4205</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.4205</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Exploitation of covert channels in smartphone operating systems may lead to furtive data transmission between applications with different permissions, which might threaten users' privacy. Restricting the access to shared system resources can effectively prevent the exploitation of known covert channels. However, it inevitably limits the normal usage of those resources. In this paper, we propose a general method that detects covert channel attack at runtime without impacting the accessibility of shared resources in the system. The main idea of the method is to track and audit the use of system resources known as potential covert channel variables and impose interferences on those channels to reduce their capacity once violations are detected. We implement a prototype framework, which is able to audit and interfere covert communication both in the application layer and in the native layer of Android. The experimental results demonstrate that our method can effectively reduce the data rate of user-defined covert channels while the overhead is negligible.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Camacho, José</author><author>Magán-Carrión, Roberto</author><author>García-Teodoro, Pedro</author><author>Treinen, James J</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Networkmetrics: multivariate big data analysis in the context of the internet</title><secondary-title>Journal of Chemometrics</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Chemometrics</full-title></periodical><pages>488-505</pages><volume>30</volume><issue>9</issue><keywords><keyword>Big Data</keyword><keyword>multivariate analysis</keyword><keyword>networking</keyword><keyword>networkmetrics</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cem.2806</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cem.2806</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Multivariate problems are found in all areas of knowledge. In chemistry and related disciplines, the chemometric community was developed in a joint effort to understand and solve problems mainly from a multivariate and exploratory perspective. This perspective is, indeed, of broader applicability, even in areas of knowledge far from chemistry. In this paper, we focus on the Internet: the net of devices that allow an interconnected world where all types of data can be shared and unprecedented communication services can be provided. Problems in the Internet or in general in networking are not very different from chemometric problems. Building on this parallelism, we review four classes of problems in networking: estimation, anomaly detection, optimization, and classification. We present an illustrative set of problems and show how a multivariate perspective may lead to significant improvements from state-of-the-art techniques. In the absence of a better name, we call the approach of treating these problems from that multivariate perspective networkmetrics. Networkmetric problems have their own specificities, mainly, their typical Big Data nature and the presence of unstructured data. We argue that multivariate analysis is, indeed, useful to tackle these specificities. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zhang, Yanping</author><author>Xiao, Yang</author><author>Ghaboosi, Kaveh</author><author>Zhang, Jingyuan</author><author>Deng, Hongmei</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A survey of cyber crimes</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>422-437</pages><volume>5</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>IDS</keyword><keyword>MAC security</keyword><keyword>forensics</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2012</year></dates><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.331</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.331</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>With the advancement of computer and information technology, cyber crime is now becoming one of the most significant challenges facing law enforcement organizations. Cyber crimes are generally referred as criminal activities that use computers or networks. An understanding of the characteristics and nature of cyber crimes is important in helping research communities find ways to effectively prevent them. Most existing research focuses more on attacks and attack models, including either actual attacks or imaginary/possible attacks over all layers of networks or computers, but there has been less work carried out on a comprehensive survey of cyber crimes. This paper provides a survey of cyber crimes that have actually occurred. First, cyber crimes in the digital world are compared with crimes in the physical world. Then, cyber crimes are categorized according to the roles of computers or networks. Furthermore, we also notice that some cyber crimes are actually traditionally non-cyber crimes that are facilitated by computers or networks. It is surprising that there are so many recurrent cyber crimes. More efforts are needed to protect people from cyber crimes. Copyright © 2011 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Traynor, Patrick</author><author>Amrutkar, Chaitrali</author><author>Rao, Vikhyath</author><author>Jaeger, Trent</author><author>McDaniel, Patrick</author><author>La Porta, Thomas</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>From mobile phones to responsible devices</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>719-726</pages><volume>4</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>cellular security</keyword><keyword>mobile phones</keyword><keyword>vulnerability analysis</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2011</year></dates><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.218</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.218</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile phones have evolved from simple voice terminals into highly-capable, general-purpose computing platforms. While people are becoming increasingly more dependent on such devices to perform sensitive operations, protect secret data, and be available for emergency use, it is clear that phone operating systems are not ready to become mission-critical systems. Through a pair of vulnerabilities and a simulated attack on a cellular network, we demonstrate that there are a myriad of unmanaged mechanisms on mobile phones, and that control of these mechanisms is vital to achieving reliable use. Through such vectors, mobile phones introduce a variety of new threats to their own applications and the telecommunications infrastructure itself. In this paper, we examine the requirements for providing effective mediation and access control for mobile phones. We then discuss the convergence of cellular networks with the Internet and its impact on effective resource management and quality of service. Based on these results, we argue for user devices that enable predictable behavior in a network—where their trusted computing bases can protect key applications and create predictable network impact. Copyright © 2010 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jang, Yu-Teng</author><author>Chang, Shuchih Ernest</author><author>Tsai, Yi-Jey</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Smartphone security: understanding smartphone users' trust in information security management</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>1313-1321</pages><volume>7</volume><issue>9</issue><keywords><keyword>computer literacy</keyword><keyword>electronic commerce (e-commerce)</keyword><keyword>information security management (ISM)</keyword><keyword>network literacy</keyword><keyword>smartphone security</keyword><keyword>trust</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.787</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.787</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Owing to the rapid advancement of technologies, today's mobile phones (e.g., smartphones) can not only fulfill users' basic requirements for communication purposes but also serve as powerful pervasive devices with various valuable functions for users. With wide and close Internet accessibility, smartphones nowadays inevitably suffer security threats and information security management (ISM) issues like common computers do. In this research, information security related trust issues are investigated through a user-based empirical study. Our research project aims to study the relationships between smartphone users' computer literacy, network literacy, knowledge on mobile phone viruses, and trust in ISM principles (i.e., confidentiality, integrity, and availability). The study results indicate that smartphone users' network literacy positively influence their knowledge on mobile phone viruses, whereas users' computer literacy is not significantly associated with their knowledge on mobile phone viruses. Moreover, smartphone users' knowledge on mobile phone viruses would significantly affect their trusts in three ISM principles. The validated research model and corresponding findings can be referenced by business executives and ISM decision makers in electronic commerce (e-commerce) for making favorable tactics to catch the revolutionary benefits offered by effective ISM policies in the ubiquitous computing environment. Copyright © 2013 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Muthukumaran, Divya</author><author>Schiffman, Joshua</author><author>Hassan, Mohamed</author><author>Sawani, Anuj</author><author>Rao, Vikhyath</author><author>Jaeger, Trent</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Protecting the integrity of trusted applications in mobile phone systems</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>633-650</pages><volume>4</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>Clark-Wilson integrity</keyword><keyword>SELinux</keyword><keyword>integrity measurement</keyword><keyword>mandatory access control</keyword><keyword>mobile phones</keyword><keyword>reference monitor</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2011</year></dates><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.194</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.194</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile phones have evolved into indispensable devices that run many exciting applications that users can download from phone vendor's application stores. However, as it is not practical to fully vet all application code, users may download malware-infected applications, which may steal or modify security-critical data. In this paper, we propose a security architecture for phone systems that protects trusted applications from such downloaded code. Our architecture uses reference monitors in the operating system and user-space services to enforce mandatory access control policies that express an approximation of Clark—Wilson integrity. In addition, we show how to justify the integrity of mobile phone applications by using the Policy Reduced Integrity Measurement Architecture (PRIMA), which enables a remote party to verify the integrity of applications running on a phone. We have implemented a prototype on the Openmoko Linux Platform, using an SELinux kernel with a PRIMA module and user-space services that leverage the SELinux user-level policy server. We find that the performance of enforcement and integrity measurement is satisfactory, and the SELinux reference policy can be reduced in size by 90% (although more reduction should be possible), enabling practical system integrity with a desirable usability model. Copyright © 2010 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Loorak, M Hosseinkhani</author><author>Fong, P W L</author><author>Carpendale, S</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Papilio: Visualizing Android Application Permissions</title><secondary-title>Computer Graphics Forum</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computer Graphics Forum</full-title></periodical><pages>391-400</pages><volume>33</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Categories and Subject Descriptors (according to A</keyword><keyword>H.5.2 [Information Systems]: Information Interfac</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/cgf.12395</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/cgf.12395</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>We introduce Papilio, a new visualization technique for visualizing permissions of real-world Android applications. We explore the development of layouts that exploit the directed acyclic nature of Android application permission data to develop a new explicit layout technique that incorporates aspects of set membership, node-link diagrams and matrix layouts. By grouping applications based on sets of requested permissions, a structure can be formed with partially ordered relations. The Papilio layout shows sets of applications centrally, the relations among applications on one side and application permissions, as the reason behind the existence of the partial order, on the other side. Using Papilio to explore a set of Android applications as a case study has led to new security findings regarding permission usage by Android applications.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mueller, Milton</author><author>Schmidt, Andreas</author><author>Kuerbis, Brenden</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Internet Security and Networked Governance in International Relations</title><secondary-title>International Studies Review</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Studies Review</full-title></periodical><pages>86-104</pages><volume>15</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/misr.12024</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/misr.12024</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This paper asks whether the Internet's heavy reliance on nonhierarchical, networked forms of governance is compatible with growing concerns about cyber-security from traditional state actors. Networked governance is defined as a semipermanent, voluntary negotiation system that allows interdependent actors to opt for collaboration or unilateral action in the absence of an overarching authority. Two case studies—Internet routing security and the response to a large-scale botnet known as Conficker—show the prevalence of networked governance on the Internet and provide insight into its strengths and limitations. The paper concludes that both cases raise doubts about the claim that introducing security concerns into Internet governance necessarily leads to more hierarchy and/or a greater role for governments.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Azfar, Abdullah</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author><author>Liu, Lin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Forensic Taxonomy of Android Social Apps</title><secondary-title>Journal of Forensic Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Forensic Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>435-456</pages><volume>62</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>digital forensics</keyword><keyword>forensic science</keyword><keyword>forensic taxonomy</keyword><keyword>mobile app forensics</keyword><keyword>mobile forensics</keyword><keyword>social app taxonomy</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/1556-4029.13267</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.13267</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>An Android social app taxonomy incorporating artifacts that are of forensic interest will enable users and forensic investigators to identify the personally identifiable information (PII) stored by the apps. In this study, 30 popular Android social apps were examined. Artifacts of forensic interest (e.g., contacts lists, chronology of messages, and timestamp of an added contact) were recovered. In addition, images were located, and Facebook token strings used to tie account identities and gain access to information entered into Facebook by a user were identified. Based on the findings, a two-dimensional taxonomy of the forensic artifacts of the social apps is proposed. A comparative summary of existing forensic taxonomies of different categories of Android apps, designed to facilitate timely collection and analysis of evidentiary materials from Android devices, is presented.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Damopoulos, Dimitrios</author><author>Menesidou, Sofia A</author><author>Kambourakis, Georgios</author><author>Papadaki, Maria</author><author>Clarke, Nathan</author><author>Gritzalis, Stefanos</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Evaluation of anomaly-based IDS for mobile devices using machine learning classifiers</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>3-14</pages><volume>5</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>anomaly-based intrusion detection system</keyword><keyword>machine learning classifiers</keyword><keyword>mobile devices</keyword><keyword>user behaviour</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2012</year></dates><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.341</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.341</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile devices have evolved and experienced an immense popularity over the last few years. This growth however has exposed mobile devices to an increasing number of security threats. Despite the variety of peripheral protection mechanisms described in the literature, authentication and access control cannot provide integral protection against intrusions. Thus, a need for more intelligent and sophisticated security controls such as intrusion detection systems (IDSs) is necessary. Whilst much work has been devoted to mobile device IDSs, research on anomaly-based or behaviour-based IDS for such devices has been limited leaving several problems unsolved. Motivated by this fact, in this paper, we focus on anomaly-based IDS for modern mobile devices. A dataset consisting of iPhone users data logs has been created, and various classification and validation methods have been evaluated to assess their effectiveness in detecting misuses. Specifically, the experimental procedure includes and cross-evaluates four machine learning algorithms (i.e. Bayesian networks, radial basis function, K-nearest neighbours and random Forest), which classify the behaviour of the end-user in terms of telephone calls, SMS and Web browsing history. In order to detect illegitimate use of service by a potential malware or a thief, the experimental procedure examines the aforementioned services independently as well as in combination in a multimodal fashion. The results are very promising showing the ability of at least one classifier to detect intrusions with a high true positive rate of 99.8%. Copyright © 2011 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mayrhofer, René</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An architecture for secure mobile devices</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>1958-1970</pages><volume>8</volume><issue>10</issue><keywords><keyword>embedded smart card</keyword><keyword>mobile device security</keyword><keyword>secure channel</keyword><keyword>user authentication</keyword><keyword>virtualization</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1028</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1028</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile devices such as smart phones have become one of the preferred means of accessing digital services, both for consuming and creating content. Unfortunately, securing such mobile devices is inherently difficult for a number of reasons. In this article, we review recent research results, systematically analyze the technical issues of securing mobile device platforms against different threats, and discuss a resulting and currently unsolved problem: How to create an end-to-end secure channel between the digital service (e.g., a secure wallet application on an embedded smart card or an infrastructure service connected over wireless media) and the user. Although the problem has been known for years and technical approaches start appearing in products, the user interaction aspects have remained unsolved. We discuss the reasons for this difficulty and suggest potential approaches to create human-verifiable secure communication with components or services within partially untrusted devices. Copyright © 2014 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Leom, Ming Di</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author><author>Hunt, Ray</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Remote Wiping and Secure Deletion on Mobile Devices: A Review</title><secondary-title>Journal of Forensic Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Forensic Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>1473-1492</pages><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>NAND nonvolatile flash memory</keyword><keyword>Solid-state drive/disk</keyword><keyword>flash storage</keyword><keyword>forensic science</keyword><keyword>remote wiping</keyword><keyword>secure deletion</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/1556-4029.13203</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.13203</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile devices have become ubiquitous in almost every sector of both private and commercial endeavors. As a result of such widespread use in everyday life, many users knowingly and unknowingly save significant amounts of personal and/or commercial data on these mobile devices. Thus, loss of mobile devices through accident or theft can expose users—and their businesses—to significant personal and corporate cost. To mitigate this data leakage issue, remote wiping features have been introduced to modern mobile devices. Given the destructive nature of such a feature, however, it may be subject to criminal exploitation (e.g., a criminal exploiting one or more vulnerabilities to issue a remote wiping command to the victim's device). To obtain a better understanding of remote wiping, we survey the literature, focusing on existing approaches to secure flash storage deletion and provide a critical analysis and comparison of a variety of published research in this area. In support of our analysis, we further provide prototype experimental results for three Android devices, thus providing both a theoretical and applied focus to this article as well as providing directions for further research.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sun, Hao</author><author>Wang, Xiaofeng</author><author>Buyya, Rajkumar</author><author>Su, Jinshu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>CloudEyes: Cloud-based malware detection with reversible sketch for resource-constrained internet of things (IoT) devices</title><secondary-title>Software: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Software: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>421-441</pages><volume>47</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>cloud-based</keyword><keyword>malware detection</keyword><keyword>reversible sketch</keyword><keyword>signature-based</keyword><keyword>suspicious bucket cross-filtering</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/spe.2420</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/spe.2420</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Because of the rapid increasing of malware attacks on the Internet of Things in recent years, it is critical for resource-constrained devices to guard against potential risks. The traditional host-based security solution becomes puffy and inapplicable with the development of malware attacks. Moreover, it is hard for the cloud-based security solution to achieve both the high performance detection and the data privacy protection simultaneously. This paper proposes a cloud-based anti-malware system, called CloudEyes, which provides efficient and trusted security services for resource-constrained devices. For the cloud server, CloudEyes presents suspicious bucket cross-filtering, a novel signature detection mechanism based on the reversible sketch structure, which provides retrospective and accurate orientations of malicious signature fragments. For the client, CloudEyes implements a lightweight scanning agent which utilizes the digest of signature fragments to dramatically reduce the range of accurate matching. Furthermore, by transmitting sketch coordinates and the modular hashing, CloudEyes guarantees both the data privacy and low-cost communications. Finally, we evaluate the performance of CloudEyes by utilizing both the campus suspicious traffic and normal files. The results demonstrate that the mechanisms in CloudEyes are effective and practical, and our system can outperform other existing systems with less time and communication consumption. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ruiz-Martínez, A</author><author>Inmaculada Marín-López, C</author><author>Sánchez-Martínez, D</author><author>Castell Egea, I</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>SIPmsign: a lightweight mobile signature service based on the Session Initiation Protocol</title><secondary-title>Software: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Software: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>511-535</pages><volume>44</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>SIP</keyword><keyword>e-commerce</keyword><keyword>instant messaging</keyword><keyword>mobile signature</keyword><keyword>mobile signature service</keyword><keyword>nonrepudiation</keyword><keyword>presence awareness</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/spe.2170</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/spe.2170</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The development of mobile signatures could increase the spread and adoption of mobile services based on electronic signatures, such as mobile payments, mobile business transactions, and mobile government services. A Mobile Signature Service (MSS) means that a user in any of the scenarios mentioned can attach an electronic signature, anywhere, anytime, as with a handwritten signature with a device that is almost always on him or her. Several solutions have appeared, such as using the European Telecommunications Standard Institute MSS, the Mobile Signature Application Unit, and the Mobile Network Operator-independent MSS. These solutions present two kinds of drawbacks. On the one hand, some of them require the service to be developed by all mobile network operators, whereas others are not based on efficient communications. In this paper, we present a new MSS named SIPmsign that solves these problems. Our proposal is based on the Session Initiation Protocol and defines how to exchange the information in a secure and more efficient way than previously. Thanks to Session Initiation Protocol, we provide the adoption of our proposal as a MSS for the new generation of mobile communications. In this paper, we also present the prototype we have developed as a proof of its feasibility as well as an evaluation of the performance of our solution. Copyright © 2012 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Abdella, J</author><author>Özuysal, M</author><author>Tomur, E</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>CA-ARBAC: privacy preserving using context-aware role-based access control on Android permission system</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>5977-5995</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>18</issue><keywords><keyword>context</keyword><keyword>permissions</keyword><keyword>privacy</keyword><keyword>roles</keyword><keyword>usability</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1750</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1750</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Existing mobile platforms are based on manual way of granting and revoking permissions to applications. Once the user grants a given permission to an application, the application can use it without limit, unless the user manually revokes the permission. This has become the reason for many privacy problems because of the fact that a permission that is harmless at some occasion may be very dangerous at another condition. One of the promising solutions for this problem is context-aware access control at permission level that allows dynamic granting and denying of permissions based on some predefined context. However, dealing with policy configuration at permission level becomes very complex for the user as the number of policies to configure will become very large. For instance, if there are A applications, P permissions, and C contexts, the user may have to deal with A × P × C number of policy configurations. Therefore, we propose a context-aware role-based access control model that can provide dynamic permission granting and revoking while keeping the number of policies as small as possible. Although our model can be used for all mobile platforms, we use Android platform to demonstrate our system. In our model, Android applications are assigned roles where roles contain a set of permissions and contexts are associated with permissions. Permissions are activated and deactivated for the containing role based on the associated contexts. Our approach is unique in that our system associates contexts with permissions as opposed to existing similar works that associate contexts with roles. As a proof of concept, we have developed a prototype application called context-aware Android role-based access control. We have also performed various tests using our application, and the result shows that our model is working as desired. Copyright © 2017 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Watanabe, Toru</author><author>Koizumi, Hisao</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A CTI System to Support the Seamless Workplace and Its Implementation</title><secondary-title>Electrical Engineering in Japan</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Electrical Engineering in Japan</full-title></periodical><pages>44-58</pages><volume>188</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>CTI service</keyword><keyword>CTI system</keyword><keyword>SIP</keyword><keyword>SIP server</keyword><keyword>Web server</keyword><keyword>smartphone</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/eej.22530</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/eej.22530</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This paper proposes a CTI client/server coordination system exclusively for use with a smart phone. The system makes use of a CTI client, performing combined functions of a SIP phone and a Web browser. The proposed CTI client/server coordination system comprises SIP servers and Web servers, both of which are installed in enterprises, and CTI clients that run on smart phones in a mobile environment. Furthermore, the CTI clients perform the function of SIP phone by communicating with SIP servers. In addition, CTI clients can display telephone directories and logging of phone calls stored in Web servers. They can display screens of ordinary Web browsers. Here, one might switch between a SIP phone function and a Web communication screen with merely a single touch of the tab key. Consequently, smart phones in the mobile environment make it possible to conduct telephone meetings while browsing with a Web screen.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Keith, Mark J</author><author>Babb, Jeffry S</author><author>Lowry, Paul Benjamin</author><author>Furner, Christopher P</author><author>Abdullat, Amjad</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The role of mobile-computing self-efficacy in consumer information disclosure</title><secondary-title>Information Systems Journal</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Information Systems Journal</full-title></periodical><pages>637-667</pages><volume>25</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>location-based services</keyword><keyword>mobile apps</keyword><keyword>mobile-computing self-efficacy</keyword><keyword>perceived risk</keyword><keyword>privacy calculus</keyword><keyword>trust</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/isj.12082</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/isj.12082</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Smartphones are increasingly penetrating business and consumer markets, and mobile applications (apps) have engendered a large and innovative market. Whereas apps are useful, they also present new forms of privacy risk associated with users' personal and location data. However, these dangers do not appear to increase the perceived risk or reduce the trust consumers demonstrate when using apps. Many information technology (IT) trust indicators are well documented such as the quality of the IT, trust assurances, brand recognition and social influences. However, these traditional indicators appear to have a lesser impact on the adoption of mobile commerce via apps because of the nature of mobile-app adoption and subsequent information disclosure. As a result, we draw from social cognitive theory and its construct of self-efficacy in particular to explain perceived mobile-app risk and provider trust. Through two controlled experiments, we demonstrate the strong direct effect of mobile-computing self-efficacy on users' initial trust in location-based app vendors as well as their perceived risk of disclosing information – regardless of the actual trustworthiness of the app vendor. The results imply that being skilled in the latest smartphones and apps can cause users to place greater trust in app providers and perceive less risk in the app itself, even when the intentions of the app providers cannot be verified.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Eterovic-Soric, Brett</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author><author>Mubarak, Sameera</author><author>Ashman, Helen</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Windows 7 Antiforensics: A Review and a Novel Approach</title><secondary-title>Journal of Forensic Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Forensic Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>1054-1070</pages><volume>62</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>DarkComet RAT</keyword><keyword>Trojan Horse Defence</keyword><keyword>Windows 7 antiforensics</keyword><keyword>digital forensics</keyword><keyword>forensic science</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/1556-4029.13393</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.13393</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>In this paper, we review literature on antiforensics published between 2010 and 2016 and reveal the surprising lack of up-to-date research on this topic. This research aims to contribute to this knowledge gap by investigating different antiforensic techniques for devices running Windows 7, one of the most popular operating systems. An approach which allows for removal or obfuscation of most forensic evidence is then presented. Using the Trojan software DarkComet RAT as a case study, we demonstrate the utility of our approach and that a Trojan Horse infection may be a legitimate possibility, even if there is no evidence of an infection on a seized computer's hard drive. Up-to-date information regarding how forensic artifacts can be compromised will allow relevant stakeholders to make informed decisions when deciding the outcome of legal cases involving digital evidence.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Carter, Henry</author><author>Amrutkar, Chaitrali</author><author>Dacosta, Italo</author><author>Traynor, Patrick</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>For your phone only: custom protocols for efficient secure function evaluation on mobile devices</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>1165-1176</pages><volume>7</volume><issue>7</issue><keywords><keyword>garbled circuits</keyword><keyword>mobile applications</keyword><keyword>partially homomorphic encryption</keyword><keyword>privacy</keyword><keyword>secure function evaluation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.851</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.851</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile applications increasingly require users to surrender private information, such as GPS location or social networking data. To facilitate user privacy when using these applications, secure function evaluation (SFE) could be used to obliviously compute functions over encrypted inputs. The dominant construction for desktop applications is the Yao garbled circuit, but this technique requires significant processing power and network overhead, making it extremely expensive on resource-constrained mobile devices. In this work, we develop Efficient Mobile Oblivious Computation, a set of SFE protocols customized for the mobile platform. Using partially homomorphic cryptosystems, we develop protocols to meet the needs of two popular application types: location-based and social networking. Using these applications as comparison benchmarks, we demonstrate execution time improvements of 99% and network overhead improvements of 96% over the most optimized garbled circuit techniques. These results show that our protocols provide mobile application developers with a more practical and equally secure alternative to garbled circuits. Copyright © 2013 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>van der Walt, Paul</author><author>Consel, Charles</author><author>Balland, Emilie</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Frameworks compiled from declarations: a language-independent approach</title><secondary-title>Software: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Software: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>741-762</pages><volume>47</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>domain-specific languages</keyword><keyword>generative programming</keyword><keyword>privacy controls</keyword><keyword>programming frameworks</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/spe.2417</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/spe.2417</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Programming frameworks are an accepted fixture in the object-oriented world, motivated by the need for code reuse, developer guidance and restriction. A new trend is emerging where frameworks require domain experts to provide declarations using a domain-specific language, influencing the structure and behaviour of the resulting application. These mechanisms address concerns such as user privacy. Although many popular open platforms such as Android are based on declaration-driven frameworks, current implementations provide ad hoc and narrow solutions to concerns raised by their openness to non-certified developers. Most widely used frameworks fail to address serious privacy leaks and provide the user with little insight into application behaviour. To address these shortcomings, we show that declaration-driven frameworks can limit privacy leaks, as well as guide developers, independently from the underlying programming paradigm. To do so, we identify concepts that underlie declaration-driven frameworks and apply them systematically to an object-oriented language, Java and a dynamic functional language, Racket. The resulting programming framework generators are used to develop a prototype mobile application, illustrating how we mitigate a common class of privacy leaks. Finally, we explore the possible design choices and propose development principles for developing domain-specific language compilers to produce frameworks, applicable across a spectrum of programming paradigms. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Smari, Waleed W</author><author>Navarro, Antonio M</author><author>McQuay, William K</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Contemporary Computer Supported Collaboration: Systems, Technologies, Algorithms, and Applications</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>2681-2685</pages><volume>27</volume><issue>11</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.3467</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.3467</url><url>http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/cpe.3467</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Rebahi, Yacine</author><author>Khalil, Mateusz</author><author>Hohberg, Simon</author><author>Lorenz, Pascal</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An Android based new German eID solution for policy making processes</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>1271-1284</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>11</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>NFC</keyword><keyword>UbiPOL</keyword><keyword>anonymity</keyword><keyword>eID cards</keyword><keyword>mParticipation</keyword><keyword>privacy</keyword><keyword>security</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1413</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1413</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>In the current paper, we propose a novel mobile-based architecture that enforces security and privacy protection in the context of mParticipation. This architecture enables the citizens to cast their opinions anonymously and without limitation in time and space. It also removes the burden of preceding registration before any voting process. As the new electronic identity (eID) Cards are replacing the conventional identity cards in most European countries, we also discussed, in this paper, how the new German eID cards can be utilized for mobile participation. The use of the eID cards offers better flexibility and stronger security. A prototype implementation of this architecture is also described in this document, and the related performance is discussed. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Noh, Jiseong</author><author>Lee, Seunghyeon</author><author>Park, Jaehyun</author><author>Shin, Seungwon</author><author>Kang, Brent Byunghoon</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Vulnerabilities of network OS and mitigation with state-based permission system</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>1971-1982</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>13</issue><keywords><keyword>network operating system</keyword><keyword>network security</keyword><keyword>software defined networking</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1369</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1369</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The advancement of software defined networking (SDN) is redefining traditional computer networking architecture. The role of the control plane of SDN is of such importance that SDNs are referred to as network operating systems (OSs). However, the robustness and security of the network OS has been overlooked. In this paper, we report three main issues pertaining to network OSs. First, we identified vulnerabilities that could be exploited by malicious or buggy applications running on network OSs. We also identified four major attack vectors that could undermine network OS operations: denial of service, global data manipulation, control plane poisoning, and system shell execution. Further, it was demonstrated that real-world attacks can be launched on commonly used network OSs without significant effort. Second, we present a method to address the attacks by analyzing network applications running on network OSs to identify their behavioral features, which enabled the extraction of a permission set for each network application. Based on this work, a permission-based malicious network application detector was introduced, which examines the permission set of each application and prevents it from executing without permission. Our system shows almost no performance overhead. Copyright © 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Varshney, Gaurav</author><author>Misra, Manoj</author><author>Atrey, Pradeep K</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A survey and classification of web phishing detection schemes</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>6266-6284</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>18</issue><keywords><keyword>deception</keyword><keyword>phishing</keyword><keyword>search engine</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1674</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1674</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Phishing is a fraudulent technique that is used over the Internet to deceive users with the goal of extracting their personal information such as username, passwords, credit card, and bank account information. The key to phishing is deception. Phishing uses email spoofing as its initial medium for deceptive communication followed by spoofed websites to obtain the needed information from the victims. Phishing was discovered in 1996, and today, it is one of the most severe cybercrimes faced by the Internet users. Researchers are working on the prevention, detection, and education of phishing attacks, but to date, there is no complete and accurate solution for thwarting them. This paper studies, analyzes, and classifies the most significant and novel strategies proposed in the area of phished website detection, and outlines their advantages and drawbacks. Furthermore, a detailed analysis of the latest schemes proposed by researchers in various subcategories is provided. The paper identifies advantages, drawbacks, and research gaps in the area of phishing website detection that can be worked upon in future research and developments. The analysis given in this paper will help academia and industries to identify the best anti-phishing technique. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sun, Jianhua</author><author>She, Lingjun</author><author>Chen, Hao</author><author>Zhong, Wenyong</author><author>Chang, Cheng</author><author>Chen, Zhiwen</author><author>Li, Wentao</author><author>Yao, Shuna</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Automatically identifying apps in mobile traffic</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>3927-3941</pages><volume>28</volume><issue>14</issue><keywords><keyword>clustering</keyword><keyword>mobile traffic</keyword><keyword>network behavior</keyword><keyword>non-negative matrix factorization</keyword><keyword>traffic classification</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.3703</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.3703</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>With the rapid development of smartphones in recent years, we have witnessed an exponential growth of the number of mobile apps. Considering the security and management issues, network operators need to have a clear visibility into the apps running in the network. To this end, this paper presents a novel approach to generating the fingerprints for mobile apps from network traffic. The fingerprints that characterize the unique behaviors of specific mobile apps can be used to identify mobile apps from the real network traffic. In order to handle the large volume of traffic efficiently, we use non-negative matrix factorization (NMF) to perform traffic analysis to cluster similar network traffic into groups. Then, access patterns of individual apps that are extracted from each group can be used as fingerprints distinguishing apps from others uniquely. The experimental evaluations show that the proposed approach can identify the mobile apps from random and mixed network traffic with high precision. Copyright © 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Park, Jong Hyuk</author><author>Gritzalis, Stefanos</author><author>Cheng, Bo-Chao</author><author>Zhang, Ning</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Challenges and opportunities in next-generation cyberspace security</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>455-456</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1468</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1468</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Teing, Yee-Yang</author><author>Dehghantanha, Ali</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>CloudMe forensics: A case of big data forensic investigation</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>n/a--n/a</pages><keywords><keyword>Big data forensics</keyword><keyword>CloudMe forensics</keyword><keyword>cloud forensics</keyword><keyword>mobile forensics</keyword></keywords><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.4277</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.4277</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The significant increase in the volume, variety, and velocity of data complicates cloud forensic efforts, and such (big) evidential data will, at some point, become too (computationally) expensive to be fully identified, collected, and analysed in a timely manner. Thus, it is important for digital forensic practitioners to have an up-to-date knowledge of relevant data artefacts that could be forensically recovered from the cloud product under investigation. In this paper, CloudMe, a popular cloud storage service, is studied. The types and locations of the artefacts relating to the installation and uninstallation of CloudMe client application, logging in and out, and file synchronization events from the computer desktop and mobile clients are described. Findings from this research will also help inform future development of tools and techniques (e.g., data mining techniques) for cloud-enabled big data endpoint forensics investigation.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Atamli-Reineh, Ahmad</author><author>Paverd, Andrew</author><author>Petracca, Giuseppe</author><author>Martin, Andrew</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A framework for application partitioning using trusted execution environments</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>n/a--n/a</pages><keywords><keyword>SGX</keyword><keyword>hardware security</keyword><keyword>software vulnerabilities</keyword><keyword>trusted execution environment</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.4130</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.4130</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The size and complexity of modern applications are the underlying causes of numerous security vulnerabilities. In order to mitigate the risks arising from such vulnerabilities, various techniques have been proposed to isolate the execution of sensitive code from the rest of the application and from other software on the platform (such as the operating system). New technologies, notably Intel's Software Guard Extensions (SGX), are becoming available to enhance the security of partitioned applications. SGX provides a trusted execution environment (TEE), called an enclave, that protects the integrity of the code and the confidentiality of the data inside it from other software, including the operating system (OS). However, even with these partitioning techniques, it is not immediately clear exactly how they can and should be used to partition applications. How should a particular application be partitioned? How many TEEs should be used? What granularity of partitioning should be applied? To some extent, this is dependent on the capabilities and performance of the partitioning technology in use. However, as partitioning becomes increasingly common, there is a need for systematisation in the design of partitioning schemes.To address this need, we present a novel framework consisting of four overarching types of partitioning schemes through which applications can make use of TEEs. These schemes range from coarse-grained partitioning, in which the whole application is included in a single TEE, through to ultra-fine partitioning, in which each piece of security-sensitive code and data is protected in an individual TEE. Although partitioning schemes themselves are application specific, we establish application-independent relationships between the types we have defined. Because these relationships have an impact on both the security and performance of the partitioning scheme, we envisage that our framework can be used by software architects to guide the design of application partitioning schemes. To demonstrate the applicability of our framework, we have carried out case studies on two widely used software packages, the Apache Web server and the OpenSSL library. In each case study, we provide four high-level partitioning schemes—one for each of the types in our framework. We also systematically review the related work on hardware-enforced partitioning by categorising previous research efforts according to our framework.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Menten, Lawrence E</author><author>Chen, Aiyou</author><author>Stiliadis, Dimitrios</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>NoBot: Embedded malware detection for endpoint devices</title><secondary-title>Bell Labs Technical Journal</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Bell Labs Technical Journal</full-title></periodical><pages>155-170</pages><volume>16</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2011</year></dates><publisher>Wiley Subscription Services, Inc., A Wiley Company</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/bltj.20492</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/bltj.20492</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>NoBot is a novel malware detection system that employs packet classification and distinct counting techniques to achieve reliable detection and identification of malware by observing the traffic to and from a network-connected host. The solution is designed to be economically incorporated into endpoint devices, such as Ethernet switches, Gigabit passive optical network (GPON) devices, and digital subscriber line access multiplexers (DSLAMs) leveraging the integral features of the hosting device, such as packet classification, packet counting, packet-forwarding features, and the computing resources of the control processor. NoBot combines these features with deep packet inspection and distinct counting to detect the presence of malware with a low rate of false positive detections. The NoBot software has been incorporated into a Linux device driver, installed into an Android-based smart phone, and implemented as a preprocessor module for the open source Snort Intrusion detection and prevention System (IDS/IPS). © 2011 Alcatel-Lucent</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Boisvert, Sue</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An enterprise look at mHealth</title><secondary-title>Journal of Healthcare Risk Management</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Healthcare Risk Management</full-title></periodical><pages>44-52</pages><volume>32</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2012</year></dates><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/jhrm.21094</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/jhrm.21094</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The theme of this year's annual American Society for Healthcare Risk Management conference is Getting to Zero™: the Power of One™. The widespread use of mHealth exemplifies the power of one. The power of one user to apply technology to change the way healthcare is delivered at the bedside, in the provider's office, and in the patient's home. The power of one organization to provide technology that ensures provider access to clinical information to improve decision making, facilitate access to clinical information, and provide new ways to partner with patients — wherever they may be. This article provides an overview of the current status of mHealth and describes risk management strategies appropriate for organizations of all sizes and complexities.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Teing, Yee-Yang</author><author>Dehghantanha, Ali</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author><author>Dargahi, Tooska</author><author>Conti, Mauro</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Forensic Investigation of Cooperative Storage Cloud Service: Symform as a Case Study</title><secondary-title>Journal of Forensic Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Forensic Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>641-654</pages><volume>62</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Symform analysis</keyword><keyword>cloud forensics</keyword><keyword>cooperative cloud</keyword><keyword>digital forensics</keyword><keyword>forensic science</keyword><keyword>mobile app forensics</keyword><keyword>mobile device forensics</keyword><keyword>peer-to-peer forensics</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/1556-4029.13271</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.13271</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Researchers envisioned Storage as a Service (StaaS) as an effective solution to the distributed management of digital data. Cooperative storage cloud forensic is relatively new and is an under-explored area of research. Using Symform as a case study, we seek to determine the data remnants from the use of cooperative cloud storage services. In particular, we consider both mobile devices and personal computers running various popular operating systems, namely Windows 8.1, Mac OS X Mavericks 10.9.5, Ubuntu 14.04.1 LTS, iOS 7.1.2, and Android KitKat 4.4.4. Potential artefacts recovered during the research include data relating to the installation and uninstallation of the cloud applications, log-in to and log-out from Symform account using the client application, file synchronization as well as their time stamp information. This research contributes to an in-depth understanding of the types of terrestrial artifacts that are likely to remain after the use of cooperative storage cloud on client devices.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Marias, Giannis F</author><author>Barros, João</author><author>Fiedler, Markus</author><author>Fischer, Andreas</author><author>Hauff, Harald</author><author>Herkenhoener, Ralph</author><author>Grillo, Antonio</author><author>Lentini, Alessandro</author><author>Lima, Luisa</author><author>Lorentzen, Charlott</author><author>Mazurczyk, Wojciech</author><author>de Meer, Hermann</author><author>Oliveira, Paulo F</author><author>Polyzos, George C</author><author>Pujol, Enric</author><author>Szczypiorski, Krzysztof</author><author>Vilela, João P</author><author>Vinhoza, Tiago T V</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Security and privacy issues for the network of the future</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>987-1005</pages><volume>5</volume><issue>9</issue><keywords><keyword>networks</keyword><keyword>privacy</keyword><keyword>security</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2012</year></dates><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.384</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.384</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The vision towards the Network of the Future cannot be separated from the fact that today's networks, and networking services are subject to sophisticated and very effective attacks. When these attacks first appeared, spoofing and distributed denial-of-service attacks were treated as apocalypse for networking. Now, they are considered moderate damage, whereas more sophisticated and inconspicuous attacks, such as botnets activities, might have greater and far reaching impact. As the Internet is expanding to mobile phones and ‘smart dust’ and as its social coverage is liberalized towards the realization of ubiquitous computing (with communication), the concerns on security and privacy have become deeper and the problems more challenging than ever. Re-designing the Internet as the Network of the Future is self-motivating for researchers, and security and privacy cannot be provided again as separate, external, add-on, solutions. In this paper, we discuss the security and privacy challenges of the Network of the Future and try to delimit the solutions space on the basis of emerging techniques. We also review methods that help the quantification of security and privacy in an effort to provide a more systematic and quantitative treatment of the area in the future. Copyright © 2011 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Chen, Zhide</author><author>Wang, Meng</author><author>Xu, Li</author><author>Wu, Wei</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Worm propagation model in mobile network</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>1134-1144</pages><volume>28</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>control factors</keyword><keyword>km model</keyword><keyword>mobile environment</keyword><keyword>worm propagation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.3566</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.3566</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>With the popularity of mobile smart devices and functional diversification, the infection ways of mobile smartphones worm also become diverse. In mobile networks, mobile devices are suffering from the threat of worms all the time. Once the worm outbreaks, it will bring huge losses to mobile phone users and mobile network operators. Researches on mobile worm propagation model allow us to control and detect potential worm threat, according to the characteristics of worm's outbreak. In the paper, we put forward a worm propagation model based on the mobile network environment. After analyzing the model, we then give the simulation for controlling factors affecting worm propagation. This model allows us to have a certain understanding for the spread on the size and speed of the mobile worm and provide effective methods to control the spread of the mobile worm. Copyright © 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Varadharajan, Vijay</author><author>Tupakula, Udaya</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Securing wireless mobile nodes from distributed denial-of-service attacks</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>3794-3815</pages><volume>27</volume><issue>15</issue><keywords><keyword>Management</keyword><keyword>Mobile IP</keyword><keyword>Wi-Fi</keyword><keyword>denial of service</keyword><keyword>distributed denial of service</keyword><keyword>intrusion detection</keyword><keyword>mobile networks</keyword><keyword>reliability</keyword><keyword>security</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.3353</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.3353</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The current mobile devices have become smart and are increasingly being used for conducting business and personal activities. Also, there is increasing number of attacks targeting such mobile devices. The term mobile botnet refers to group of mobile devices that are compromised and controlled by the attacker that can be used for generating distributed denial-of-service attacks. The security protocols that have been proposed for wireless and mobile networks have several weaknesses that can be exploited by the attacker to obtain unauthorized access and generate attacks. Also, there is growing number of malicious applications that are aimed to compromise smartphones and using them for generating different types of attacks. In this paper, we propose techniques to counteract distributed denial-of-service attacks on wireless mobile devices. We describe the operation and architectural components of our model. We will show that our model is able to efficiently deal with the attacks by dropping the attack traffic before it targets the victim mobile node, can prevent the attack traffic at the upstream nodes, and also deal with the attack cases that involve mobility of the attacking and victim nodes. Copyright © 2014 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Dong, Fang</author><author>Shen, Jun</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>New trends and innovative methods in cloud computing and big data</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>n/a--n/a</pages><volume>29</volume><issue>19</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.4279</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.4279</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Oh, Doohwan</author><author>Kim, Ilkyu</author><author>Kim, Keunsoo</author><author>Lee, Sang-Min</author><author>Ro, Won Woo</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Highly Secure Mobile Devices Assisted with Trusted Cloud Computing Environments</title><secondary-title>ETRI Journal</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ETRI Journal</full-title></periodical><pages>348-358</pages><volume>37</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Mobile security</keyword><keyword>Wu-Manber</keyword><keyword>cloud computing</keyword><keyword>offloading computing</keyword><keyword>pattern matching</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.4218/etrij.15.0114.0397</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.4218/etrij.15.0114.0397</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Mobile devices have been widespread and become very popular with connectivity to the Internet, and a lot of desktop PC applications are now aggressively ported to them. Unfortunately, mobile devices are often vulnerable to malicious attacks due to their common usage and connectivity to the Internet. Therefore, the demands on the development of mobile security systems increase in accordance with advances in mobile computing. However, it is very hard to run a security program on a mobile device all of the time due the device's limited computational power and battery life. To overcome these problems, we propose a novel mobile security scheme that migrates heavy computations on mobile devices to cloud servers. An efficient data transmission scheme for reducing data traffic between devices and servers over networks is introduced. We have evaluated the proposed scheme with a mobile device in a cloud environment, whereby it achieved a maximum speedup of 13.4 compared to a traditional algorithm.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cytryn, Allan</author><author>Beck, Eric</author><author>Ross, Steven</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Hackers, Snoopers, and Thieves: How to Handle the Latest Threats</title><secondary-title>Journal of Corporate Accounting &amp; Finance</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Corporate Accounting &amp; Finance</full-title></periodical><pages>45-50</pages><volume>25</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/jcaf.21972</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/jcaf.21972</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Governments have been snooping on information systems in foreign countries and in their own. However, that's only part of a greater problem. The threat of cyberattacks from a variety of sources violates confidentiality and can cause the theft, abuse, manipulation, or destruction of information. But instead of narrowly focusing on a specific type of threat, the authors advise a well-considered program: understand the actual risks, develop an overall information security strategy, and implement advanced and persistent defenses against cyberattacks.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Manifavas, Charalampos</author><author>Fysarakis, Konstantinos</author><author>Papanikolaou, Alexandros</author><author>Papaefstathiou, Ioannis</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Embedded Systems Security: A Survey of EU Research Efforts</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>2016-2036</pages><volume>8</volume><issue>11</issue><keywords><keyword>embedded systems</keyword><keyword>resource-constrained devices</keyword><keyword>security</keyword><keyword>sensor networks</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1151</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1151</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Embedded systems security is a recurring theme in current research efforts, brought in the limelight by the wide adoption of ubiquitous devices. Significant funding has been allocated to various European projects on this subject area, in order to investigate and overcome the various security challenges. This paper provides an overview of recent EU research efforts pertaining to embedded systems security, where several prominent security issues and the respective proposed approaches are presented. Surveying relatively recent EU research projects, the authors identify 20 such projects that focus on embedded systems security aspects. The investigated technologies are categorised using a layered approach, to facilitate the presentation of the results; the categories comprise the node, network, and middleware and overlay layers, as well as architectures, frameworks and formal validation of the security of embedded systems. From this survey, certain patterns emerge regarding the issues investigated and the technologies researchers focus on, in order to address the said issues. Finally, the existing open issues are summarised, and directions for future research are given. Copyright © 2014 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Pokharel, Shasi</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author><author>Liu, Jixue</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Can Android VoIP voice conversations be decoded? I can eavesdrop on your Android VoIP communication</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>n/a--n/a</pages><volume>29</volume><issue>7</issue><keywords><keyword>Android VoIP apps</keyword><keyword>VoIP communications</keyword><keyword>VoIP interception</keyword><keyword>VoIP surveillance</keyword><keyword>codec identification</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.3845</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.3845</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP) is increasingly used by both individuals and corporate users. Recent studies had suggested that communications using VoIP apps may not be encrypted, although it has not been demonstrated that original conversations could be recovered from unencrypted communications that were subsequently intercepted. In this research, we propose a process for codec identification and decoding of captured communications from 15 popular Android VoIP apps. We are able to recover the original voice conversations from intercepted app-to-app voice calls of nine apps and app-to-phone calls from 10 apps. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Fanning, Kurt</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Thin Client: New Cost Savings?</title><secondary-title>Journal of Corporate Accounting &amp; Finance</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Corporate Accounting &amp; Finance</full-title></periodical><pages>7-12</pages><volume>25</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/jcaf.21933</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/jcaf.21933</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Information technology (IT) costs can be a major headache for cost managers. To cut costs, companies replaced desktop PCs with what are called thin clients: a software program, actual computer, or other device that relies on another computer to do most of the computing. While the expected cost savings didn't happen in all cases, the thin-client model still achieved significant cost savings and became a large portion of IT spending. But all this has taken place over the past two decades, so why is there now a new interest now in using thin clients?</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Dinh, Hoang T</author><author>Lee, Chonho</author><author>Niyato, Dusit</author><author>Wang, Ping</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A survey of mobile cloud computing: architecture, applications, and approaches</title><secondary-title>Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing</full-title></periodical><pages>1587-1611</pages><volume>13</volume><issue>18</issue><keywords><keyword>mobile cloud computing</keyword><keyword>mobile services</keyword><keyword>offloading</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/wcm.1203</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/wcm.1203</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Together with an explosive growth of the mobile applications and emerging of cloud computing concept, mobile cloud computing (MCC) has been introduced to be a potential technology for mobile services. MCC integrates the cloud computing into the mobile environment and overcomes obstacles related to the performance (e.g., battery life, storage, and bandwidth), environment (e.g., heterogeneity, scalability, and availability), and security (e.g., reliability and privacy) discussed in mobile computing. This paper gives a survey of MCC, which helps general readers have an overview of the MCC including the definition, architecture, and applications. The issues, existing solutions, and approaches are presented. In addition, the future research directions of MCC are discussed. Copyright © 2011 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Chen, Ting</author><author>Zhang, Xiao-song</author><author>Zhu, Cong</author><author>Ji, Xiao-li</author><author>Guo, Shi-ze</author><author>Wu, Yue</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Design and implementation of a dynamic symbolic execution tool for windows executables</title><secondary-title>Journal of Software: Evolution and Process</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Software: Evolution and Process</full-title></periodical><pages>1249-1272</pages><volume>25</volume><issue>12</issue><keywords><keyword>automated test generation</keyword><keyword>code coverage</keyword><keyword>dynamic symbolic execution</keyword><keyword>implementations</keyword><keyword>software testing</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/smr.1601</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smr.1601</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Dynamic symbolic execution, or DSE for short, has become a promising technique in software testing. However, the implementation details of DSE have not been described in depth in existing works. Although some open-source DSE tools are available nowadays, to design and implement a specific DSE tool from scratch is necessary for some reasons. To this end, we implement a Smart Fuzzing Tool for Windows Native Executables, or SMAFE for short, which utilizes Pin and STP for instrumentation and constraint solving, respectively. Advantages of Pin and STP make SMAFE portable. The major contribution of this paper is our detailed description of the implementation of DSE, including symbolization of inputs, tracking of symbols, synchronization of overlapped symbols, environment modeling, and so on. A practical case study validates the effectiveness of SMAFE. Then, the experiments with two benchmark sets present that the code coverage is above 90% on average. Benefits from this paper are at least twofold: moderating learning curve for scholars and shortening the development circle for practitioners. Copyright © 2013 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bai, Guangdong</author><author>Yan, Lin</author><author>Gu, Liang</author><author>Guo, Yao</author><author>Chen, Xiangqun</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Context-aware usage control for web of things</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>2696-2712</pages><volume>7</volume><issue>12</issue><keywords><keyword>Internet of Things</keyword><keyword>Web of Things</keyword><keyword>context awareness</keyword><keyword>security</keyword><keyword>usage control</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.424</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.424</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The Web of Things (WoT), inherited from the Internet of Things (IoT), encapsulates functionalities into publishable services on the Web to enable the IoT a seamless integration with the Web. The openness of the Web, in turn, directly exposes WoT to existing attacks from the Web. In addition, WoT possesses characteristics of high security and privacy concerns, mobility, and limited capabilities, which require specific and additional security and privacy protection beyond existing mechanisms. More importantly, WoT is inherently connected to its context, so context information must be taken into account in its security and privacy measures.To address these challenges, we propose a context-aware usage control model (ConUCON), which leverages the context information to enhance data, resource, and service protection for WoT. On the basis of ConUCON, we also design and implement a context-aware usage control framework on the middleware layer in our ongoing SmartHome project, to provide security and privacy protection. ConUCON is designed specifically to express the context-aware usage policy specification, such that security and privacy requirements can be easily specified and enforced with the proposed model and framework. Finally, we apply ConUCON to a remote appliance management prototype, as a case study, to demonstrates its feasibility in a real environment. Copyright © 2012 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Abo-alian, Alshaimaa</author><author>Badr, Nagwa L</author><author>Tolba, M F</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Keystroke dynamics-based user authentication service for cloud computing</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>2567-2585</pages><volume>28</volume><issue>9</issue><keywords><keyword>authentication</keyword><keyword>cloud computing</keyword><keyword>keystroke dynamics</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.3718</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.3718</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>User authentication is a crucial requirement for cloud service providers to prove that the outsourced data and services are safe from imposters. Keystroke dynamics is a promising behavioral biometrics for strengthening user authentication, however, current keystroke based solutions designed for certain datasets, for example, a fixed length text typed on a traditional personal computer keyboard and their authentication performances were not acceptable for other input devices nor free length text. Moreover, they suffer from a high dimensional feature space that degrades the authentication accuracy and performance.In this paper, a keystroke dynamics based authentication system is proposed for cloud environments that is applicable to fixed and free text typed on traditional and touch screen keyboards. The proposed system utilizes different feature extraction methods, as a preprocessing step, to minimize the feature space dimensionality. Moreover, different fusion rules are evaluated to combine the different feature extraction methods so that a set of the most relevant features is chosen. Because of the huge number of users' samples, a clustering method is applied to the users' profile templates to reduce the verification time. The proposed system is applied to three different benchmark datasets using three different classifiers. Experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness and efficiency of the proposed system. Copyright © 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Peng, Jian</author><author>Detchon, Sam</author><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author><author>Ashman, Helen</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Astroturfing detection in social media: a binary n-gram–based approach</title><secondary-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Concurrency and Computation: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>n/a--n/a</pages><volume>29</volume><issue>17</issue><keywords><keyword>astroturfing</keyword><keyword>authorship attribution</keyword><keyword>n-gram</keyword><keyword>social media astroturfing</keyword><keyword>user profiling</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/cpe.4013</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cpe.4013</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Astroturfing is appearing in numerous contexts in social media, with individuals posting product reviews or political commentary under a number of different names, and is of concern because of the intended deception. An astroturfer works with the aim of making it seem that a large number of people hold the same opinion, promoting a consensus based on the astroturfer's intentions. It is generally done for commercial or political advantage, often by paid writers or ideologically motivated writers. This paper brings the notion of authorship attribution to bear on the astroturfing problem, collecting quantities of data from public social media sites and analyzing the putative individual authors to see if they appear to be the same person. The analysis comprises a binary n-gram method, which was previously shown to be effective at accurately identifying authors on a training set from the same authors, while this paper shows how authors on different social media turn out to be the same author. The method has identified numerous instances where multiple accounts are apparently being operated by a single individual.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Guido, Mark</author><author>Brooks, Marc</author><author>Grover, Justin</author><author>Katz, Eric</author><author>Ondricek, Jared</author><author>Rogers, Marcus</author><author>Sharpe, Lauren</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Generating a Corpus of Mobile Forensic Images for Masquerading user Experimentation</title><secondary-title>Journal of Forensic Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Forensic Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>1467-1472</pages><volume>61</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>corpus</keyword><keyword>digital and multimedia forensics</keyword><keyword>forensic images</keyword><keyword>forensic science</keyword><keyword>masquerading</keyword><keyword>mobile</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/1556-4029.13178</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.13178</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The Periodic Mobile Forensics (PMF) system investigates user behavior on mobile devices. It applies forensic techniques to an enterprise mobile infrastructure, utilizing an on-device agent named TractorBeam. The agent collects changed storage locations for later acquisition, reconstruction, and analysis. TractorBeam provides its data to an enterprise infrastructure that consists of a cloud-based queuing service, relational database, and analytical framework for running forensic processes. During a 3-month experiment with Purdue University, TractorBeam was utilized in a simulated operational setting across 34 users to evaluate techniques to identify masquerading users (i.e., users other than the intended device user). The research team surmises that all masqueraders are undesirable to an enterprise, even when a masquerader lacks malicious intent. The PMF system reconstructed 821 forensic images, extracted one million audit events, and accurately detected masqueraders. Evaluation revealed that developed methods reduced storage requirements 50-fold. This paper describes the PMF architecture, performance of TractorBeam throughout the protocol, and results of the masquerading user analysis.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Aloi, Gianluca</author><author>Bedogni, Luca</author><author>Felice, Marco Di</author><author>Loscrì, Valeria</author><author>Molinaro, Antonella</author><author>Natalizio, Enrico</author><author>Pace, Pasquale</author><author>Ruggeri, Giuseppe</author><author>Trotta, Angelo</author><author>Zema, Nicola Roberto</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>STEM-Net: an evolutionary network architecture for smart and sustainable cities</title><secondary-title>Transactions on Emerging Telecommunications Technologies</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Transactions on Emerging Telecommunications Technologies</full-title></periodical><pages>21-40</pages><volume>25</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/ett.2785</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/ett.2785</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The concept of smart city has emerged worldwide as a feasible answer to the challenges raised by the increasing urbanisation. From the technological point of view, guaranteeing ubiquitous connectivity, reliable communications and seamless integration of multiple network access technologies are mandatory in a smart city. This is in contrast with the current infrastructure deployment in several urban areas, which is characterised by lack of ubiquitous connectivity and coverage and by fragmentation of networks that are usually deployed by different operators and without any centralised control by the city authorities. In this paper, we look at the heterogeneity of devices and network technologies under a different perspective by not perceiving it as a limitation but as a potential to increase the connectivity in a smart city. We propose a new generation of network nodes, called stem nodes, based on the innovative idea of ‘stemness’, which pushes forward the well-known self-configuration and self-management concepts towards the idea of node mutation and evolution. We also deployed prototypes that demonstrate the stem-node architecture and basic operations in different hardware platforms of common communication devices (an Alix-based router, a laptop and a smartphone). Copyright © 2014 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Raghunath, Riyukta</author><author>Anker, Connie</author><author>Nortcliffe, Anne</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Are academics ready for smart learning?</title><secondary-title>British Journal of Educational Technology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>British Journal of Educational Technology</full-title></periodical><pages>n/a--n/a</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/bjet.12532</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/bjet.12532</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Ownership of smartphones and tablets among the student population is growing. Students are using their devices to support their learning. Employers and employees are increasingly bringing their own smart devices into private and public organisations to support their business. This is leading to employees driving the Bring Your Own Device (BYOD) agenda in organisations. It is not clear the extent to which academics are embracing smart technology to manage their workload or to enhance the student experience of learning. This paper presents a qualitative study of how engineering academics are using their own BYOD or institutionally provided smart devices. A 6Cs (connect, communicate, collaborate, curate, create and coordinate) framework has been used to analyse the results. The findings indicate that academics are primarily using devices to create materials, second to coordinate their work and third to communicate with students about their learning. However, there are a number of inhibiting and enabling factors that need to be addressed by academic institutions to develop the effective adoption of smart technologies for academic practice. Infrastructure, including developing widespread access to WiFi, and the prioritisation of opportunities to support staff to learn how to apply the technology to enhance student learning and experience are key areas of necessary development.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Monteiro, David M</author><author>Rodrigues, Joel J P C</author><author>Lloret, Jaime</author><author>Sendra, Sandra</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A hybrid NFC–Bluetooth secure protocol for Credit Transfer among mobile phones</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>325-337</pages><volume>7</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Bluetooth</keyword><keyword>NFC</keyword><keyword>mobile computing</keyword><keyword>mobile payments</keyword><keyword>peer-to-peer</keyword><keyword>security</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.732</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.732</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The next-generation networks improve people's quality of life with new services and applications. The evolution of Internet technologies also promoted the development of electronic commerce and the evolution of mobile payments. Near field communication (NFC) was proposed as a new short-range wireless technology and can play an important role in such issues. Money transactions among mobile devices could play an important role in a near future in order to simplify and perform such operations safely. Furthermore, it is important that tasks are easy to perform. Then, this paper presents a mobile solution based on a peer-to-peer communication system for money transfer, based on NFC and Bluetooth communications. A hybrid communication protocol combining the security characteristics of NFC and better Bluetooth data transfer rates is proposed. The proposal was deployed in real environments, and it was evaluated, demonstrated, and validated with different NFC tags and the Bluetooth traffic was also analyzed. It was shown that system presents good response times. The solution offers a friendly user's interface and very easy to use, guaranteeing the security of money transfer, and it is ready for use. Copyright © 2013 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Röpke, Christian</author><author>Holz, Thorsten</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>On network operating system security</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Network Management</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Network Management</full-title></periodical><pages>6-24</pages><volume>26</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>network operating system</keyword><keyword>sandbox</keyword><keyword>software-defined networking</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/nem.1918</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/nem.1918</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The emerging concept of software-defined networking (SDN) enables new opportunities for building future networks. In such setups, a so-called network operating system (NOS), which is also known as SDN controller, provides services to manage the underlying and programmable network infrastructure. On top, the so-called SDN applications leverage NOS services and implement business needs in order to orchestrate the network as required. Thereby, such applications have access to all kinds of operations (including critical ones) to use valuable NOS and SDN resources. In case of faulty and malicious SDN applications, we demonstrate that today's NOSs can be significantly harmed, for example, by fatal errors and the adverse use of critical operations. To tackle this problem, we propose a sandbox system, which allows us to restrict not only SDN applications but also internal NOS components to access only a configurable set of critical operations. This enables operators to prevent the entire NOS from crashing in case a single SDN application or NOS component runs into a fatal error. Furthermore, operators can deny access to unwanted critical operations in order to prevent the potential misuse of such operations. For our proposal, we provide two proof-of-concept implementations: one for the industry's leading open-source NOS called OpenDaylight and another one for the HP controller, which serves as foundation for the world's first SDN App Store. As a result of our work, we harden a mandatory SDN component, that is, the NOS, and achieve robustness as well as pro-active security against faulty and malicious SDN software. Copyright © 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sedhai, Surendra</author><author>Sun, Aixin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An analysis of 14 Million tweets on hashtag-oriented spamming*</title><secondary-title>Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology</full-title></periodical><pages>1638-1651</pages><volume>68</volume><issue>7</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/asi.23836</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/asi.23836</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Over the years, Twitter has become a popular platform for information dissemination and information gathering. However, the popularity of Twitter has attracted not only legitimate users but also spammers who exploit social graphs, popular keywords, and hashtags for malicious purposes. In this paper, we present a detailed analysis of the HSpam14 dataset, which contains 14 million tweets with spam and ham (i.e., nonspam) labels, to understand spamming activities on Twitter. The primary focus of this paper is to analyze various aspects of spam on Twitter based on hashtags, tweet contents, and user profiles, which are useful for both tweet-level and user-level spam detection. First, we compare the usage of hashtags in spam and ham tweets based on frequency, position, orthography, and co-occurrence. Second, for content-based analysis, we analyze the variations in word usage, metadata, and near-duplicate tweets. Third, for user-based analysis, we investigate user profile information. In our study, we validate that spammers use popular hashtags to promote their tweets. We also observe differences in the usage of words in spam and ham tweets. Spam tweets are more likely to be emphasized using exclamation points and capitalized words. Furthermore, we observe that spammers use multiple accounts to post near-duplicate tweets to promote their services and products. Unlike spammers, legitimate users are likely to provide more information such as their locations and personal descriptions in their profiles. In summary, this study presents a comprehensive analysis of hashtags, tweet contents, and user profiles in Twitter spamming.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Godfrey, Michael W</author><author>German, Daniel M</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>On the evolution of Lehman's Laws</title><secondary-title>Journal of Software: Evolution and Process</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Software: Evolution and Process</full-title></periodical><pages>613-619</pages><volume>26</volume><issue>7</issue><keywords><keyword>Lehman's Laws</keyword><keyword>software architecture</keyword><keyword>software evolution</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/smr.1636</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/smr.1636</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>In this brief paper, we honor the contributions of the late Prof. Manny Lehman to the study of software evolution. We do so by means of a kind of evolutionary case study: First, we discuss his background in engineering and explore how this helped to shape his views on software systems and their development; next, we discuss the laws of software evolution that he postulated based on his industrial experiences; and finally, we examine how the nature of software systems and their development are undergoing radical change, and we consider what this means for future evolutionary studies of software. Copyright © 2013 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wong, Kok-Seng</author><author>Kim, Myung Ho</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An enhanced user authentication solution for mobile payment systems using wearables</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>4639-4649</pages><volume>9</volume><issue>17</issue><keywords><keyword>biometrics-based authentication</keyword><keyword>mobile devices</keyword><keyword>mobile payment systems</keyword><keyword>secret splitting</keyword><keyword>wearable devices</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.1654</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.1654</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>As technology continues to evolve, banks and other enterprises are restructuring their businesses to provide services to customers anywhere and anytime. However, it is challenging to move from conventional payment systems toward digital wallets across a range of payment services. Mobile devices are easily lost or stolen, so the rapid adoption of mobile devices for payment systems requires protection against unauthorized access to private applications and data. When mobile devices communicate with merchant point-of-sale systems, there is a risk of data leakage because third party applications in point-of-sale systems might access private data stored on the device without the user's knowledge or permission. We thus propose the use of wearable devices to store partial private data for the user and to participate in the user authentication. In this paper, we design a practical user authentication solution for mobile payment systems, and the main idea is to split the user's private data, such as credit card and banking information, and then store them across two separate devices (e.g., a smartphone and a wearable device). Our solution can improve the security of existing mobile payment systems that utilize user biometrics as an authentication factor, such as Apple Pay and Samsung Pay. Copyright © 2016 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bou-Harb, Elias</author><author>Pourzandi, Makan</author><author>Debbabi, Mourad</author><author>Assi, Chadi</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A secure, efficient, and cost-effective distributed architecture for spam mitigation on LTE 4G mobile networks</title><secondary-title>Security and Communication Networks</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Security and Communication Networks</full-title></periodical><pages>1478-1489</pages><volume>6</volume><issue>12</issue><keywords><keyword>LTE Networks</keyword><keyword>SPAM mitigation</keyword><keyword>security architectures</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sec.413</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sec.413</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The 4G of mobile networks will be a technology-opportunistic and user-centric system, combining the economical and technological advantages of various transmission technologies. As a part of its new architecture, LTE networks will implement an evolved packet core. Although this will provide various critical advantages, it will, on the other hand, expose telecom networks to serious IP-based attacks. One often adopted solution to mitigate such attacks is based on a centralized security architecture. However, this approach requires large processing and memory resources to handle huge amounts of traffic, which, in turn, causes a significant over dimensioning problem in the centralized nodes. Hence, it may cause this approach to fail from achieving its security task. In this paper, we focus on a SPAM flooding attack, namely SMTP SPAM, and demonstrate, through simulations and discussion, its DoS impact on the Long Term Evolution (LTE) network and subsequent effects on the mobile network operator. Our main contribution involves proposing a distributed architecture on the LTE network that is secure and that mitigates attacks efficiently by solving the over dimensioning problem. It is also cost-effective by utilizing ‘off-the-shelf’ low-cost hardware in the distributed nodes. Through additional simulation and analysis, we demonstrate the feasibility and effectiveness of our approach. Copyright © 2012 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kim, Kwanghyun</author><author>del Carmen Triana, María</author><author>Chung, Kwiyoung</author><author>Oh, Nahyun</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>When Do Employees Cyberloaf? An Interactionist Perspective Examining Personality, Justice, and Empowerment</title><secondary-title>Human Resource Management</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Human Resource Management</full-title></periodical><pages>1041-1058</pages><volume>55</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>cyberloafing</keyword><keyword>empowerment</keyword><keyword>justice</keyword><keyword>personality</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/hrm.21699</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/hrm.21699</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Cyberloafing—using the Internet for non-work-related activities—is a prevalent counterproductive work behavior in the workplace, but researchers have not yet paid sufficient attention to this issue, especially related to the role of personality in cyberloafing. Recognizing such a research gap, and using a trait activation theory framework, this study examines whether conscientiousness and emotional stability negatively relate to cyberloafing. We further investigate how organizational justice perceptions and psychological empowerment moderate the negative relationship between these personality traits and cyberloafing. Based on a sample of 247 employees, we find that those high in conscientiousness cyberloaf less when they perceive greater levels of organizational justice. In addition, highly conscientious individuals cyberloaf less when they have low, rather than high, levels of psychological empowerment. Implications for research and practice as well as future research directions are discussed. © 2015 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ranjan, Rajiv</author><author>Wang, Lizhe</author><author>Jayaraman, Prem Prakash</author><author>Mitra, Karan</author><author>Georgakopoulos, Dimitrios</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Special issue on Big Data and Cloud of Things (CoT)</title><secondary-title>Software: Practice and Experience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Software: Practice and Experience</full-title></periodical><pages>345-347</pages><volume>47</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/spe.2475</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/spe.2475</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kobsa, Alfred</author><author>Cho, Hichang</author><author>Knijnenburg, Bart P</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The effect of personalization provider characteristics on privacy attitudes and behaviors: An Elaboration Likelihood Model approach</title><secondary-title>Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology</full-title></periodical><pages>2587-2606</pages><volume>67</volume><issue>11</issue><keywords><keyword>judgment</keyword><keyword>privacy</keyword><keyword>reasoning</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/asi.23629</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/asi.23629</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Many computer users today value personalization but perceive it in conflict with their desire for privacy. They therefore tend not to disclose data that would be useful for personalization. We investigate how characteristics of the personalization provider influence users' attitudes towards personalization and their resulting disclosure behavior. We propose an integrative model that links these characteristics via privacy attitudes to actual disclosure behavior. Using the Elaboration Likelihood Model, we discuss in what way the influence of the manipulated provider characteristics is different for users engaging in different levels of elaboration (represented by the user characteristics of privacy concerns and self-efficacy). We find particularly that (a) reputation management is effective when users predominantly use the peripheral route (i.e., a low level of elaboration), but much less so when they predominantly use the central route (i.e., a high level of elaboration); (b) client-side personalization has a positive impact when users use either route; and (c) personalization in the cloud does not work well in either route. Managers and designers can use our results to instill more favorable privacy attitudes and increase disclosure, using different techniques that depend on each user's levels of privacy concerns and privacy self-efficacy.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Rindova, Violina P</author><author>Yeow, Adrian</author><author>Martins, Luis L</author><author>Faraj, Samer</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Partnering portfolios, value-creation logics, and growth trajectories: A comparison of Yahoo and Google (1995 to 2007)</title><secondary-title>Strategic Entrepreneurship Journal</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Strategic Entrepreneurship Journal</full-title></periodical><pages>133-151</pages><volume>6</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Google</keyword><keyword>Yahoo</keyword><keyword>entrepreneurial firm growth</keyword><keyword>partnering portfolios</keyword><keyword>value creation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2012</year></dates><publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/sej.1131</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/sej.1131</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>We add to the theory of entrepreneurial firm growth by inductively theorizing the processes through which new high-growth firms utilize their partnering portfolios to pursue distinctive approaches to growth. We extend the strategic perspective on entrepreneurial networks by identifying three mechanisms linking partnering portfolios to differences in firm growth: configuring partnering portfolios to pursue distinctive logics for sourcing external resources, aligning resource-sourcing and resource-linking logics in new product development, and embarking on different growth trajectories, which contribute to different performance patterns. These theoretical insights contribute to current understanding of the external and internal sources of heterogeneity in the performance of entrepreneurial firms. Copyright © 2012 Strategic Management Society.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Song, Wook</author><author>Kim, Yeseong</author><author>Kim, Hakbong</author><author>Lim, Jehun</author><author>Kim, Jihong</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Personalized Optimization for Android Smartphones</title><secondary-title>ACM Trans. Embed. Comput. Syst.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Trans. Embed. Comput. Syst.</full-title></periodical><pages>60:1--60:25</pages><volume>13</volume><issue>2s</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>application usage pattern</keyword><keyword>mobile systems</keyword><keyword>user experience</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2544375.2544380</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2544375.2544380</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ota, Kaoru</author><author>Dao, Minh Son</author><author>Mezaris, Vasileios</author><author>Natale, Francesco G B De</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Deep Learning for Mobile Multimedia: A Survey</title><secondary-title>ACM Trans. Multimedia Comput. Commun. Appl.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Trans. Multimedia Comput. Commun. Appl.</full-title></periodical><pages>34:1--34:22</pages><volume>13</volume><issue>3s</issue><keywords><keyword>Deep learning</keyword><keyword>deep neural networks</keyword><keyword>mobile multimedia computing</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3092831</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/3092831</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Shu, Junliang</author><author>Zhang, Yuanyuan</author><author>Li, Juanru</author><author>Li, Bodong</author><author>Gu, Dawu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Why Data Deletion Fails? A Study on Deletion Flaws and Data Remanence in Android Systems</title><secondary-title>ACM Trans. Embed. Comput. Syst.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Trans. Embed. Comput. Syst.</full-title></periodical><pages>61:1--61:22</pages><volume>16</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Data recovery</keyword><keyword>file carving</keyword><keyword>mobile security</keyword><keyword>secure deletion</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3007211</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/3007211</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bauman, Erick</author><author>Ayoade, Gbadebo</author><author>Lin, Zhiqiang</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Survey on Hypervisor-Based Monitoring: Approaches, Applications, and Evolutions</title><secondary-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</full-title></periodical><pages>10:1--10:33</pages><volume>48</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>VM</keyword><keyword>Virtualization</keyword><keyword>detection</keyword><keyword>hypervisor</keyword><keyword>integrity</keyword><keyword>introspection</keyword><keyword>isolation</keyword><keyword>malware</keyword><keyword>monitoring</keyword><keyword>semantic gap</keyword><keyword>virtual machine monitor</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2775111</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2775111</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Rodr\'\iguez-Gómez, Rafael A</author><author>Maciá-Fernández, Gabriel</author><author>Garc\'\ia-Teodoro, Pedro</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Survey and Taxonomy of Botnet Research Through Life-cycle</title><secondary-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</full-title></periodical><pages>45:1--45:33</pages><volume>45</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Attack</keyword><keyword>botnet</keyword><keyword>defense</keyword><keyword>detection</keyword><keyword>survey</keyword><keyword>taxonomy</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2501654.2501659</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2501654.2501659</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Seneviratne, Suranga</author><author>Seneviratne, Aruna</author><author>Kaafar, Mohamed Ali</author><author>Mahanti, Anirban</author><author>Mohapatra, Prasant</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Spam Mobile Apps: Characteristics, Detection, and in the Wild Analysis</title><secondary-title>ACM Trans. Web</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Trans. Web</full-title></periodical><pages>4:1--4:29</pages><volume>11</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Spam</keyword><keyword>android</keyword><keyword>mobile apps</keyword><keyword>spam apps</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3007901</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/3007901</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Meng, Guozhu</author><author>Liu, Yang</author><author>Zhang, Jie</author><author>Pokluda, Alexander</author><author>Boutaba, Raouf</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Collaborative Security: A Survey and Taxonomy</title><secondary-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</full-title></periodical><pages>1:1--1:42</pages><volume>48</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Collaborative security</keyword><keyword>information sharing</keyword><keyword>intrusion detection</keyword><keyword>malware</keyword><keyword>privacy</keyword><keyword>spam</keyword><keyword>taxonomy</keyword><keyword>trust</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2785733</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2785733</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Petsas, Thanasis</author><author>Papadogiannakis, Antonis</author><author>Polychronakis, Michalis</author><author>Markatos, Evangelos P</author><author>Karagiannis, Thomas</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Measurement, Modeling, and Analysis of the Mobile App Ecosystem</title><secondary-title>ACM Trans. Model. Perform. Eval. Comput. Syst.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Trans. Model. Perform. Eval. Comput. Syst.</full-title></periodical><pages>7:1--7:33</pages><volume>2</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Appstores</keyword><keyword>app popularity</keyword><keyword>app pricing</keyword><keyword>clustering effect</keyword><keyword>mobile apps</keyword><keyword>revenue</keyword><keyword>workload characterization</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2993419</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2993419</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Avancha, Sasikanth</author><author>Baxi, Amit</author><author>Kotz, David</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Privacy in Mobile Technology for Personal Healthcare</title><secondary-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</full-title></periodical><pages>3:1--3:54</pages><volume>45</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>HIPAA</keyword><keyword>Privacy framework</keyword><keyword>e-health</keyword><keyword>electronic health record</keyword><keyword>home healthcare</keyword><keyword>mHealth</keyword><keyword>medicine</keyword><keyword>mobile healthcare</keyword><keyword>personal health record</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2012</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2379776.2379779</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2379776.2379779</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Guri, Mordechai</author><author>Monitz, Matan</author><author>Elovici, Yuval</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Bridging the Air Gap Between Isolated Networks and Mobile Phones in a Practical Cyber-Attack</title><secondary-title>ACM Trans. Intell. Syst. Technol.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Trans. Intell. Syst. Technol.</full-title></periodical><pages>50:1--50:25</pages><volume>8</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>APT</keyword><keyword>Air-gap</keyword><keyword>EMSEC</keyword><keyword>FM Radio</keyword><keyword>TEMPEST</keyword><keyword>bridging the air-gap</keyword><keyword>cyber-attack</keyword><keyword>data exfiltration</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2870641</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2870641</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Heartfield, Ryan</author><author>Loukas, George</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Taxonomy of Attacks and a Survey of Defence Mechanisms for Semantic Social Engineering Attacks</title><secondary-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</full-title></periodical><pages>37:1--37:39</pages><volume>48</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Computer crime</keyword><keyword>semantic attacks</keyword><keyword>social engineering attacks</keyword><keyword>survey</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2835375</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2835375</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kim, Hyojun</author><author>Agrawal, Nitin</author><author>Ungureanu, Cristian</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Revisiting Storage for Smartphones</title><secondary-title>Trans. Storage</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Trans. Storage</full-title></periodical><pages>14:1--14:25</pages><volume>8</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>Storage systems</keyword><keyword>mobile</keyword><keyword>mobile storage</keyword><keyword>smartphones</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2012</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2385603.2385607</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2385603.2385607</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sufatrio</author><author>Tan, Darell J J</author><author>Chua, Tong-Wei</author><author>Thing, Vrizlynn L L</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Securing Android: A Survey, Taxonomy, and Challenges</title><secondary-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</full-title></periodical><pages>58:1--58:45</pages><volume>47</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>Android security</keyword><keyword>malware mitigation</keyword><keyword>mobile security</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2733306</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2733306</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Tam, Kimberly</author><author>Feizollah, Ali</author><author>Anuar, Nor Badrul</author><author>Salleh, Rosli</author><author>Cavallaro, Lorenzo</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The Evolution of Android Malware and Android Analysis Techniques</title><secondary-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</full-title></periodical><pages>76:1--76:41</pages><volume>49</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>classification</keyword><keyword>detection</keyword><keyword>dynamic analysis</keyword><keyword>malware</keyword><keyword>static analysis</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3017427</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/3017427</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Xu, Meng</author><author>Song, Chengyu</author><author>Ji, Yang</author><author>Shih, Ming-Wei</author><author>Lu, Kangjie</author><author>Zheng, Cong</author><author>Duan, Ruian</author><author>Jang, Yeongjin</author><author>Lee, Byoungyoung</author><author>Qian, Chenxiong</author><author>Lee, Sangho</author><author>Kim, Taesoo</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Toward Engineering a Secure Android Ecosystem: A Survey of Existing Techniques</title><secondary-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</full-title></periodical><pages>38:1--38:47</pages><volume>49</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>ecosystem</keyword><keyword>mobile malware</keyword><keyword>survey</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2963145</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://4ab89637524d50f4fd232c9c4983a91c9968.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2963145</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Enck, William</author><author>Gilbert, Peter</author><author>Han, Seungyeop</author><author>Tendulkar, Vasant</author><author>Chun, Byung-Gon</author><author>Cox, Landon P</author><author>Jung, Jaeyeon</author><author>McDaniel, Patrick</author><author>Sheth, Anmol N</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>TaintDroid: An Information-Flow Tracking System for Realtime Privacy Monitoring on Smartphones</title><secondary-title>ACM Trans. Comput. Syst.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Trans. Comput. Syst.</full-title></periodical><pages>5:1--5:29</pages><volume>32</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Information-flow tracking</keyword><keyword>mobile apps</keyword><keyword>privacy monitoring</keyword><keyword>smartphones</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2619091</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2619091</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Chang, Jian</author><author>Venkatasubramanian, Krishna K</author><author>West, Andrew G</author><author>Lee, Insup</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Analyzing and Defending Against Web-based Malware</title><secondary-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</full-title></periodical><pages>49:1--49:35</pages><volume>45</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Web-based malware</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2501654.2501663</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2501654.2501663</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, Haoyu</author><author>Li, Yuanchun</author><author>Guo, Yao</author><author>Agarwal, Yuvraj</author><author>Hong, Jason I</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Understanding the Purpose of Permission Use in Mobile Apps</title><secondary-title>ACM Trans. Inf. Syst.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Trans. Inf. Syst.</full-title></periodical><pages>43:1--43:40</pages><volume>35</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>Permission</keyword><keyword>access control</keyword><keyword>mobile applications</keyword><keyword>privacy</keyword><keyword>purpose</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3086677</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/3086677</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Choo, Kim-Kwang Raymond</author><author>Fei, Yunsi</author><author>Xiang, Yang</author><author>Yu, Yu</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Embedded Device Forensics and Security</title><secondary-title>ACM Trans. Embed. Comput. Syst.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Trans. Embed. Comput. Syst.</full-title></periodical><pages>50:1--50:5</pages><volume>16</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Embedded device security</keyword><keyword>and digital forensics</keyword><keyword>embedded device forensics</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3015662</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/3015662</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ye, Yanfang</author><author>Li, Tao</author><author>Adjeroh, Donald</author><author>Iyengar, S Sitharama</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Survey on Malware Detection Using Data Mining Techniques</title><secondary-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</full-title></periodical><pages>41:1--41:40</pages><volume>50</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Survey</keyword><keyword>data mining</keyword><keyword>malware detection</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3073559</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://50e85d52628a0c909a4c731369f9e8574f54.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/3073559</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Reaves, Bradley</author><author>Bowers, Jasmine</author><author>Scaife, Nolen</author><author>Bates, Adam</author><author>Bhartiya, Arnav</author><author>Traynor, Patrick</author><author>Butler, Kevin R B</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Mo(Bile) Money, Mo(Bile) Problems: Analysis of Branchless Banking Applications</title><secondary-title>ACM Trans. Priv. Secur.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Trans. Priv. Secur.</full-title></periodical><pages>11:1--11:31</pages><volume>20</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Mobile money</keyword><keyword>branchless banking</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/3092368</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/3092368</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection_701to 800.enl" path="My Collection_701to 800.enl">My Collection_701to 800.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Reaves, Bradley</author><author>Bowers, Jasmine</author><author>Gorski III, Sigmund Albert</author><author>Anise, Olabode</author><author>Bobhate, Rahul</author><author>Cho, Raymond</author><author>Das, Hiranava</author><author>Hussain, Sharique</author><author>Karachiwala, Hamza</author><author>Scaife, Nolen</author><author>Wright, Byron</author><author>Butler, Kevin</author><author>Enck, William</author><author>Traynor, Patrick</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>&amp;Ast;Droid: Assessment and Evaluation of Android Application Analysis Tools</title><secondary-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ACM Comput. Surv.</full-title></periodical><pages>55:1--55:30</pages><volume>49</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Android</keyword><keyword>application security</keyword><keyword>program analysis</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><pub-location>New York, NY, USA</pub-location><publisher>ACM</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1145/2996358</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2996358</url></web-urls></urls></record></records></xml>
